<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>

<!--
Strings for the alert window

Note that the rules are different here than in other text xml files.
This is because the alert window will read this file directly rather than relying on the normal TXT_KEY system,
as the alert window needs to be active prior to the TXT_KEYs are being read.

Special rules:
No plural or gender. Just provide one string for each language.
Arguments are given using the printf system https://cplusplus.com/reference/cstdio/printf/
In general, this means arguments are named %d (number) and %s (string). No numbers given as that is assigned by order.

-->



<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_ALERT_XML_ERROR</Tag>
        <English>XML READ ERROR</English>
        <Russian>ОШИБКА ЧТЕНИЯ XML</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_ALERT_MOD_IN_DOCUMENTS_HEADER</Tag>
        <English>Invalid Mod install location</English>
        <Russian>Некорректное место расположения мода</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_ALERT_MOD_IN_DOCUMENTS</Tag>
        <English>This mod doesn't work correctly when installed in My Documents.
Please move it to Mods in the game directory.
See Readme for more details.</English>
        <Russian>Этот мод работает некорректно при установке в папке "Мои документы".
Пожалуйста, переместите его в Mods в папке с игрой.
Прочитайте Readme для более подробной информации.</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_ALERT_CONFIGURATION_ERROR_HEADER</Tag>
        <English>Configuration error</English>
        <Russian>Ошибка конфигурации</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_ALERT_CONFIGURATION_ERROR</Tag>
        <English>The game tried to set AllowPublicMaps to 0 in %s. Something went wrong while doing so and now it's possible that incompatible public maps can be selected ingame. Please manually open this file and set AllowPublicMaps = 0 Restart the game once this is done.</English>
        <Russian>Игра пыталась установить значение AllowPublicMaps на 0 в файле %s. При этом что-то пошло не так и теперь в игре могут быть выбраны общедоступные карты, несовместимые с модом. Пожалуйста, вручную откройте этот файл и установите AllowPublicMaps = 0 Перезапустите игру, как только это будет сделано.</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_ALERT_PUBLIC_MAPS_DISABLED_HEADER</Tag>
        <English>Restart required</English>
        <Russian>Требуется перезагрука</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_ALERT_PUBLIC_MAPS_DISABLED</Tag>
        <English>The mod has changed configuration to remove known incompatible maps from the menus. Please restart the game for the new settings to take effect. Do you want to quit now?</English>
        <Russian>Мод изменил конфигурацию, чтобы удалить известные несовместимые карты из меню. Пожалуйста, перезапустите игру, чтобы новые настройки вступили в силу. Сделать это сейчас?</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_ALERT_LARGE_ADDRESS_AWARE_HEADER</Tag>
        <English>Low memory warning</English>
        <Russian>Предупреждение о нехватке памяти</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_ALERT_LARGE_ADDRESS_AWARE</Tag>
        <English>Colonization.exe is currently set to use max 2 GB of RAM. We The People will sometimes need more than that and if so the game will crash. Do you want to quit the game and open the readme on how to patch the game to use 4 GB?</English>
        <Russian>В настоящее время Colonization.exe настроен на использование не более 2 ГБ ОЗУ. Моду "We The People" иногда может понадобится больше и тогда игра вылетит. Хотите выйти из игры и открыть инструкцию о том, как пропатчить игру, чтобы использовать 4 ГБ?</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_ALERT_WRONG_STEAM_VERION_HEADER</Tag>
        <English>Wrong steam version</English>
        <Russian>Неправильная Стим-версия игры</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_ALERT_WRONG_STEAM_VERION</Tag>
        <English>The currently selected version of Colonization has issues with mod compatibility. This can be fixed by telling steam to switch to the beta version. Do you want to quit now and open the readme on this issue?</English>
        <Russian>Текущая выбранная версия Колонизации имеет проблемы с совместимостью модов. Это можно исправить, изменив в настройках Steam версию игры на бета-версию. Хотите выйти сейчас и открыть инструкцию по этому вопросу?</Russian>
    </TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>
