<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>

<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUTTON_POPUP_CHOOSE_CITY_PLOT_YIELD_TITLE</Tag>
		<English>Crops can be grown on the land near the settlement. The governor asks if you have any requests.</English>
		<French>On peut cultiver sur les terres près de la colonie. Le gouverneur demande si vous avez des demandes.</French>
		<German>Es können Feldfrüchte auf dem Land nahe der Siedlung angebaut werden. Der Gouverneur fragt, ob Sie besondere Wünsche haben.</German>
		<Italian>Le colture possono essere coltivate sul terreno vicino all'insediamento. Il governatore chiede se hai qualche richiesta.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Se puede cultivar en las tierras cercanas al asentamiento. El gobernador pregunta si tiene alguna petición.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUTTON_POPUP_CHOOSE_CITY_PLOT_YIELD_AUTO</Tag>
		<English>The governor knows best how to use his land.</English>
		<French>Le gouverneur sait mieux que quiconque comment utiliser ses terres.</French>
		<German>Der Gouverneur weiß am besten, wie sein Land zu nutzen ist.</German>
		<Italian>Il governatore sa come utilizzare al meglio la sua terra.</Italian>
		<Spanish>El gobernador es el que mejor sabe cómo utilizar su tierra.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUTTON_POPUP_CHOOSE_CITY_PLOT_YIELD_HELP</Tag>
		<English>Each turn the governor will consider what would be best to produce. He can easily change production to get the best out of the situation whenever things change.[PARAGRAPH:2]Note: Your requests are guidelines only. If in future the requested crops are unavailable, the governor will switch production to make the best out of the situation. If your request becomes available again later, the governor remembers and will resume production.</English>
		<French>À chaque tour, le gouverneur réfléchira à ce qui serait le mieux à produire. Il peut facilement modifier la production pour tirer le meilleur parti de la situation lorsque les choses changent.[PARAGRAPH:2]Remarque : vos demandes ne sont que des indications. Si, à l'avenir, les cultures demandées ne sont plus disponibles, le gouverneur modifiera la production pour tirer le meilleur parti de la situation. Si votre demande redevient disponible plus tard, le gouverneur s'en souvient et reprendra la production.</French>
		<German>Jede Runde wird der Gouverneur überlegen, was am besten angebaut werden soll. Sollten die Umstände es erfordern, etwas zu ändern, kann er frei über die Produktion entscheiden, um das Beste aus der Situation zu machen.[PARAGRAPH:2]Beachten Sie, daß Ihre Wünsche nur Richtlinien sind. Sollte es in Zukunft nicht möglich sein, die gewünschten Feldfrüchte anzubauen, wird der Governeur die Produktion umstellen. Wenn Ihre Wünsche wieder erfüllbar sind, wird sich der Gouverneur an sie erinnern und die gewünschten Feldfrüchte anbauen lassen.</German>
		<Italian>Ad ogni turno il governatore considererà cosa sarebbe meglio produrre. Egli può facilmente cambiare la produzione per ottenere il meglio dalla situazione ogni volta che le cose cambiano.[PARAGRAPH:2]Nota: Le tue richieste sono solo linee guida. Se in futuro le colture richieste non saranno disponibili, il governatore cambierà la produzione per trarre il meglio dalla situazione. Se la tua richiesta tornerà disponibile più tardi, il governatore se ne ricorderà e riprenderà la produzione.</Italian>
		<Spanish>En cada turno, el gobernador considerará qué sería lo mejor para producir. Puede cambiar fácilmente la producción para sacar lo mejor de la situación siempre que las cosas cambien.[PARAGRAPH:2]Nota: Sus peticiones son sólo orientativas. Si en el futuro los cultivos solicitados no están disponibles, el gobernador cambiará la producción para sacar lo mejor de la situación. Si su solicitud vuelve a estar disponible más adelante, el gobernador lo recordará y reanudará la producción.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_POPUP_IMPORT_TITLE</Tag>
        <English>[COLOR_SELECTED_TEXT]%s1_city[COLOR_REVERT][PARAGRAPH:2]Select imports, exports, minimum and maximum goods stored (Read Colopedia's concept page [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Transport Automation[COLOR_REVERT] to learn how to use this.) :[NEWLINE]</English>
        <French>[COLOR_SELECTED_TEXT]%s1_city[COLOR_REVERT][PARAGRAPH:2]Sélectionnez les importations, les exportations, le minimum et le maximum de marchandises stockées (Lisez la page conceptuelle de Colopedia [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Automatisation du transport[COLOR_REVERT] pour savoir comment l'utiliser). :[NEWLINE]</French>
        <German>[COLOR_SELECTED_TEXT]%s1_city[COLOR_REVERT][PARAGRAPH:2]Importe, Exporte sowie Ober- und Untergrenze für Lagerbestände festlegen (Details sind in der Colopedia unter dem Konzept [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Transportautomatisierung[COLOR_REVERT] nachzulesen) :[NEWLINE]</German>
        <Italian>[COLOR_SELECTED_TEXT]%s1_city[COLOR_REVERT][PARAGRAPH:2]Seleziona le importazioni, le esportazioni, le merci minime e massime immagazzinate (Leggi la pagina del concetto di Colopedia [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Automazione dei trasporti[COLOR_REVERT] per sapere come usarlo). :[NEWLINE]</Italian>
        <Spanish>[COLOR_SELECTED_TEXT]%s1_city[COLOR_REVERT][PARAGRAPH:2]Seleccione las importaciones, las exportaciones y las mercancías mínimas y máximas almacenadas (Lea la página de conceptos de Colopedia [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Automatización del transporte[COLOR_REVERT] para aprender a utilizarlo). :[NEWLINE]</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_POPUP_IMPORT_CLEAR_ALL</Tag>
        <English>Clear All</English>
        <French>Supprimer tout</French>
        <German>Alles löschen</German>
        <Italian>Cancellare tutto</Italian>
        <Spanish>Eliminar todo</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_POPUP_IMPORT_ALL</Tag>
        <English>Import all goods</English>
        <French>Importation de tous les biens</French>
        <German>Import aller Güter</German>
        <Italian>Importazione di tutte le merci</Italian>
        <Spanish>Importar todas las mercancías</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_POPUP_IMPORT_EXPORT_ALL</Tag>
        <English>Auto-export all goods</English>
        <French>Exportation automatique de tous les biens</French>
        <German>Automatischer Export aller Güter</German>
        <Italian>Esportazione automatica di tutte le merci</Italian>
        <Spanish>Exportación automática de todas las mercancías</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_POPUP_IMPORT_IMPORT</Tag>
        <English>Import</English>
        <French>Importer</French>
        <German>Import</German>
        <Italian>Importazione</Italian>
        <Spanish>Importar</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_POPUP_IMPORT_IMPORT_HELP</Tag>
        <English>[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Import this good[COLOR_REVERT][PARAGRAPH:2]Left: import limit[NEWLINE]While importing, no transport can make the warehouse exceed this amount.[NEWLINE]0 means no limit.</English>
        <French>[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Importer cette bien[COLOR_REVERT][PARAGRAPH:2]A gauche : limite d'importation[NEWLINE]Pendant l'importation, aucun transport ne peut faire dépasser ce montant à l'entrepôt.[NEWLINE]0 signifie aucune limite.</French>
        <German>[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Güter importieren[COLOR_REVERT][PARAGRAPH:2]Links: Obergrenze für Importe[NEWLINE]Wenn importiert wird, kann der Lagerbestand durch ankommende Transporte nicht überschritten werden.[NEWLINE]0 bedeutet keine Einschränkungen.</German>
        <Italian>[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Importa questo merce[COLOR_REVERT][PARAGRAPH:2]Sinistra: limite di importazione[NEWLINE]Durante l'importazione, nessun trasporto può far superare al magazzino questa quantità.[NEWLINE]0 significa nessun limite.</Italian>
        <Spanish>[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Importar esta mercancía[COLOR_REVERT][PARAGRAPH:2]Izquierda: límite de importación[NEWLINE]Durante la importación, ningún transporte puede hacer que el almacén supere esta cantidad.[NEWLINE]0 significa que no hay límite.</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_POPUP_IMPORT_FEEDER</Tag>
        <English>Feeder</English>
	<Spanish>Alimentador</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_POPUP_IMPORT_FEEDER_HELP</Tag>
        <English>[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Import feeder[COLOR_REVERT][PARAGRAPH:2]Turn import on at 75%[NEWLINE]Turn import off at 100%[NEWLINE]Compared to maintain level (bottom spinbutton)</English>
        <French>[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Gestionnaire d'importation[COLOR_REVERT][PARAGRAPH:2]Démarre l'importation à 75%[NEWLINE]Arrête l'importation à 100%[NEWLINE]Par rapport au niveau de maintien (bouton rotatif inférieur)</French>
        <German>[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Importsteuerung[COLOR_REVERT][PARAGRAPH:2]Schaltet Import bei 75% an[NEWLINE]Schaltet Import bei 100% aus[NEWLINE]In Relation zur Obergrenze für Importe (unterer Button)</German>
        <Italian>[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Import feeder[COLOR_REVERT][PARAGRAPH:2]Attiva l'importazione al 75%[NEWLINE]Disattiva l'importazione al 100%[NEWLINE]Rispetto al mantenimento del livello (pulsante in basso)</Italian>
        <Spanish>[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Alimentador de importación[COLOR_REVERT][PARAGRAPH:2]Activar la importación al 75%[NEWLINE]Desactivar la importación al 100%[NEWLINE]En comparación con mantener el nivel (botón giratorio inferior)</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_POPUP_IMPORT_EXPORT</Tag>
        <English>Export</English>
        <French>Exporter</French>
        <German>Export</German>
        <Italian>Esportazione</Italian>
        <Spanish>Exportar</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_POPUP_IMPORT_EXPORT_HELP</Tag>
        <English>[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Export this good[COLOR_REVERT][PARAGRAPH:2]Left: maintain level[NEWLINE]Import if warehouse is below this level or export if warehouse exceeds this level.</English>
        <French>[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Exporter ce bien[COLOR_REVERT][PARAGRAPH:2]Gauche : maintenir le niveau[NEWLINE]Importer si l'entrepôt est inférieur à ce niveau ou exporter si l'entrepôt dépasse ce niveau.</French>
        <German>[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Güter exportieren[COLOR_REVERT][PARAGRAPH:2]Links: Lagerbestand einhalten[NEWLINE]Importieren, wenn der Lagerbestand unterhalb dieser Schwelle liegt.[NEWLINE]Exportieren, wenn der Lagerbestand oberhalb dieser Schwelle liegt.</German>
        <Italian>[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Esporta questo bene[COLOR_REVERT][PARAGRAPH:2]Sinistra: mantenere il livello[NEWLINE]Importa se il magazzino è sotto questo livello o esporta se il magazzino supera questo livello.</Italian>
        <Spanish>[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Exportar este bien[COLOR_REVERT][PARAGRAPH:2]Izquierda: mantener el nivel[NEWLINE]Importar si el almacén está por debajo de este nivel o exportar si el almacén supera este nivel.</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_POPUP_IMPORT_AUTO_EXPORT</Tag>
        <English>Auto</English>
        <French>Automatique</French>
        <German>Automatisch</German>
        <Italian>Automatico</Italian>
        <Spanish>Automático</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_POPUP_IMPORT_AUTO_EXPORT_HELP</Tag>
        <English>[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Automatic turn export ON/OFF at turn start[COLOR_REVERT][PARAGRAPH:2]A high number of trade routes slows down the game. This feature allows disabling trade routes when there's nothing to transport.[PARAGRAPH:2]Remember that restarting exports won't take effect until the next turn. This means it isn't well suited for cases where you both import and export at the same time.</English>
        <French>[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Activation/désactivation automatique des exportations au début du tour [COLOR_REVERT][PARAGRAPH:2]Un nombre élevé de routes commerciales ralentit le jeu. Cette fonctionnalité permet de désactiver les routes commerciales lorsqu'il n'y a rien à transporter.[PARAGRAPH:2]N'oubliez pas que le redémarrage des exportations ne prend effet qu'au tour suivant. Cela signifie qu'elle n'est pas bien adaptée aux cas où vous importez et exportez en même temps.</French>
        <German>[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Automatisches Ein- und Ausschalten des Exports bei Rundenbeginn[COLOR_REVERT][PARAGRAPH:2]Da eine hohe Anzahl von Handelsrouten das Spiel verlangsamt, ermöglicht diese Funktion es, Handelsrouten zu deaktivieren, wenn es nichts zu transportieren gibt.[PARAGRAPH:2]Denken Sie daran, dass das erneute Starten der Exporte erst in der nächsten Runde wirksam wird. Das heißt, es ist nicht gut geeignet für Fälle, in denen Sie gleichzeitig importieren und exportieren.</German>
        <Italian>[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Automatico attiva/disattiva le esportazioni all'inizio del turno[COLOR_REVERT][PARAGRAPH:2]Un alto numero di rotte commerciali rallenta il gioco. Questa funzione permette di disabilitare le rotte commerciali quando non c'è nulla da trasportare.[PARAGRAPH:2]Ricorda che il riavvio delle esportazioni non avrà effetto fino al turno successivo. Questo significa che non è adatto ai casi in cui si importa e si esporta allo stesso tempo.</Italian>
        <Spanish>[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Activación/desactivación automática de la exportación al inicio del turno[COLOR_REVERT][PARAGRAPH:2]Un número elevado de rutas comerciales ralentiza el juego. Esta característica permite desactivar las rutas comerciales cuando no hay nada que transportar.[PARAGRAPH:2]Recuerda que el reinicio de las exportaciones no tendrá efecto hasta el siguiente turno. Esto significa que no es adecuado para los casos en los que se importa y exporta al mismo tiempo.</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_TRADE_ROUTES_MAIN_TABLE</Tag>
        <English>Available transport routes :</English>
        <French>Route commerciale :</French>
        <German>Liste verfügbarer Transportrouten</German>
	<Spanish>Rutas de transporte disponibles</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_TRADE_ROUTES_YIELD_PREVIEW</Tag>
        <English>Yields</English>
        <French>Ressources</French>
        <German>Waren</German>
        <Italian>Yields</Italian>
        <Spanish>Recursos</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_TRADE_ROUTES_YIELD_HELP</Tag>
        <English>Select a yield type for new transport route</English>
        <French>Sélectionner une ressource</French>
        <German>Warentyp für neue Transportroute auswählen</German>
        <Italian>Select a yield type</Italian>
        <Spanish>Seleccione un tipo de recurso para la nueva ruta de transporte</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_TRADE_ROUTES_EXPORT_PREVIEW</Tag>
        <English>Export</English>
        <French>Exporter</French>
        <German>Export</German>
        <Italian>Esportazione</Italian>
        <Spanish>Exportar</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_TRADE_ROUTES_EXPORT_HELP</Tag>
        <English>Select an export city for new transport route (minimum stocks of goods that are not to be transported away can be set locally in the settlement screen)</English>
        <French>Sélectionner une colonie exportatrice</French>
        <German>Exportsiedlung für neue Transportroute auswählen (Mindestbestände von Waren, die nicht abtransportiert werden sollen, lassen sich vor Ort im Siedlungsbildschirm einstellen)</German>
        <Italian>Select an export city</Italian>
        <Spanish>Seleccione una ciudad de exportacion para la nueva ruta de transporte (La cantidad minima de bienes que no seran transportados puede ser configurada localmente en la pantalla del Asentamiento)</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_TRADE_ROUTES_IMPORT_PREVIEW</Tag>
        <English>Import</English>
        <French>Importer</French>
        <German>Import</German>
        <Italian>Importazione</Italian>
        <Spanish>Importar</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_TRADE_ROUTES_IMPORT_HELP</Tag>
        <English>Select an import city for new transport route</English>
        <French>Sélectionner une colonie importatrice</French>
        <German>Importsiedlung für neue Transportroute auswählen</German>
        <Italian>Select an import city</Italian>
        <Spanish>Seleccione una ciudad de importacion, para la nueva ruta de transporte</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_TRADE_ROUTES_NEW_ROUTE</Tag>
        <English>Create new transport route :</English>
        <French>Créer une nouvelle route commerciale :</French>
        <German>Neue Transportroute erstellen :</German>
	<Spanish>Crear nueva ruta de transporte</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_TRADE_ROUTES_YIELD_TABLE</Tag>
        <English>Yield types :</English>
        <French>Ressource :</French>
        <German>Warentyp :</German>
	<Spanish>Tipos de Recursos</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_TRADE_ROUTES_EXPORT_TABLE</Tag>
        <English>Source city :</English>
        <French>Provenance :</French>
        <German>Exportsiedlung :</German>
	<Spanish>Ciudad de origen</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_TRADE_ROUTES_IMPORT_TABLE</Tag>
        <English>Destination city :</English>
        <French>Destination :</French>
        <German>Importsiedlung :</German>
	<Spanish>Ciudad destino</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_TRADE_ROUTES_LOAD_GROUP_TABLE</Tag>
        <English>Load group :</English>
        <French>Groupe de Route :</French>
        <German>Gruppe laden :</German>
        <Italian>Gruppo di Carico :</Italian>
        <Spanish>Grupo de Carga :</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_HELP_LOAD_TRADE_GROUP</Tag>
        <English> ([COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; Click &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] to load)</English>
        <French> (cliquer pour charger)</French>
        <German> ([COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; Anklicken &gt;[COLOR_REVERT], um zu laden)</German>
        <Italian> (clicca per caricare)</Italian>
        <Spanish> ([COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; Clic &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] para cargar)</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_NAME_COL_TRADE_GROUP</Tag>
        <English>Name</English>
        <French>Nom</French>
        <German>Name</German>
        <Italian>Nome</Italian>
        <Spanish>Nombre</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_DESC_COL_TRADE_GROUP</Tag>
        <English>Description</English>
        <French>Description</French>
        <German>Beschreibung</German>
        <Italian>Descrizione</Italian>
        <Spanish>Descripción</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_TRADE_ROUTES_DELETE_GROUP_TABLE</Tag>
        <English>Delete group :</English>
        <French>Supprimer Groupe :</French>
        <German>Gruppe entfernen :</German>
        <Italian>Elimina Gruppo :</Italian>
        <Spanish>Eliminar Grupo :</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_HELP_DELETE_TRADE_GROUP</Tag>
        <English> ([COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; Click &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] to delete)</English>
        <French> (cliquer pour effacer)</French>
        <German> ([COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; Anklicken &gt;[COLOR_REVERT], um zu löschen)</German>
        <Italian> (clic per rimuovere)</Italian>
        <Spanish> ([COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; Clic &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] para borrar)</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_TRADE_ROUTES_EXPORT_TABLE_2</Tag>
        <English>Name</English>
        <French>Nom</French>
        <German>Name</German>
        <Italian>Name</Italian>
        <Spanish>Nombre</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_TRADE_ROUTES_MAIN_TABLE_3</Tag>
        <English>from</English>
        <French>de</French>
        <German>von</German>
        <Italian>from</Italian>
        <Spanish>de</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_TRADE_ROUTES_MAIN_TABLE_4</Tag>
        <English>to</English>
        <French>vers</French>
        <German>nach</German>
        <Italian>to</Italian>
        <Spanish>hasta</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_TRADE_ROUTES_MISSING_YIELD</Tag>
        <English>-</English>
        <French>-</French>
        <German>-</German>
        <Italian>-</Italian>
        <Spanish>-</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_TRADE_ROUTES_MISSING_CITY</Tag>
        <English>-</English>
        <French>-</French>
        <German>-</German>
        <Italian>-</Italian>
        <Spanish>-</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_TRADE_ROUTES_CLEAR_SELECTION_HELP</Tag>
        <English>Remove selection</English>
        <French>Annuler la sélection</French>
        <German>Auswahl löschen</German>
        <Italian>Remove selection</Italian>
        <Spanish>Remover seleccion</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_TRADE_ROUTES_SELECT_ROUTES_HELP</Tag>
        <English>Assign all transport routes of this list to the unit</English>
        <French>Activer toutes les routes commerciales</French>
        <German>Alle Transportrouten dieser Liste der Einheit zuweisen</German>
        <Italian>Activate all shown trade routes</Italian>
        <Spanish>Asignar todas las rutas de transporte de esta lista a la unidad</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_TRADE_ROUTES_DESELECT_ROUTES_HELP</Tag>
        <English>Deactivate all currently assigned transport routes for this unit</English>
        <French>Désactiver toutes les routes commerciales</French>
        <German>Alle derzeit zugewiesenen Transportrouten für diese Einheit deaktivieren</German>
	<Spanish>Desactivar todos los transportes asignados actualmente para esta unidad</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_TRADE_ROUTES_RETURN_HELP</Tag>
        <English>Return to transport routes main view</English>
        <French>Retourner au menu principal des routes commerciales</French>
        <German>Zur Routenübersicht zurückkehren</German>
        <Italian>Return to trade routes main view</Italian>
        <Spanish>Regresar a la vista principal</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_TRADE_ROUTES_IGNORE_DANGER_HELP</Tag>
        <English>Unit does currently stop when an enemy comes into view ([COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; Click &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] to change)</English>
        <French>Ignorer les dangers</French>
        <German>Einheit hält derzeit an, wenn ein Feind in Sichtweite gerät ([COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; Anklicken &gt;[COLOR_REVERT], um das zu ändern)</German>
	<Spanish>Unidad se detendrá cuando aparezca un enemigo ([COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; Clic &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] para cambiar)</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_TRADE_ROUTES_CANCEL_IGNORE_DANGER_HELP</Tag>
        <English>Unit does not currently stop when an enemy comes into view ([COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; Click &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] to change)</English>
        <French>Annuler l'ordre d'ignorer les dangers</French>
        <German>Einheit hält nicht derzeit an, wenn ein Feind in Sichtweite gerät ([COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; Anklicken &gt;[COLOR_REVERT], um das zu ändern)</German>
	<Spanish>Unidad no se detendrá cuando un enemigo aparezca ([COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; Clic &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] para cambiar)</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_TRADE_ROUTES_ADD_SELECTION_HELP</Tag>
        <English>Confirm this transport route and make it available for transport units</English>
        <French>Ajouter la sélection en tant que nouvelle route commerciale</French>
        <German>Diese Transportroute bestätigen und für Transporteinheiten zur Verfügung stellen</German>
	<Spanish>Confirmar esta ruta de transporte y hacerla disponible para las unidades de transporte</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_TRADE_ROUTES_HELP_HELP</Tag>
        <English>: Help</English>
        <French>: Aide</French>
        <German>: Anleitung</German>
        <Italian>: Help</Italian>
        <Spanish>: Ayuda</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_POPUP_CHOOSE_PROFESSION_UNREST</Tag>
        <English>The colony is in chaos. Nobody will be able to leave before order is restored.</English>
	<Spanish>La colonia es un caos. Nadie podra irse hasta que el orden sea restaurado</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>
