<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<!-- edited with XMLSPY v2004 rel. 2 U (http://www.xmlspy.com) by lcollins (Firaxis Games) -->
<!-- Sid Meier's Civilization 4 -->
<!-- Copyright Firaxis Games 2005 -->
<!-- -->
<!-- Game Text - New -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CREDITS_BUTTON</Tag>
		<English>WTP - Credits</English>
		<French>WTP - Crédits</French>
		<Russian>WTP - Спасибо</Russian>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CREDITS_HEAD</Tag>
		<English>We The People - Credits</English>
		<French>We The People - Crédits</French>
		<Russian>We The People - Благодарности</Russian>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CREDITS_WTP</Tag>
		<English>[H1]"We The People" (WTP)[\H1]</English>
		<Russian>[H1]Команда "We The People" (WTP)[\H1]</Russian>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CREDITS_SPECIAL</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Special Credits[\H1]</English>
		<French>[H1]Nos remerciements particuliers[\H1]</French>
		<German>[H1]Besonderen Dank[\H1]</German>
		<Spanish>[H1]Agradecimientos Especiales[\H1]</Spanish>
		<Russian>[H1]Особая благодарность[\H1]</Russian>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CREDITS_RAR</Tag>
		<English>[H1]"Religion and Revolution" (RaR)[\H1] has been developed by an international mod-team at CivFanatics.</English>
		<French>[H1]"Religion and Revolution" (RaR)[\H1]a été développé par une équipe internationale de moddeurs sur le site de CivFanatics.</French>
		<Russian>[H1]"Religion and Revolution" (RaR)[\H1] разработаный международной командой моддеров CivFanatics</Russian>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CREDITS_TAC</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Special Credits to "The Authentic Colonization" (TAC), including former members:[\H1]</English>
		<French>[H1]Nous tenons à remercier tout particulièrement les membres de l'équipe de développement du mod TAC ("The Authentic Colonization") y compris les anciens membres[\H1]</French>
		<Russian>[H1]Особенная благодарность команде "The Authentic Colonization" (TAC), включая бывших участников:[\H1]</Russian>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CREDITS_MUSIC</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Special Credits for our Soundtrack to Rene Osmanczyk who allowed us to use his fantastic work.[\H1]</English>
		<French>[H1]Nous remercions chaleureusement Rene Osmanczyk pour a bande-son extraordinaire.[\H1]</French>
		<Russian>[H1]Особая благодарность за наш саундтрек Rene Osmanczyk, который позволил нам использовать его фантастическую работу.[\H1]</Russian>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CREDITS_OTHER_PROJECTS</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Credits to artists, modders and projects for work included:[\H1]</English>
		<French>[H1]Nous remercions aussi les artistes, moddeurs ou projets dont les travaux ont été inclus:[\H1]</French>
		<Russian>[H1]Наша благодарность художникам, моддерам и сторонникам за их работу:[\H1]</Russian>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CREDITS_OTHER_PROJECTS_TAC</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Further Credits go other artists, modders and projects for work included through TAC:[\H1]
[ICON_BULLET] Netbandit (Netbandit's balance MOD)
[ICON_BULLET] Dale (Age of Discovery II; Achievements v1.00)
[ICON_BULLET] cgtextures.com (textures)
[ICON_BULLET] the_suebian (background images)
[ICON_BULLET] cephalo (script Faire Weather)
[ICON_BULLET] ledat (script Hemispherical)
[ICON_BULLET] Ekmek (leaderheads)
[ICON_BULLET] Mangammal (leaderhead model)
[ICON_BULLET] Aymerick (artwork plantation, parts of whaling, parts of route planning)
[ICON_BULLET] Deliverator &amp; BLU-Mod-Team (units)
[ICON_BULLET] oleg153 (artwork units)
[ICON_BULLET] charle88 (artwork units)
[ICON_BULLET] Kailric (artwork units, parts of whaling feature)
[ICON_BULLET] jdog5000 (code attacks of AI)
[ICON_BULLET] hrochland (artwork tornado)
[ICON_BULLET] Fierabras (events "tornado" and "volcano")
[ICON_BULLET] Kissa (artwork mountain)
[ICON_BULLET] Team of Fall for Heaven (artwork desert)
[ICON_BULLET] Marry Harrsch (foto)
[ICON_BULLET] Aeterna (French Translation)</English>
		<French>[H1]Nous remercions également d'autres contributeurs dont le travail avait été repris par TAC:[\H1][NEWLINE]
[ICON_BULLET] Netbandit (Netbandit's balance MOD)
[ICON_BULLET] Dale (Age of Discovery II; Achievements v1.00)
[ICON_BULLET] cgtextures.com (textures)
[ICON_BULLET] the_suebian (images de fond)
[ICON_BULLET] cephalo (script Faire Weather)
[ICON_BULLET] ledat (script Hemispherical)
[ICON_BULLET] Ekmek (leaderheads)
[ICON_BULLET] Mangammal (modèle de leaderhead)
[ICON_BULLET] Aymerick (graphisme des plantations, composants pour pêche à la baleine et planification de routes commerciales)
[ICON_BULLET] Deliverator &amp; BLU-Mod-Team (unités)
[ICON_BULLET] oleg153 (graphismes d'unités)
[ICON_BULLET] charle88 (graphismes d'unités)
[ICON_BULLET] Kailric (graphismes d'unités, composants pour pêche à la baleine)
[ICON_BULLET] jdog5000 (code pour attaque IA)
[ICON_BULLET] hrochland (graphismes du cyclone)
[ICON_BULLET] Fierabras (événements "cyclone" and "volcan")
[ICON_BULLET] Kissa (graphismes des montagnes)
[ICON_BULLET] L'équipe de Fall for Heaven (graphismes du désert)
[ICON_BULLET] Marry Harrsch (photo)
[ICON_BULLET] Aeterna (Traduction française)</French>
		<Russian>[H1]Отдельная благодарность другим художникам, моддерам и сторонникам за их работу, включенную в TAC:[\H1]
[ICON_BULLET] Netbandit (Netbandit's balance MOD)
[ICON_BULLET] Dale (Age of Discovery II; Достижения v1.00)
[ICON_BULLET] cgtextures.com (текстуры)
[ICON_BULLET] the_suebian (рисунки заднего плана)
[ICON_BULLET] cephalo (скрипт Faire Weather)
[ICON_BULLET] ledat (скрипт Hemispherical)
[ICON_BULLET] Ekmek (лидеры)
[ICON_BULLET] Mangammal (модели лидеров)
[ICON_BULLET] Aymerick (рисунки плантации, части китобойного промысла, части планирования маршрута)
[ICON_BULLET] Deliverator &amp; BLU-Mod-Team (юниты)
[ICON_BULLET] oleg153 (рисунки юнитов)
[ICON_BULLET] charle88 (рисунки юнитов)
[ICON_BULLET] Kailric (рисунки юнитов, части китобойного промысла)
[ICON_BULLET] jdog5000 (кодирование поведения ИИ)
[ICON_BULLET] hrochland (рисунки торнадо)
[ICON_BULLET] Fierabras (события "торнадо" и "вулкан")
[ICON_BULLET] Kissa (рисунки гор)
[ICON_BULLET] Team of Fall for Heaven (рисунки пустыни)
[ICON_BULLET] Marry Harrsch (фотографии)
[ICON_BULLET] Aeterna (перевод на фрацузский)</Russian>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CREDITS_END</Tag>
		<English>And we don't want to forget to thank Firaxis and 2Kgames for their masterpiece Civ4/BtS. We use a lot of material from these games.[NEWLINE]
The copyright of these materials belongs to the respective owners. In most cases we got permission to use their materials but in some cases we didn't. We ask these authors to contact us as to whether we can use their material. The copyright of the changes the TAC team has done to these materials belongs to TAC. The copyright of changes the RaR team has done to these materials belongs to RaR. The copyright of changes the WtP team has done to these materials belongs to WtP.[NEWLINE]
The copyright of "Sid Meier's Civilisation IV: Colonization" belongs to Take Two Interactive. Sid Meier's Civilization IV: Colonization, Civ, Civilization, 2K Games, the 2K-Logo, Firaxis Games, the Firaxis game logo and Take-Two Interactive Software are registered trademarks of Take-Two Interactive Software, Inc. Developed by Firaxis Games.[NEWLINE]
Some textures on our 3D-models have been created with images from CGTextures.com. These images may not be redistributed by default. Please visit www.cgtextures.com for more information.[NEWLINE]
RaR is a non-commercial mod project. If you use or distribute RaR please pay attention to the copyright. We allow usage and distribution as long as RaR remains non-commercial.[NEWLINE]
As a matter of course it is permitted to use RaR in an own mod project as long as the copyrights are not harmed, and it remains a non-commercial project. If you use RaR in an own mod project you have to make clear that you have done changes to the original TAC and to RaR. If you wish to use artwork, we could give you more information about the creators so that you can mention them in the credits of your own modification.[NEWLINE]
You can contact TAC, RaR and WtP via CivFanatics forum (you will find the link in the readme file) or via email to writing.bull@gmx.de.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]</English>
		<French>Et nous n'oublions pas de remercier Firaxis et 2Kgames pour leur chef d'oeuvre Civ4/BtS. De nombreux éléments ont été repris de ces jeux.[NEWLINE]
Les droits de reproduction de ces éléments appartiennent à leurs propriétaires respectifs. Dans la plupart des cas nous avons eu l'autorisation de les utiliser, sauf exception. Nous remercions les propriétaires de nous contacter pour nous donner ou non cette autorisation. Les droits liés à l'utilisation de TAC appartiennent à l'équipe de TAC. Les droits liés à l'utilisation de RAR appartiennent à l'équipe de RAR. Les droits liés à l'utilisation de WtP appartiennent à l'équipe de WtP.[NEWLINE]
Les droits de reproduction de "Sid Meier's Civilisation IV: Colonization" appartiennent à Take Two Interactive. Sid Meier's Civilization IV: Colonization, Civ, Civilization, 2K Games, the 2K-Logo, Firaxis Games, the Firaxis game logo and Take-Two Interactive Software sont des marques déposées de Take-Two Interactive Software, Inc. Developé par Firaxis Games.[NEWLINE]
Quelques textures de nos modèles 3D ont été créées avec des images de CGTextures.com. Ces images ne sont pas redistribuées par défaut. Merci de visiter www.cgtextures.com pour plus d'information.[NEWLINE]
RaR est un projet à but non commercial. Si vous utilisez ou distribuez RaR, merci de faire attention à ces droits de reproduction. Nous autorisons l'utilisation et la distribution qu'à la condition que RaR reste à usage non-commercial.[NEWLINE]
Il est par ailleurs permis d'utiliser RAR pour d'autres projets de mods à la condition que les droits de reproduction soient respectés, et s'il s'agit également de projets non-commerciaux. Si vous utilisez RaR pour un projet personnel, vous devez spécifier qu'il s'agit d'une version modifiée des projets TAC et RaR. Si vous souhaitez utiliser des graphismes, nous pouvons vous donner plus d'informations sur leurs créateurs de façon à les mentionner dans vos crédits.[NEWLINE]
Vous pouvez contacter TAC, RaR et WtP via le site "CivFanatics forum" (vous trouverez le lien dans le fichier readme) ; ou par e-mail : writing.bull@gmx.de.</French>
		<Russian>Мы также благодарны Firaxis и 2Kgames за их шедевр Civ4/BtS. Мы используем много материала из этих игр.[NEWLINE]Авторские права на эти материалы принадлежат соответствующим правообладателям. В большинстве случаев мы получили разрешение на использование их материалов, но в некоторых случаях мы этого не сделали. Мы просим этих авторов связаться с нами, чтобы узнать, можем ли мы использовать их материалы. Авторские права на изменения, внесенные командой TAC в эти материалы, принадлежат TAC. Авторские права на изменения, внесенные командой RaR в эти материалы, принадлежат RaR.Авторские права на изменения, внесенные командой WtP в эти материалы, принадлежат WtP.[NEWLINE]Авторские права на "Sid Meier's Civilization IV: Colonization" принадлежат Take Two Interactive. Sid Meier's Civilization IV: Colonization, Civ, Civilization, 2K Games, 2K-Logo, Firaxis Games, игровой логотип Firaxis и Take-Two Interactive Software являются зарегистрированными товарными знаками Take-Two Interactive Software, Inc., разработанными Firaxis Games.[NEWLINE]Некоторые текстуры на наших 3D-моделях созданы с использованием изображений с сайта CGTextures.com. Эти изображения не могут распространяться по умолчанию. Посетите сайт www.cgtextures.com для получения дополнительной информации.[NEWLINE]WtP — это некоммерческий мод-проект. Если вы используете или распространяете WtP, обратите внимание на авторские права. Мы разрешаем использование и распространение, пока WtP остается некоммерческим.[NEWLINE]Разумеется, разрешено использовать WtP в собственном мод-проекте, если не нарушаются авторские права и он остается некоммерческим проектом. Если вы используете WtP в собственном проекте мода, вы должны четко указать, что вы внесли изменения в исходный TAC, RaR и WtP. Если вы хотите использовать обложку, мы можем предоставить вам больше информации о создателях, чтобы вы могли упомянуть их в титрах своей модификации.[NEWLINE]Вы можете связаться с командой WtP через форум CivFanatics или группу ВК (ссылки есть в Readme).</Russian>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CREDITS_FURSTBISCHOF</Tag>
		<English>Fürstbischof</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CREDITS_RAUWURGER</Tag>
		<English>Raubwürger</English>
	</TEXT>
		<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CREDITS_f1rpo</Tag>
		<English>f1rpo (continous support related to coding)</English>
		<German>f1rpo (wiederholte Unterstützung zu Code)</German>
		<Spanish>f1rpo (ayuda repetida con código)</Spanish>
		<Russian>f1rpo (постоянная поддержка, связанная с кодированием)</Russian>
	</TEXT>
		<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CREDITS_karadoc</Tag>
		<English>karadoc (for his pathfinding code)</English>
		<German>karadoc (für seinen Pathfinding Code)</German>
		<Spanish>karadoc (por su algoritmo de búsqueda)</Spanish>
		<Russian>karadoc (за его код поиска пути)</Russian>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CREDITS_FORMER_MEMBER</Tag>
		<English>(former member)</English>
		<German>(früheres Mitglied)</German>
		<French>(ex-membre)</French>
		<Spanish>(ex-miembro)</Spanish>
		<Russian>(бывшие участники)</Russian>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CREDITS_MELCHER_KURZER</Tag>
		<English>melcher kürzer</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CREDITS_STOPSEL</Tag>
		<English>Stöpsel</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CREDITS_OTHER_NAME_1</Tag>
		<English>Victor Meirelles (Painting: Primeira missa no Brasil)</English>
		<French>Victor Meirelles (Peinture : Primeira missa no Brasil)</French>
		<Russian>Victor Meirelles (Картина: Первая месса в Бразилии)</Russian>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CREDITS_OTHER_NAME_2</Tag>
		<English>John Trumbull (Painting: The Death of General Warren at the Battle of Bunker Hill)</English>
		<French>John Trumbull (Peinture : The Death of General Warren at the Battle of Bunker Hill)</French>
		<Russian>John Trumbull (Картина: Смерть генерала Уоррена в битве при Банкер-Хилле)</Russian>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CREDITS_OTHER_NAME_3</Tag>
		<English>George Walter Vincent Smith (Painting: New England Scenery)</English>
		<French>George Walter Vincent Smith (Peinture : New England Scenery)</French>
		<Russian>George Walter Vincent Smith (Картина: Пейзаж Новой Англии)</Russian>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CREDITS_OTHER_NAME_4</Tag>
		<English>Clint Mansell (Main Theme)</English>
		<French>Clint Mansell (Thème principal)</French>
		<Russian>Clint Mansell (Главная тема)</Russian>
	</TEXT>
	<!-- Readme -->
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_README_BUTTON</Tag>
		<English>WtP concept</English>
		<French>Concept de WtP</French>
		<German>WtP-Konzept</German>
		<Russian>Концепция WtP</Russian>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_README_HEAD</Tag>
		<English>We the People</English>
		<French>We the People</French>
		<German>We the People</German>
		<Italian>We the People</Italian>
		<Spanish>We the People</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_README_TEXT</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Welcome to "We the People" - WtP ![\H1][NEWLINE]
[H2]The idea behind "We the People" is simple: We want to create the largest and best CivCol-Mod ever ![\H2][NEWLINE]
Thus we have chosen "The Authentic Colonization" (TAC) and "Religion and Revolution" (RaR) as base for this project and added many many cool features and improvements to it.[NEWLINE]
Enjoy![NEWLINE]
		</English>
		<French>[H1]Bienvenue dans "We the People" - WtP ![\H1][NEWLINE]
[H2]L'idée derrière "We the People" est simple : nous voulons créer le plus grand et le meilleur mod pour CivCol ![\H2][NEWLINE]
C'est pourquoi nous avons choisi de prendre "The Authentic Colonization" (TAC) et "Religion and Revolution" (RaR) comme base en y ajoutant de nouveaux éléments et améliorations.[NEWLINE]
Faites-vous plaisir ![NEWLINE]
		</French>
		<German>[H1]Willkommen zu "We the People" - WtP ![\H1][NEWLINE]
[H2]Die Grundidee zu "We the People" ist einfach: Wir wollen die grösste und beste CivCol-Mod aller Zeiten schaffen ![\H2][NEWLINE]
Deshalb haben wir uns für "The Authentic Colonization" (TAC) und "Religion and Revolution" (RaR) als Basis entschlossen und viele neue Features und Verbesserungen hinzugefügt.[NEWLINE]
Viel Spass![NEWLINE]
		</German>
		<Russian>[H1]Добро пожаловать в мод "We the People" — WtP![\H1][NEWLINE][H2]Идея "We the People" проста: мы хотим создать самый большой и лучший CivCol-Mod![\H2][NEWLINE]Поэтому мы выбрали "The Authentic Colonization" (TAC) и "Religion and Revolution" (RaR) в качестве основы для этого проекта и добавили множество интересных функций и улучшений.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Наслаждайтесь![NEWLINE]</Russian>
	</TEXT>
	<!-- Hints -->
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_1</Tag>
		<English>Once vigorous measures appear to be the only means left of bringing the Americans to a due submission to the mother country, the colonies will submit.[NEWLINE]--- George III, King of Great Britain in the period 1760-1820</English>
		<French>Lorsque des mesures vigoureuses sembleront être le seul moyen qu'il reste pour ramener les américains à leur soumission légitime envers leur mère patrie, les colonies se soummettront.[NEWLINE]--- George III, Roi de Grande-Bretagne dans la période 1760-1820</French>
		<German>Once vigorous measures appear to be the only means left of bringing the Americans to a due submission to the mother country, the colonies will submit.[NEWLINE]--- George III, König von Großbritannien in der Zeit von 1760-1820</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_2</Tag>
		<English>A traitor is everyone who does not agree with me.[NEWLINE]--- George III, King of Great Britain in the period 1760-1820</English>
		<French>Un traître est quiconque n'est pas d'accord avec moi.[NEWLINE]--- George III, Roi de Grande-Bretagne dans la période 1760-1820</French>
		<German>A traitor is everyone who does not agree with me.[NEWLINE]--- George III, König von Großbritannien in der Zeit von 1760-1820</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_3</Tag>
		<English>America owes most of its social prejudices to the exaggerated religious opinions of the different sects which were so instrumental in establishing the colonies.[NEWLINE]--- James Fenimore Cooper (1789 - 1851), novelist</English>
		<French>L'Amérique doit la plupart de ses préjugés sociaux aux opinions religieuses si prévalentes des différentes chapelles qui furent si fondamentales à l'établissement des colonies.[NEWLINE]--- James Fenimore Cooper (1789 - 1851), romancier.</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_4</Tag>
		<English>Slavery is no more sinful, by the Christian code, than it is sinful to wear a whole coat, while another is in tatters, to eat a better meal than a neighbour, or otherwise to enjoy ease and plenty, while our fellow creatures are suffering and in want.[NEWLINE]--- James Fenimore Cooper (1789 - 1851), novelist</English>
		<French>L'esclavage n'est pas plus un pêché, selon le code de conduite chrétien, que ne le sont le fait de porter un manteau confortable, quand un autre est en lambeaux, de mieux manger que son voisin, ou jouir de l'abondance et d'une vie facile, quand nos frères souffrent et manquent de tout.[NEWLINE]--- James Fenimore Cooper (1789 - 1851), romancier.</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_5</Tag>
		<English>The Indian Corn, or Maiz, proves the most useful Grain in the World; and had it not been for the Fruitfulness of this Species, it would have proved very difficult to have settled some of the Plantations in America.[NEWLINE]--- John Lawson (1674 - 1711), British explorer</English>
		<French>Le blé indien, ou maïs, s'est montré la meilleure céréale dans ce monde, et sans l'abondance et la fertilité de cette plante, l'établissement des Plantations en Amériques se serait avéré bien difficile.[NEWLINE]--- John Lawson (1674 - 1711), explorateur britannique</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_6</Tag>
		<English>There are not enough Indians in the world to defeat the Seventh Cavalry.[NEWLINE]--- George Armstrong Custer, Seventh Cavalry Commander, prior to being massacred by the Sioux at the Battle of Little Bighorn (June 25-26, 1876)</English>
		<French>Il n'y a pas assez d'indiens dans ce monde pour battre la Septième Cavalerie.[NEWLINE]--- George Armstrong Custer, Commandant de la Septième Cavalerie, avant de se faire massacrer avec ses troupes par les Sioux à la bataille de Little Bighorn (25-26 juin 1876)</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_7</Tag>
		<English>The Indians gave up the land of their own free will, and for it received brass kettles, blankets, guns, shirts, flints, tobacco, rum and many trinkets in which their simple hearts delighted.[NEWLINE]--- Patrick Gordon (1635 - 1699), Scottish explorer</English>
		<French>Les Indiens ont cédé leurs terres de leur plein gré, et ils ont reçu en échange des bouilloires, des couvertures, des fusils, des vêtements, du tabac, du rhum, et biens des babioles qui ont ravi leur esprit simple.[NEWLINE]--- Patrick Gordon (1635 - 1699), Explorateur écossais</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_8</Tag>
		<English>It affords me sincere pleasure to be able to apprise you of the entire removal of the Cherokee Nation of Indians to their new homes west of the Mississippi.[NEWLINE]--- Martin Van Buren, 8th President of the United States</English>
		<French>J'ai le plus grand plaisir de pouvoir vous annoncer la déportation de toute la nation indienne des Cherokees vers leur nouveau domicile à l'ouest du Mississippi.[NEWLINE]--- Martin Van Buren, 8e président des États-Unis</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_9</Tag>
		<English>We derive our authority from God and the West India Company, not from the pleasure of a few ignorant subjects.[NEWLINE]--- Peter Stuyvesant, directeur-generaal of Nieuw-Nederland in the period 1647-1664</English>
		<French>Nous tenons notre autorité de Dieu et de la Companie des Indes Occidentales, et non du bon-vouloir d'une poignée de sujets idiots.[NEWLINE]--- Peter Stuyvesant, directeur-général de la Nouvelle-Néerlande dans la période 1647-1664</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_10</Tag>
		<English>We pray that the deceitful race - such hateful enemies and blasphemers of the name of Christ - be not allowed to further infect and trouble this new colony.[NEWLINE]--- Peter Stuyvesant, directeur-generaal of Nieuw-Nederland in the period 1647-1664, on Jewish citizens of Nieuw-Amsterdam</English>
		<French>Nous prions que cette race perfide - des ennemis haineux et blasphémateurs envers le Christ - ne soit pas autorisé à infester davantage et gâter cette nouvelle colonie[NEWLINE]--- Peter Stuyvesant, directeur-général de la Nouvelle-Néerlande dans la période 1647-1664, au sujet des juifs établis à la Nouvelle-Amsterdam</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_11</Tag>
		<English>Money is the father of luxury, lasciviousness, intrigues, trickery, lies, betrayal, insincerity – of all the world's worst behaviour. Fathers sell their children, husbands their wives, wives betray their husbands, brothers kill each other, friends are false, and all because of money. In the light of all this, tell me that we Wendat are not right in refusing to touch, or so much to look at silver?[NEWLINE]--- Kondiaronk, Wendat Chief, 1703</English>
		<French>L'argent, la monnaie est la source de la luxure, de la débauche, des intrigues, des tromperies, des mensonges, des trahisons, et de la fausseté - des pires comportements au monde. Des pères vendent leurs enfants, des maris leur femmes, les femmes trompent leur mari, les frères s'entretuent, les amis sont faux, et tout à cause de l'argent. En voyant tout cela, dites-moi que nous, Wendats, avons tort de refuser à toucher, et même de regarder l'argent?[NEWLINE]--- Kondiaronk, chef des Wendats, 1703  </French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_12</Tag>
		<English>The attack did not succeed as well as I had hoped, no small impediment having been the loss of my right leg.[NEWLINE]--- Peter Stuyvesant, directeur-generaal of Nieuw-Nederland in the period 1647-1664</English>
		<French>L'attaque ne réussit pas aussi bien que je ne l'avais espéré, un des coups du sort fut la perte de ma jambe droite.[NEWLINE]--- Peter Stuyvesant, directeur-général de la Nouvelle-Néerlande dans la période 1647-1664</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_13</Tag>
		<English>I value the blood of one Christian more than that of a hundred Indians.[NEWLINE]--- Peter Stuyvesant, directeur-generaal of Nieuw-Nederland in the period 1647-1664</English>
		<French>J'estime davantage le sang d'un seul chrétien que celui de cent Indiens [NEWLINE]--- Peter Stuyvesant, directeur-général de la Nouvelle-Néerlande dans la période 1647-1664</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_14</Tag>
		<English>There are apothecaries' shops, where prepared medicines, liquids, ointments, and plasters are sold; barbers' shops, where they wash and shave the head; and restaurateurs, that furnish food and drink at a certain price.[NEWLINE]--- Hernán Cortés, Spanish conquistador, on the Aztec capital of Tenochtitlan (November 8, 1519)</English>
		<French>Il y a des boutiques d'apothiquaires, où l'on vent des remèdes tout prêts, des liquides, des onguents, et des cataplames; des barbiers, où ils lavent et rasent la têtes, et des restaurateurs; qui fournissent nourritures et boisson à un certain prix.[NEWLINE]--- Hernán Cortés, Conquistador espagnol, au sujet de la capitale aztèque de Tenochtitlan, le 9 novembre 1519</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_15</Tag>
		<English>The city is as large as Sevilla or Córdoba; its streets, I speak of the principal ones, are very wide and straight; some of these, and all the inferior ones, are half land and half water, and are navigated by canoes.[NEWLINE]--- Hernán Cortés, Spanish conquistador, on the Aztec capital of Tenochtitlan (November 8, 1519)</English>
		<French>La cité est aussi grande que Séville ou Cordoue; ses artères principales sont très larges et droites, et les secondaires, sont mi-rues, mi-canaux, et il y navigue des canoës.[NEWLINE]--- Hernán Cortés, Conquistador espagnol, au sujet de la capitale aztèque de Tenochtitlan, le 9 novembre 1519</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_16</Tag>
		<English>Among these temples there is one which far surpasses all the rest, whose grandeur of architectural details no human tongue is able to describe; for within its precincts, surrounded by a lofty wall, there is room enough for a town of five hundred families.[NEWLINE]--- Hernán Cortés, Spanish conquistador, on the Aztec capital of Tenochtitlan (November 8, 1519)</English>
		<French>Parmi ces temples il y en a un qui surpasse tous les autres, dont la grandeur des détails d'architecture surpasse toute description ; En son sein, entouré d'un mur imposant, il y a assez de place pour une ville de cinq cents familles.[NEWLINE]--- Hernán Cortés, Conquistador espagnol, au sujet de la capitale aztèque de Tenochtitlan, le 9 novembre 1519</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_17</Tag>
		<English>If the freedom of speech is taken away then dumb and silent we may be led, like sheep to the slaughter.[NEWLINE]--- George Washington (1732 - 1799), Commander-in-Chief of the Continental Army and first President of the United States</English>
		<French>Si la liberté de la presse est retirée, alors nous pourrions être menés aveuglement et sans bruit comme des moutons à l'abattoir.[NEWLINE]--- George Washington (1732 - 1799), Commandeur-en-Chef de l'Armée Continentale et Premier président des États-Unis</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_18</Tag>
		<English>The marvel of all history is the patience with which men and women submit to burdens unnecessarily laid upon them by their governments.[NEWLINE]--- George Washington (1732 - 1799), Commander-in-Chief of the Continental Army and first President of the United States</English>
		<French>Une des merveilles de l'histoire et la patience avec laquelle hommes et femmes subissent les tracas superflus que leur imposent leurs gouvernements.[NEWLINE]--- George Washington (1732 - 1799), Commandeur-en-Chef de l'Armée Continentale et Premier président des États-Unis</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_19</Tag>
		<English>The alternate domination of one faction over another, sharpened by the spirit of revenge, natural to party dissension, which in different ages and countries has perpetrated the most horrid enormities, is itself a frightful despotism. But this leads at length to a more formal and permanent despotism. The disorders and miseries which result gradually incline the minds of men to seek security and repose in the absolute power of an individual; and sooner or later the chief of some prevailing faction, more able or more fortunate than his competitors, turns this disposition to the purposes of his own elevation, on the ruins of public liberty.[NEWLINE]--- George Washington (1732 - 1799), President of the United States farewell address, 1796</English>
		<French>L'alternance au pouvoir d'une faction puis de l'autre, aiguisée par l'esprit de revanche accompagnant les désaccords entre les partis, ce qui a perpétué les pires horreurs en d'autres temps et d'autres pays, est en elle même un despotisme atroce. Mais cela mène avec le temps à un autre despotisme de droit plus permanent. Les désordres et les malheurs qui en découlent poussent peu à peu l'esprit des hommes à chercher la sécurité et la quiétude dans le pouvoir absolu d'un seul individu ; tôt ou tard le chef d'une des factions importantes, plus chanceux ou plus abile que ses concurrents, tirera parti de cette tendance pour son propre profit, sur les ruines des libertés publiques.[NEWLINE]--- George Washington (1732 - 1799), Discours d'adieu en tant que président des États-Unis, 1796</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_20</Tag>
		<English>Rebellion to tyrants is obedience to God.[NEWLINE]--- William Penn (1644 - 1718), Founder of Pennsylvania</English>
		<French>La rébellion face aux tyrans est obéir à Dieu[NEWLINE]--- William Penn (1644 - 1718), Fondateur de la Pennsylvanie</French>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_21</Tag>
		<English>This land is naturally fruitful, and capable of supporting a large population, if it were judiciously allotted according to location. The air is pleasant, and more temperate than in Netherland.[NEWLINE]--- Adriaen van der Donck (c.1618 - 1655), Dutch lawyer, on Nieuw-Nederland</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_22</Tag>
		<English>Why does Maxixcatzin deem these people gods, who seem more like ravenous monsters thrown up by the intemperate sea to blight us, gorging themselves on gold, silver, stones and pearls; sleeping in their own clothes; and generally acting in the manner of those who would one day make cruel masters?[NEWLINE]--- Xicotencatl, Tlatoani (elder) of Tlaxcatl (almost one hundred years old), 1520</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_23</Tag>
		<English>The natives are generally well-set in their limbs, slender round the waist, broad across the shoulders, and have black hair and dark eyes. They are very nimble and active, well adapted to travel on foot and to drag heavy burdens. They are divided into different tribes and languages, each tribe living generally by itself, and having one of its number as a chief, though he has not much power or distinction except in their dances or in time of wars. Among some there is not the least knowledge of God, and among others very little, though they relate very strange fables concerning Him.[NEWLINE]--- Adriaen van der Donck (c.1618 - 1655), Dutch lawyer</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_24</Tag>
		<English>A state too expensive in itself, or by virtue of its dependencies, ultimately falls into decay; its free government is transformed into a tyranny; it disregards the principles which it should preserve, and finally degenerates into despotism. The distinguishing characteristic of small republics is stability: the character of large republics is mutability.[NEWLINE]--- Simón Bolívar, Latin American Revolutionary, "Letter from Jamaica" (Summer 1815)</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_25</Tag>
		<English>Colombians! My last wish is for the happiness of the patria. If my death contributes to the end of partisanship and the consolidation of the union, I shall be lowered in peace into my grave.[NEWLINE]--- Simón Bolívar, Latin American Revolutionary, "Final proclamation to the people of Colombia" (December 8, 1830)</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_26</Tag>
		<English>I have fulfilled the sacred promises which I made Peru; I have witnessed the assembly of its representatives; the enemy's force threatens the independence of no place that wishes to be free, and that possesses the means of being so. A numerous army, under the direction of warlike chiefs, is ready to march in a few days to put an end to the war. Nothing is left for me to do, but to offer you my sincerest thanks, and to promise, that if the liberties of the Peruvians shall ever be attacked, I shall claim the honor of accompanying them to defend their freedom like a citizen.[NEWLINE]--- José de San Martín, Latin American Revolutionary, "Resignation address to the Peruvian Congress" (September 22, 1820)</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_27</Tag>
		<English>From this moment on, Peru is free and independent by the general will of its people and by the justice of its cause that God defends. Long live the nation! Long live the freedom! Long live the independence![NEWLINE]--- "Peruvian Declaration of Independence" (July 28, 1821)</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_28</Tag>
		<English>The Indians were totally deprived of their freedom and were put into the harshest, fiercest, most horrible servitude and captivity which no one who has not seen it can understand. Even beasts enjoy more freedom when they are allowed to graze in the field.[NEWLINE]--- Bartolomé de Las Casas, "History of the Indies" (1561)</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_29</Tag>
		<English>Broken spears lie in the roads;[NEWLINE]We have torn our hair in our grief.[NEWLINE]The houses are roofless now, and their walls[NEWLINE]Are red with blood.[NEWLINE]--- Nahuatl poem (16th century)</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_30</Tag>
		<English>Who could conquer Tenochtitlán? Who could shake the foundation of heaven?[NEWLINE]--- Nahuatl poem (15th century)</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_31</Tag>
		<English>Who can doubt that gunpowder against the infidels is incense for the Lord?[NEWLINE]--- Gonzalo Fernández de Oviedo y Valdés, Spanish conquistador, "General and Natural History of the Indies" (1526)</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_32</Tag>
		<English>The Inca asked Fray Vicente who had told him so. Fray Vicente responded that the Gospel had told him, the book. Atahualpa said, "Give me the book, so that it will tell me." So he gave it to him and he took it in his hands and began to look through the pages of the book. The Inca said, "Well, why doesn't it tell me? The book doesn't even talk to me!" Speaking with great majesty, seated in his throne, the Inca Atahualpa threw the book down from his hands. Don Francisco Pizarro and Don Diego de Almagro shouted and said, "Out, knights, against these infidels who are against our Christianity, and for our Emperor and King let us have at them!"[NEWLINE]--- Felipe Guamán Poma de Ayala, "The First New Chronicle and Good Government" (1615), on the conquest of the Incan Empire</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_33</Tag>
		<English>We never bring lawsuits against one another. And why do we never bring lawsuits? Well, because we made a decision neither to accept or make use of money. And why do we refuse to allow money into our communities? The reason is this: we are determined not to have laws – because, since the world was a world, our ancestors have been able to live contentedly without them.[NEWLINE]--- Kondiaronk, Wendat Chief, 1703</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_34</Tag>
		<English>All Christians have a duty toward missions so long as any heathen exists. Christians will be called severely to account if they content themselves merely in carrying on in trading with the heathen.[NEWLINE]--- Hans Egede (1686 - 1758), Danish Lutheran Missionary</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_35</Tag>
		<English>These natives are a very good people; for when they saw that I would not remain, they supposed that I was afraid of their bows; and, taking their arrows, they broke them in pieces and threw them into the fire.[NEWLINE]--- Henry Hudson, English explorer, on the Algonquian natives of the Hudson River (September 4, 1609)</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_36</Tag>
		<English>At this time, they (the Muisca) stripped the heir to his skin, and anointed him with a sticky earth on which they placed gold dust so that he was completely covered with this metal. They placed him on the raft ... and at his feet they placed a great heap of gold and emeralds for him to offer to his God. In the raft with him went four principal subject chiefs, decked in plumes, crowns, bracelets, pendants and ear rings all of gold. They, too, were naked, and each one carried his offering ... when the raft reached the centre of the lagoon, they raised a banner as a signal for silence.[NEWLINE]--- Juan Rodríguez Freyle, "El Carnero" (1638), on the Muisca natives</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_37</Tag>
		<English>The Great Montezuma was about forty years old, of good height and well proportioned, slender, and spare of flesh, not very swarthy, but of the natural colour and shade of an Indian. He did not wear his hair long, but so as just to cover his ears, his scanty black beard was well shaped and thin. His face was somewhat long, but cheerful, and he had good eyes and showed in his appearance and manner both tenderness and, when necessary, gravity. He was very neat and clean and bathed once every day in the afternoon.[NEWLINE]--- Bernal Díaz del Castillo, "The Discovery and Conquest of Mexico" (1568)</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_38</Tag>
		<English>Vigorous measures at present would soon put an end to this rebellion. The deluded people are made to believe that they are invincible... When this army is ordered to act against them, they will soon be convinced that they are very insignificant when opposed to regular troops.[NEWLINE]--- Thomas Pitcairn, Royal Army Commander, in a letter to John Montagu, Lord Sandwich, the British Secretary of State (February 14, 1775)</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_39</Tag>
		<English>By the rude bridge that arched the flood,[NEWLINE]Their flag to April's breeze unfurled,[NEWLINE]Here once the embattled farmers stood,[NEWLINE]And fired the shot heard round the world.[NEWLINE]--- Ralph Waldo Emerson, "Concord Hymn" (1837), commemorating the Battle of Lexington and Concord (April 19, 1775)</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_40</Tag>
		<English>Come out, you old rat. Surrender in the name of the Great Jehovah and the Continental Congress.[NEWLINE]--- Ethan Allen, leader of the Green Mountain Boys, demanding the surrender of the British commander of Fort Ticonderoga (May 10, 1775)</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_41</Tag>
		<English>We must all hang together now, or assuredly we shall hang separately.[NEWLINE]--- Benjamin Franklin, after signing the "Declaration of Independence" (July 4, 1776)</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_42</Tag>
		<English>No man shall be compelled to frequent or support any religious worship, place, or ministry... nor shall otherwise suffer on account of his religious opinions or belief, but that all men shall be free to profess, and by argument to maintain, their opinion on matters of religion.[NEWLINE]--- Thomas Jefferson, "Virginia Bill on Religious Freedom" (1776)</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_43</Tag>
		<English>When once these rebels have felt a smart blow, they will submit.[NEWLINE]--- Comment of a Hessian mercenary, before going into battle against American rebels (1776)</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_44</Tag>
		<English>The unfortunate soldiers were in want of everything; they had neither coats, nor hats, nor shirts, nor shoes; their feet and their legs froze till they grew black and it was often necessary to amputate them... The army frequently passed whole days without food.[NEWLINE]--- Gilbert du Motier, Marquis de La Fayette, on the Continental Army at Valley Forge, Pennsylvania (1777)</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_45</Tag>
		<English>Poor food - hard lodging - cold weather - fatigue - nasty clothes - nasty cookery... There comes a bowl of beef soup, full of burnt leaves and dirt![NEWLINE]--- Albigence Waldo, Continental Army surgeon, writing in his diary on conditions of the army at Valley Forge (1777)</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_46</Tag>
		<English>There was as much sorrow as joy... We had lived together as a family of brothers for several years, setting aside some little family squabbles, like most other families, had shared with each other the hardships, dangers, and sufferings incident to a soldier's life, had sympathized with each other in trouble and in sickness; had assisted in bearing each other's burdens... And now we were to be... parted forever.[NEWLINE]--- Joseph Plumb Martin, Continental Army soldier, in his memoir "Private Yankee Doodle" (1830)</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_47</Tag>
		<English>Here is the God the Spaniards worship. For these they fight and kill; for these they persecute us and that is why we have to throw them into the sea... They tell us, these tyrants, that they adore a God of peace and equality, and yet they usurp our land and make us their slaves. They speak to us of an immortal soul and of their eternal rewards and punishments, and yet they rob our belongings, seduce our women, violate our daughters. Incapable of matching us in valor, these cowards cover themselves with iron that our weapons cannot break.[NEWLINE]--- Hatuey, Arawak cacique, to the Carib natives of Cuba, 1511</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_48</Tag>
		<English>Hatuey, thinking a little, asked the religious man if Spaniards went to heaven. The religious man answered yes... The chief then said without further thought that he did not want to go there but to hell so as not to be where they were and where he would not see such cruel people. This is the name and honor that God and our faith have earned February 2, 1512[NEWLINE]--- Bartolomé de Las Casas, "Brief account of the destruction of the Indies" (1552), on the execution of the Arawak cacique Hatuey</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_49</Tag>
		<English>And never have the Indians in all the Indies committed any act against the Spanish Christians, until those Christians have first and many times committed countless cruel aggressions against them or against neighbouring nations.[NEWLINE]--- Bartolomé de Las Casas, "Brief account of the destruction of the Indies" (1552)</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_50</Tag>
		<English>Their reason for killing and destroying such an infinite number of souls is that the Christians have an ultimate aim, which is to acquire gold, and to swell themselves with riches in a very brief time and thus rise to a high estate disproportionate to their merits.[NEWLINE]--- Bartolomé de Las Casas, "Brief account of the destruction of the Indies" (1552)</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_51</Tag>
		<English>We can estimate very surely and truthfully that in the forty years that have passed, with the infernal actions of the Christians, there have been unjustly slain more than twelve million men, women, and children. In truth, I believe without trying to deceive myself that the number of the slain is more like fifteen million.[NEWLINE]--- Bartolomé de Las Casas, "Brief account of the destruction of the Indies" (1552)</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_52</Tag>
		<English>Compare then the blessings enjoyed by Spaniards of prudence, genius, magnanimity, temperance, humanity, and religion with those of the little men [the Indians] in whom you will scarcely find even vestiges of humanity. ... How can we doubt that these people - so uncivilized, so barbaric, contaminated with so many impieties and obscenities - have been justly conquered?[NEWLINE]--- Juan Ginés de Sepúlveda, to Bartolomé de Las Casas, at the Valladolid debate (1550-1551)</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_53</Tag>
		<English>The Russians went to the settlement and carried out a terrible blood bath. Only a few people were able to flee to Angyahtalek in baidarkas; 300 Koniags were shot by the Russians. This happened in April. When our people revisited the place in the summer the stench of the corpses lying on the shore polluted the air so badly that none could stay there, and since then the island has been uninhabited. After this every chief had to surrender his children as hostages; I was saved only by my father's begging and many sea otter pelts.[NEWLINE]--- Arsenti Aminak, Alutiiq native, on the 1784 massacre of thousands of Alutiiq by Russian fur traders at Ala'uq</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_QUOTE_54</Tag>
		<English>The time is near at hand which must determine whether Americans are to be free men or slaves.[NEWLINE]--- George Washington (1732 - 1799), Commander-in-Chief of the Continental Army and first President of the United States</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_1</Tag>
		<English>They do not bear arms, and do not know them, for I showed them a sword, they took it by the edge and cut themselves out of ignorance.[NEWLINE]--- Christopher Columbus, about Arawak Indians in the Bahamas (October 13, 1492)</English>
		<French>They do not bear arms, and do not know them, for I showed them a sword, they took it by the edge and cut themselves out of ignorance.[NEWLINE]--- Christopher Columbus, about Arawak Indians in the Bahamas</French>
		<German>Sie tragen keine Waffen und kennen sie nicht, denn ich zeigte ihnen ein Schwert, sie nahmen es an der Schneide und schnitten sich aus Unwissenheit.[NEWLINE]--- Christoph Kolumbus, über Arawak-Indianer auf den Bahamas (13. Oktober 1492)</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_2</Tag>
		<English>We found a large number of books in these characters and, as they contained nothing in which were not to be seen as superstition and lies of the Devil, we burned them all, which they (the Maya) regretted to an amazing degree, and which caused them much affliction.[NEWLINE]--- Diego de Landa Calderón, Spanish Bishop of Yucatán</English>
		<French>Pour vous emparer d'une colonie ou d'une pile d'unités non-combattantes, il vous faudra vaincre toutes les unités de combat présentes, plus l'une des unités non-combattantes. Si vous y parvenez, les colons restants sont à vous !</French>
		<German>Wir fanden bei den Indios eine große Zahl von Büchern mit fremden Buchstaben, und weil sie nichts enthielten, was von Aberglauben und den Täuschungen des Teufels frei wäre, verbrannten wir sie alle.[NEWLINE]--- Diego de Landa Calderón, spanischer Missionar und Bischof in Yucatán</German>
		<Italian>Per conquistare un insediamento o un gruppo di unità non combattenti devi sconfiggere tutte le unità combattenti presenti, più una di quelle non combattenti. Dopodiché i rimanenti coloni saranno tutti tuoi!</Italian>
		<Spanish>Para capturar un asentamiento y un apilamiento de unidades no combatientes, tendréis que derrotar a todas las unidades de combate presentes y a una de las civiles. Tras ello, los Colonos restantes serán vuestros.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_3</Tag>
		<English>To free us of this feare, leave aboord your weapons, for here they are needlesse, we being all friends, and for ever Powhatans.[NEWLINE]--- Chief Powhatan to Captain John Smith</English>
		<French>Pour attribuer une profession à l'un des colons de votre colonie, effectuez un [double-clic] sur le colon dans l'écran de colonie.</French>
		<German>Wir sind unbewaffnet und bereit, euch zu geben, was ihr wollt, wenn ihr freundlich auftretet.[NEWLINE]--- Häuptling Powhatan in einer Botschaft an John Smith, Gründer von Jamestown</German>
		<Italian>Per assegnare a un colono in un insediamento una professione, [clicca due volte] sul colono nella schermata dell'insediamento.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Para asignar una profesión a un Colono del asentamiento, haced doble clic en él en la pantalla del asentamiento.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_4</Tag>
		<English>It was a fearfull sight to see them thus frying in ye fyer, and ye streams of blood quenching ye same, and horrible was ye stinck and sente ther of; but ye victory seemed a sweete sacrifice, and they gave the prays therof to God, who had wrought so wonderfuly for them, thus to inclose their enimise in their hands, and give them so speedy a victory over so proud and insulting an enimie.[NEWLINE]--- William Bradford about the English massacre of the Pequot</English>
		<French>L'argent n'a pas besoin d'être retravaillé, vous pouvez le vendre immédiatement à un prix élevé. L'argent ne peut être excavé que des pitons rocheux et des cases affichant l'icône de la ressource.</French>
		<German>Es war ein schrecklicher Anblick, die Pequot im Feuer brennen und das Blut hervorquellen zu sehen, und der Gestank war fürchterlich. Aber die Engländer sandten ihre Gebete zu Gott, der ihnen ihre Feinde in die Hände gespielt hatte.[NEWLINE]--- William Bradford, Augenzeuge von John Masons Überfall auf ein Pequot-Dorf</German>
		<Italian>L'argento non va lavorato, quindi può essere venduto fin da subito a un prezzo molto alto. Può essere estratto solo dalle montagne, o dalle caselle con la risorsa argento.</Italian>
		<Spanish>La Plata no tiene que procesarse, por lo que se puede vender de inmediato a un buen precio. La Plata solo puede extraerse de picos o de casillas con el recurso de Plata.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_5</Tag>
		<English>The allowance for a man in those times was only 8 ounces of meat and half a pint of peas a day, both the one and the other being moldy, rotten and full of cobwebs and maggots.[NEWLINE]--- Jamestown under the administration of Sir Thomas Smith</English>
		<French>Dans l'écran de colonie, vous pouvez glisser/déposer vos citoyens afin de leur attribuer de nouvelles professions. Effectuez un [clic gauche] sur le citoyen auquel vous désirez attribuer une profession et faites-le glisser sur la case ou le bâtiment voulu. Il commencera immédiatement son travail.</French>
		<German>Die Zuteilung pro Mann und Tag betrug 200 Gramm Fleisch und eine Tasse Erbsen, verschimmelt und voller Spinnweben und Maden.[NEWLINE]--- "Chronik der Bürgerversammlung von Virginia" über die Gründerzeit von Jamestown</German>
		<Italian>Nella schermata dell'insediamento puoi trascinare i coloni per assegnare loro nuove professioni. [Clicca col pulsante sinistro] sul cittadino a cui vuoi assegnare una professione, quindi trascinalo sulla casella o sull'edificio che desideri e comincerà immediatamente a lavorare.</Italian>
		<Spanish>En la pantalla del asentamiento podéis arrastrar y soltar ciudadanos para asignarles nuevas profesiones. Haced clic con el botün izquierdo en el ciudadano que queráis y arrastradlo al edificio o casilla deseados e inmediatamente se pondrá a trabajar.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_6</Tag>
		<English>Nay, so great was our famine, that a Savage we slew, and buried, the poorer sort tooke him up againe and eat him, and so did divers one another boyled and stewed with roots and herbs: And one amongst the rest did kill his wife, powdered her, and had eaten part of her before it was knowne.[NEWLINE]--- "A True declaration of the estate of the Colonie in Virginia" (1610)</English>
		<French>Si vous désirez modifier ce que vos colons produisent dans une case, effectuez un [double-clic] sur l'un d'entre eux et une liste des professions disponibles apparaîtra.</French>
		<German>Unerträglicher Hunger trieb uns dazu, einen Indianer aus seinem Grabe zu schaufeln, in dem er drei Tage gelegen hatte, und ihn ganz zu verschlingen.[NEWLINE]--- "Chronik der Bürgerversammlung von Virginia" über die Gründerzeit von Jamestown</German>
		<Italian>Se vuoi cambiare quello che sta producendo uno dei tuoi coloni in una casella, [clicca due volte] sul cittadino e apparirà una lista delle nuove professioni.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Si queréis cambiar lo que un ciudadano está produciendo en una casilla, haced doble clic en él y aparecerá una lista de nuevas profesiones.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_7</Tag>
		<English>And it is hereby further enacted by the authority aforesaid that if any negroe or other slave shall absent himself from his masters service and lye hid and lurking in obscure places, it shall be lawful for such persons to kill the said negroe or slave so lying out.[NEWLINE]--- "Virginia Slave Codes" (1682)</English>
		<French>Pour vendre un trésor, vous devez d'abord le déplacer jusque dans l'une de vos villes côtières. Une fois qu'il s'y trouve, vous pouvez choisir de le faire rapatrier par les galions du roi (qui prendront une part des profits) ou de l'acheminer vous-même vers l'Europe à bord de l'un de vos propres galions.</French>
		<German>Und es wird hiermit weiter durch die oben genannte Autorität verordnet, dass, wenn ein Neger oder ein anderer Sklave sich vom Dienst seines Herrn entfernt und sich an dunklen Orten versteckt und auf der Lauer liegt, es für solche Personen rechtmäßig ist, den besagten Neger oder Sklaven zu töten, der so draußen liegt.[NEWLINE]--- "Sklaven-Kodex von Virginia" (1682)</German>
		<Italian>Per vendere un tesoro devi prima farlo arrivare in uno dei tuoi insediamenti costieri. Una volta là, puoi decidere se farlo trasportare sui galeoni del re (che si prenderà parte dei profitti), oppure inviarlo in Europa con un tuo galeone.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Para vender una unidad de Tesoro, primero debéis llevarla a una de vuestras ciudades costeras. Una vez que esté allí, podéis optar entre que vuestro rey la embarque en uno de sus Galeones (y también saque tajada de los beneficios) o enviarla a Europa en uno de vuestros propios Galeones.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_8</Tag>
		<English>But during the voyage there is on board these ships terrible misery, stench, fumes, horror, vomiting, many kinds of sea-sickness, fever, dysentery, headache, heat, constipation, boils, scurvy, cancer, mouth-rot, and the like, so that many die miserably.[NEWLINE]--- Gottlieb Mittelberger's Journey to Pennsylvania (1754)</English>
		<French>Le fer est une ressource inestimable : il vous permet de fabriquer des outils (nécessaires pour créer les pionniers et sélectionner de nouveaux bâtiments et unités). Les outils peuvent ensuite être transformés en armes à feu.</French>
		<German>Aber während der Reise gibt es an Bord dieser Schiffe furchtbares Elend, Gestank, Gerüche, Schrecken, Erbrechen, viele Arten von Seekrankheit, Fieber, Durchfall, Kopfschmerzen, Hitze, Verstopfung, Eiterbeulen, Skorbut, Krebs, Mundfäule und dergleichen, so dass viele elendig sterben.[NEWLINE]--- Gottlieb Mittelberger über seine Überfahrt von Deutschland nach Amerika (1750)</German>
		<Italian>Il minerale è una risorsa preziosa, dato che può essere trasformato in attrezzi (necessari per creare pionieri e determinati edifici e unità). Gli attrezzi possono anche essere trasformati in armi.</Italian>
		<Spanish>El Mineral es un recurso valioso, ya que se procesa y convierte en Herramientas (necesarias para crear Pioneros y ciertas unidades y edificios). Las Herramientas también se pueden convertir en Armas.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_9</Tag>
		<English>One day, just as we had a heavy gale, a woman in our ship, who was to give birth and could not give birth under the circumstances, was pushed through a loophole in the ship and dropped into the sea.[NEWLINE]--- Gottlieb Mittelberger's Journey to Pennsylvania (1754)</English>
		<French>Explorer le Nouveau monde peut s'avérer particulièrement profitable. En fouillant des ruines et en entrant en contact avec les chefs de colonies indigènes, vous pouvez récupérer de l'or, des points d'expérience, voire des trésors.</French>
		<German>Eines Tages, als wir gerade einen schweren Sturm hatten, wurde eine Frau in unserem Schiff, die kurz vor der Niederkunft stand und unter den Umständen nicht entbinden konnte, durch eine Geschützpforte aus dem Schiff gestoßen und ins Meer geworfen.[NEWLINE]--- Gottlieb Mittelberger über seine Überfahrt von Deutschland nach Amerika (1750)</German>
		<Italian>L'esplorazione del Nuovo Mondo può essere un'impresa proficua. Cercando tra le antiche rovine e contattando i capi degli insediamenti nativi puoi ricevere regali in oro, punti esperienza e addirittura tesori.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Explorar el Nuevo Mundo puede ser una empresa provechosa. Al husmear en Ruinas antiguas y establecer contacto con los jefes de los asentamientos indígenas, podéis recibir regalos de oro, puntos de experiencia e incluso unidades de Tesoro.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_10</Tag>
		<English>I challenge the warmest advocate for reconciliation to shew a single advantage that this continent can reap by being connected with Great Britain.[NEWLINE]--- Thomas Paine, "Common Sense" (1776)</English>
		<French>Le canon est l'arme de siège ultime. Si vous avez l'intention de vous emparer d'une colonie ennemie, posséder un canon simplifiera grandement votre belliqueuse entreprise.</French>
		<German>Ich fordere den wärmsten Verfechter einer Versöhnung mit England heraus, auch nur einen einzigen Vorteil zu nennen, den dieser Kontinent dadurch genießen könnte.[NEWLINE]--- Thomas Paine, in einer Streitschrift zur Unabhängigkeit Amerikas (1776)</German>
		<Italian>I cannoni sono l'arma da assedio definitiva. Se decidi di conquistare un insediamento nemico avere un cannone renderà l'impresa molto più facile.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Los Cañones son las armas de asedio definitivas. Si pretendéis tomar un asentamiento enemigo, tener un Cañón a vuestro lado os facilitará mucho la conquista.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_11</Tag>
		<English>There is something very absurd in supposing a continent to be perpetually governed by an island. In no instance hath nature made the satellite larger than its primary planet, and as England and America, with respect to each other, reverses the common order of nature, it is evident they belong to different systems: England to Europe, America to itself.[NEWLINE]--- Thomas Paine, "Common Sense" (1776)</English>
		<French>Pour mettre en place une économie forte, vous devez attribuer des professions à vos unités. Ceci n'est possible qu'à partir de l'écran de colonie.</French>
		<German>Alles, was richtig und vernünftig ist, plädiert für eine Trennung von England.[NEWLINE]--- Thomas Paine, in einer Streitschrift zur Unabhängigkeit Amerikas, 1776</German>
		<Italian>Per costruire un'economia devi assegnare delle professioni alle tue unità, cosa che puoi fare solo nella schermata dell'insediamento.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Para levantar vuestra economía necesitáis asignar profesiones a las unidades, lo cual puede hacerse en la pantalla del asentamiento.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_12</Tag>
		<English>We have appealed to their native justice and magnanimity, and we have conjured them by the ties of our common kindred to disavow these usurpations, which, would inevitably interrupt our connections and correspondence. They too have been deaf to the voice of justice and of consanguinity.[NEWLINE]--- "The Declaration of Independence" (1776)</English>
		<French>N'importe quelle unité humaine peut adopter n'importe quelle profession (à quelques exceptions près). Les possibilités dépendent en fait des cases, des ressources et des bâtiments disponibles. Cependant, pour une profession donnée, les spécialistes sont plus efficaces que les autres citoyens.</French>
		<German>Wir haben es nicht an Aufforderungen an unsere britischen Brüder fehlen lassen. Doch sie waren taub gegen die Stimme der Gerechtigkeit und der Blutsverwandschaft.[NEWLINE]--- "Unabhängigkeitserklärung der USA" (1776)</German>
		<Italian>Un'unità umana può intraprendere qualsiasi professione (con qualche eccezione), a patto di avere a disposizione caselle, risorse o edifici adatti. Gli specialisti, comunque, sono più bravi dei cittadini comuni in determinate professioni.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Cualquier unidad humana puede adoptar cualquier profesión (con algunas excepciones), siempre que estén disponibles las casillas, los recursos o los edificios necesarios. No obstante, los especialistas son mejores en sus profesiones que los demás ciudadanos.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_13</Tag>
		<English>The history of the present King of Great Britain is a history of repeated injuries and usurpations, all having in direct object the establishment of an absolute Tyranny over these States.[NEWLINE]--- "The Declaration of Independence" (1776)</English>
		<French>Un fort sentiment de rébellion dans votre colonie augmentera son taux de production de matières premières et de produits manufacturés, ainsi que la puissance défensive de vos unités.</French>
		<German>Die Geschichte des gegenwärtigen Königs von Großbritannien ist eine Geschichte von wiederholten Ungerechtigkeiten und eigenmächtigen Anmaßungen.[NEWLINE]--- "Unabhängigkeitserklärung der USA" (1776)</German>
		<Italian>Avere un sentimento di ribellione alto, nell'insediamento, aumenterà la produzione di beni e materie prime e la forza difensiva delle tue unità.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Tener un sentimiento de rebelión alto en el asentamiento aumentará en éste la producción de mercancías, materias primas y la fuerza defensiva de vuestras unidades.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_14</Tag>
		<English>We, therefore, the Representatives of the United States of America, do, in the Name, and by Authority of the good People of these Colonies, solemnly publish and declare, That these United Colonies are, and of Right ought to be Free and Independent States; that they are Absolved from all Allegiance to the British Crown.[NEWLINE]-- "The Declaration of Independence" (1776)</English>
		<French>Avant de déclarer votre indépendance, assurez-vous que votre colonie est assez solide pour franchir le pas ! Vous pouvez visualiser les unités auxquelles vous aurez à faire face dans l'écran de Révolution [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; F3 &gt;[COLOR_REVERT].</French>
		<German>Wir, die Volksvertreter der Vereinigten Staaten von Amerika, verkünden feierlichst, dass diese vereinten Kolonien losgesprochen sind von allem Gehorsam gegen die britische Krone.[NEWLINE]--- "Unabhängigkeitserklärung der USA" (1776)</German>
		<Italian>Assicurati di essere pronto, prima di dichiarare l'indipendenza. Puoi dare un'occhiata alle forze che dovrai affrontare visitando la schermata della rivoluzione [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; F3 &gt;[COLOR_REVERT].</Italian>
		<Spanish>Aseguraos de prepararos adecuadamente para proclamar vuestra independencia. Veréis las fuerzas a las que deberéis enfrentaros si visitáis la pantalla Revolución [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; F3 &gt;[COLOR_REVERT].</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_15</Tag>
		<English>Sell a country! Why not sell the air, the clouds and the great sea, as well as the earth? Did not the Great Spirit make them all for the use of his children?[NEWLINE]--- Tecumseh to William Henry Harrison, 1810</English>
		<French>Vous gagnez des points d'exploration (et avez ainsi davantage de chance d'attirer un Père fondateur explorateur) en découvrant de nouvelles cases de terre et de mer, et en entrant en contact avec les chefs indigènes.</French>
		<German>Dieses Land gehört allen. Kein Roter Mann hat das Recht, Land zu verkaufen, schon gar nicht an Fremde.[NEWLINE]--- Tecumseh, Häuptling der Shawnee</German>
		<Italian>Puoi ottenere punti esplorazione (e quindi avere più probabilità di acchiappare un Padre Fondatore esploratore) scoprendo caselle terrestri e marine inesplorate e stabilendo contatti coi capi nativi.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Ganáis puntos de exploración (y, por tanto, tenéis más posibilidades de captar a un Padre fundador explorador) descubriendo casillas de tierra y mar ocultas y estableciendo contacto con los líderes indígenas.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_16</Tag>
		<English>I fought hard. But your guns were well aimed. The bullets flew like birds in the air, and whizzed by our ears like the wind through the trees in the winter. My warriors fell around me; it began to look dismal.[NEWLINE]--- Black Hawk's Surrender Speech, 1832</English>
		<French>Vous gagnez des points politiques (et augmentez ainsi vos chances de rallier à votre cause un Père fondateur politicien) en générant des Cloches de la liberté. Plus vous en générez, plus vous remporterez de points politiques.</French>
		<German>Ich habe hart gekämpft. Aber eure Gewehre zielten gut. Eure Kugeln flogen wie Vögel durch die Luft und zischten an unseren Ohren vorbei wie der Wind durch die Bäume im Winter. Meine Krieger fielen rund um mich; es begann, düster auszusehen.[NEWLINE]--- Häuptling Black Hawk, in seiner Kapitulationsrede, 1832</German>
		<Italian>Ottieni punti politica (e aumenti la possibilità di convincere un Padre Fondatore politico a unirsi alla tua causa) generando campane della libertà. Più ne generi e più punti politica ottieni.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Ganáis puntos de política (y posibilidades de que un Padre fundador político se una a vuestra causa) generando Campanas de la libertad. Cuantas más Campanas de la libertad produzcáis, más puntos de política recibiréis.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_17</Tag>
		<English>The white men speak bad of the Indian, and look at him spitefully. But the Indian does not tell lies; Indians do not steal.[NEWLINE]--- Black Hawk's Surrender Speech, 1832</English>
		<French>Vous pouvez gagner des points militaires (et augmenter ainsi vos chances de récupérer un Père fondateur militaire) en remportant des combats, en vous emparant de colonies ennemies, ainsi qu'en construisant des barricades, des forts et des forteresses.</French>
		<German>Die weißen Männer schauen verächtlich auf uns Indianer herab. Aber der Indianer lügt nicht. Indianer stehlen nicht. Indianer betrügen nicht.[NEWLINE]--- Häuptling Black Hawk, in seiner Kapitulationsrede, 1832</German>
		<Italian>Puoi guadagnare punti esercito (aumentando le probabilità di ottenere un Padre Fondatore militare) vincendo battaglie, conquistando insediamenti nemici e costruendo palizzate, forti e fortezze.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Podéis obtener puntos militares (y aumentar vuestras posibilidades de conseguir un Padre fundador militar) ganando batallas, capturando asentamientos enemigos y construyendo Empalizadas, Fuertes y Fortalezas.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_18</Tag>
		<English>The white men do not scalp the head; but they do worse - they poison the heart, it is not pure with them.[NEWLINE]--- Black Hawk's Surrender Speech, 1832</English>
		<French>Vous gagnez des points de commerce (et augmentez ainsi vos chances d'obtenir un Père fondateur marchand) en vendant des marchandises aux indigènes ou en Europe.</French>
		<German>Die weißen Männer skalpieren keine Köpfe; aber sie tun Schlimmeres - sie vergiften das Herz, es ist nicht rein bei ihnen.[NEWLINE]--- Häuptling Black Hawk, in seiner Kapitulationsrede, 1832</German>
		<Italian>Guadagni punti commercio (incrementando la possibilità che un Padre Fondatore commerciante si schieri al tuo fianco) vendendo beni all'Europa o ai nativi.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Ganáis puntos de intercambio (y aumentáis la probabilidad de que un Padre fundador comerciante se una a vuestra causa) vendiendo mercancías a Europa o a los Nativos.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_19</Tag>
		<English>An Indian who is as bad as the white men could not live in our nation; he would be put to death and eaten up by the wolves.[NEWLINE]--- Black Hawk's Surrender Speech, 1832</English>
		<French>Vous gagnez des points de foi (et augmentez ainsi vos chances de convaincre une Père fondateur religieux de vous rejoindre) en générant des croix et en établissant des missions dans les colonies indigènes.</French>
		<German>Ein Indianer, der so schlecht ist wie die weißen Männer, könnte in unserem Volk nicht leben. Er würde getötet und den Wölfen zum Fraß vorgeworfen.[NEWLINE]--- Häuptling Black Hawk, in seiner Kapitulationsrede, 1832</German>
		<Italian>Puoi ottenere punti religione (e aumentare le probabilità di convincere un Padre Fondatore religioso a unirsi a te) generando croci e fondando missioni negli insediamenti nativi.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Ganáis puntos de religión (y aumentáis vuestras posibilidades de convencer a un Padre fundador religioso de que se ponga de vuestro lado) generando Cruces y fundando misiones en los asentamientos indígenas.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_20</Tag>
		<English>Unless Your Majesties' orders are that they all be taken to Spain or held captive on the island itself, for with fifty men one could keep the whole population in subjection.[NEWLINE]--- Christopher Columbus, about Arawak Indians (October 14, 1492)</English>
		<French>Chaque Père fondateur coûte un certain nombre de points du type correspondant à sa spécialité. Lorsque vous acceptez d'accueillir un Père fondateur, vous dépensez un nombre de points égal à son coût. Ainsi, si un Père fondateur vous propose de rejoindre votre colonie, mais qu'un Père fondateur à venir vous intéresse davantage, il pourrait être plus sage de refuser sa proposition afin d'économiser vos points pour acquérir celui que vous souhaitez réellement obtenir.</French>
		<German>Ihre Speere sind aus Schilfrohr gemacht. Mit fünfzig Mann könnten wir sie alle unterwerfen und sie zu allem zwingen, was wir wollen.[NEWLINE]--- Christoph Kolumbus, über die Arawak-Indianer auf den Bahamas (14. October 1492)</German>
		<Italian>Ogni Padre Fondatore ha un costo in punti. Quando accetti un Padre Fondatore al tuo fianco, perdi un numero di punti pari al costo di quel Padre Fondatore. Quindi se un Padre Fondatore si offre di schierarsi dalla tua parte, ma se più interessato in un altro, può essere una buona idea rifiutare, in modo da risparmiare i punti per quello che vuoi veramente.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Cada Padre fundador tiene asociado un coste específico en puntos. Cuando aceptéis a un Padre fundador en vuestro bando, perderéis un número de puntos igual al coste de éste. Así que, si uno de ellos se ofrece a unirse a vuestro bando pero os interesa más otro posterior, resultaría aconsejable rechazarlo para poder guardar los puntos para el que realmente queréis.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_21</Tag>
		<English>We, out of the fullness of our apostolic power, by the authority of Almighty God, give, grant, and assign to you and your heirs and successors, kings of Castile and León, forever, together with all their dominions, cities, camps, places, and villages, and all rights, jurisdictions, and appurtenances, all islands and mainlands found and to be found, discovered and to be discovered.[NEWLINE]--- Pope Alexander VI, Papal Bull "Inter caetera" (1493)</English>
		<French>Une fois qu'une civilisation a convaincu un Père fondateur de la rejoindre, ce dernier lui reste fidèle jusqu'au bout. Même si la civilisation en question venait à être vaincue, aucun autre joueur ne pourrait plus acquérir ce Père fondateur.</French>
		<German>Auf Grund der Stellvertreterschaft Jesu Christi auf Erden übertragen Wir hiermit an Euch und Eure Erben für alle Zeiten alle entdeckten oder zu entdeckenden Inseln und Festländer, mitsamt allen Herrschaften, Städten, Lägern, Plätzen und Dörfern.[NEWLINE]--- Papst Alexander VI., Päpstliche Bulle "Inter caetera" (1493)</German>
		<Italian>Una volta che una civiltà ha convinto un Padre Fondatore a unirsi alla propria causa, questi è permanentemente assegnato a quella civiltà. Anche se questa dovesse perdere, nessun altro giocatore potrà ottenere quel Padre Fondatore.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Cuando una civilización convence a un Padre fundador de que se una a su causa, éste quedará asignado permanentemente a ella. Incluso si dicha civilización cae derrotada, ninguna otra podrá ganarse a ese Padre fundador.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_22</Tag>
		<English>No vote. No work.[NEWLINE]--- Polish Immigrants, Jamestown, 1619</English>
		<French>Pas de vote. Pas de de travail.[NEWLINE]--- Immigrants polonais, Jamestown, 1619</French>
		<German>Kein Stimmrecht, keine Arbeit.[NEWLINE]--- Polnische Einwanderer, Jamestown, 1619</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_23</Tag>
		<English>Will you free yourselves? Will you recover the lands stolen three hundred years ago from your forefathers by the hated Spaniards? We must act at once. Will you defend your religion and your rights as true patriots? Long live our Lady of Guadalupe! Death to bad government! Death to the gachupines![NEWLINE]--- Miguel Hidalgo y Costilla, "Grito de Dolores" (1810)</English>
		<French>Lorsque l'une de vos unités se rend dans une colonie indigène, pensez bien à parler à son chef. Il aura peut-être un présent à vous offrir.</French>
		<German>Werdet Ihr Euch befreien? Werdet Ihr das Land Euer Vorväter zurückerobern, dass von den verhassten Spaniern vor dreihundert Jahren gestohlen wurde? Lang lebe unsere Jungfrau von Guadalupe! Tod der schlechten Regierung! Tod den Spaniern.[NEWLINE]--- Miguel Hidalgo y Costilla, "Grito de Dolores" (1810), Aufruf zur Unabhängigkeitsrevolution Mexikos</German>
		<Italian>Quando una delle tue unità visita un insediamento di nativi, assicurati di parlare con il capo. Potrebbe avere un regalo per te.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Cuando una de vuestras unidades visite un asentamiento indígena, no dejéis de hablar con el jefe. Puede que tenga un regalo para vos.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_24</Tag>
		<English>Many master craftspeople must choose which one of two or more yields to work on at any given time, creating different finished goods. Some finished items, such as tools for guns, can be used to make other things. One example of a long sequence starts with sheep providing wool through the butcher, then wool cloth from the weaver, coloured wool cloth from the dyer, and ends once the tailor stitches together everyday clothes. Trading can happen at every stage. Some yields are useful only as trade commodities. Gold is valuable but rare. Rubber is mid-priced, but much more common.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_25</Tag>
		<English>As terrain increases in variety, choosing where to settle is a more subtle choice. A bonus resource is good but that might be only one of three or more resources on a single terrain tile. Resources affect how building is done. Without original food available a windmill can't be built. Without ore there can never be an iron mill. Depending on strategy, the best site might have no bonuses. Instead it will have tiles with the right combination of basic resources for production and trading success.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_26</Tag>
		<English>[BOLD]Don't put troops on your first frigate![\BOLD]When you get your first frigate, whether you buy it, build it, or get it from a quest or a Founding Father, the King is going to commandeer it for the Royal Navy. Don't worry. You'll get it back in ten turns. However if you put any of your soldiers aboard they'll be shanghaied into the Royal Marines. You'll never see those troops again.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_27</Tag>
		<English>This country is worth seeking, not only because great wealth may be obtained from it, gold and silver, all sorts of gems, and spices, which never reach us.[NEWLINE]--- Paolo Toscanelli, "First Letter to Columbus" (1474)</English>
		<French>Si vos réserves de nourriture atteignent 200 unités, ces dernières seront immédiatement consumées et vous obtiendrez un nouveau colon libre.</French>
		<German>Eine Reise zu den Ostländern führt zu mächtigen Königreichen, berühmten Städten und Provinzen, die alles im Überfluss besitzen, was wir benötigen, auch alle Arten von Gewürzen in reicher Fülle sowie Edelsteine in großer Menge aufweisen.[NEWLINE]--- Paolo Toscanelli, Brief des Kartografen aus Florenz an Kolumbus (etwa 1474)</German>
		<Italian>Se le tue riserve di cibo arrivano a quota 200, quelle 200 unità di cibo verranno immediatamente trasformate in un nuovo libero colono.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Si vuestros almacenes llegan a los 200 Alimentos, esa cantidad se transformará de inmediato en un Colono libre.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_29</Tag>
		<English>I knew that they were a people who could be more easily freed and converted to our holy faith by love than by force, gave to some of them red caps and glass beads to put round their necks and many other things of little value, which gave them great pleasure.[NEWLINE]--- Christopher Columbus, about Arawak Indians (October 14, 1492)</English>
		<French>Il existe quatre moyens d'obtenir des experts et des maîtres. Vous pouvez en récupérer dans un port d'Europe puis le faire venir dans le Nouveau monde comme immigrant, en recruter depuis l'écran de l'Europe (mais leur prix est élevé), en former au sein de vos écoles, lycées et universités, ou demander aux indigènes d'en former.</French>
		<German>In der Erkenntnis, dass es sich um Leute handle, die man weit besser durch Liebe als durch das Schwert zu unserem Glauben bekehren könne, gedachte ich sie mir zu Freunden zu machen und schenkte also einigen von ihnen Kappen und Halsketten aus Glas und noch andere Kleinigkeiten von geringem Wert, worüber sie sich ungemein erfreut zeigten.[NEWLINE]--- Christoph Kolumbus, über die Arawak-Indianer auf den Bahamas (14. October 1492)</German>
		<Italian>Puoi portare esperti e mastri nella tua colonia in quattro modi diversi: prendendoli sui moli europei e facendoli arrivare come immigranti, reclutandoli nella schermata dell'Europa (spendendo molto), educandoli tramite la costruzione di una scuola, un college o un'università, oppure facendoli addestrare dai nativi.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Podéis llevar a vuestras colonias expertos y maestros de cuatro maneras: recogiéndolos en los muelles de Europa y trayéndolos como inmigrantes, reclutándolos en la pantalla de Europa (a un coste considerable), formándolos mediante una Escuela, Colegio universitario o Universidad o entrenándolos con los Nativos.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_31</Tag>
		<English>Armbands off, soldiers. Hail to the independence, to freedom and to the separation of Brazil. Independence or death![NEWLINE]--- Dom Pedro, 1822</English>
		<French>Chaque citoyen de votre colonie a besoin de deux unités de nourriture par tour pour subsister. Si vous ne disposez pas de suffisamment de nourriture, vos citoyens quitteront la colonie, et ce jusqu'à ce qu'il reste assez de nourriture pour la population.</French>
		<German>Sollten Eure Hoheiten den Befehl erteilen, alle Inselbewohner nach Kastilien zu schaffen oder aber sie auf ihrer eigenen Insel als Sklaven zu halten, so wäre dieser Befehl leicht durchführbar.[NEWLINE]--- Christoph Kolumbus, über die Arawak-Indianer auf den Bahamas</German>
		<Italian>Ogni cittadino in un insediamento ha bisogno di due unità di cibo a turno. Se non è disponibile cibo a sufficienza, i cittadini usciranno sulla mappa principale di gioco fino a quando non ci sarà abbastanza cibo per la popolazione che rimane.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Cada ciudadano del asentamiento precisa 2 Alimentos por turno. Si no tenéis bastantes Alimentos disponibles, los ciudadanos saldrán al mapa principal del juego hasta que haya Alimentos suficientes para mantener a la población.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_33</Tag>
		<English>!Ama Sua, Ama Kjella, Ama Lllulla! - Don't lie, don't cheat, don't be lazy.[NEWLINE]--- Quechua greeting during Inca times</English>
		<French>Pour attribuer les professions militaires d'éclaireur, de soldat ou de dragon à un citoyen, vous devez disposer de chevaux et d'armes. Les éclaireurs requièrent 50 chevaux, les soldats 50 armes, et les dragons 50 de chaque.</French>
		<German>Die Wilden bestaunen unsere Gesichtsbehaarung, da ihnen selbst keine Bärte wachsen. Und auch die Pferde werden wie Wunderwesen betastet, die donnernden Arkebusen verbreiten großen Schrecken.[NEWLINE]--- Tagebuch des Paters Antonio Toledo - Begleiter von Pizarro bei der Eroberung des Inkareiches 1532</German>
		<Italian>Per assegnare un cittadino alle professioni militari di scout, soldato o dragone devi avere a disposizione armi o cavalli. Per gli scout servono 50 cavalli, per i soldati 50 armi, per i dragoni 50 di entrambi.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Para asignarle la profesión de combate Batidor, Soldado o Dragón a una unidad debéis tener disponibles Caballos o Mosquetes. Los Batidores necesitan 50 Caballos; los Soldados, 50 Mosquetes; y los Dragones, 50 de cada.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_34</Tag>
		<English>The "We The People" Colopedia is rich with gameplay and historical information. It should be your first stop for any questions. You can visit it by pressing [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; F12 &gt;[COLOR_REVERT], clicking the "Colopedia" icon, or by selecting it on the Main Menu.</English>
		<French>La Colonizopédia de Colonization est truffée d'informations historiques et de conseils de jeu. N'hésitez pas à la consulter dès que vous vous posez des questions. Pour ce faire, appuyez sur [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; F12 &gt;[COLOR_REVERT], cliquez sur l'icône Colonizopédia ou sélectionnez-la dans le menu principal.</French>
		<German>Die Colopädie steckt voller geschichtlicher und spielrelevanter Informationen. Wenn du eine Frage hast, solltest du also zuerst dort nachsehen. Du kannst die Colopädie per [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; F12 &gt;[COLOR_REVERT], per Mausklick auf das "Colopädie"-Symbol oder durch Auswählen im Hauptmenü aufrufen.</German>
		<Italian>La Colonizopedia di Colonization è ricca di informazioni storiche e di gioco e dovrebbe essere il primo posto in cui cercare delle risposte alle tue domande. Puoi visualizzarla premendo [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; F12 &gt;[COLOR_REVERT], cliccando sull'icona "Colonizopedia", oppure selezionandola nel menu principale.</Italian>
		<Spanish>La Colonizopedia de Colonization está llena de información histórica y del juego y debería ser lo que primero que consultarais si tenéis alguna duda. Podéis mirarla pulsando [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; F12 &gt;[COLOR_REVERT], haciendo clic en el icono de la Colonizopedia o buscándola en el menú principal.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_35</Tag>
		<English>As for your pope of whom you speak, he must be mad to speak of giving away countries that do not belong to him. As for my faith, I will not change it. Your own God, as you tell me, was put to death by the very men He created. But my God still looks down on His children.[NEWLINE]--- Atahualpa, Inca Chief, 1532</English>
		<French>Si vous produisez davantage de marchandises que vous n'êtes capable d'en stocker, la marchandise excédentaire commencera à se détériorer et finira par disparaître. Assurez-vous de construire des entrepôts et d'organiser des transports de fret réguliers afin que vos fidèles colons n'aient pas travaillé pour rien.</French>
		<German>Der Mann, den du Papst nennst, muss verrückt sein, wenn er Länder verschenkt, die ihm nicht gehören. Und warum sollte ich meinen Glauben ablegen? Euer Gott wurde, wie du selbst sagst, von seinen eigenen Geschöpfen zu Tode gebracht, meiner hingegen lebt.[NEWLINE]--- Inkakaiser Atahualpa, 1532</German>
		<Italian>Se produci più beni di quelli che puoi immagazzinare, quelli in più cominceranno a rovinarsi e scompariranno. Assicurati di costruire magazzini e di fare spedizioni regolari, in modo da non sprecare il risultato del duro lavoro dei tuoi coloni.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Si producís más mercancías de las que podáis almacenar, las restantes empezarán a echarse a perder y desaparecer poco a poco. No dejéis de construir Almacenes y hacer envíos regulares, para que no se eche a perder el duro trabajo de los Colonos.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_36</Tag>
		<English>They taught them Latin and other subjects which are worth a lot more than all the silver taken from them... it was to their benefit to be conquered and, even more, to become Christians.[NEWLINE]--- Francisco López de Gómara, chaplain and secretary to Cortés</English>
		<French>Les unités indigènes n'ont que faire de ces stupides histoires de frontières. Ils entreront librement dans votre territoire et dans vos colonies.</French>
		<German>Zu dieser Zeit kamen Botschafter Montezumas an und sagten, dass sie auf sein Geheiß kämen, weil er vom Krieg gehört habe, den die Tlaxcalteken uns lieferten, und dass sie uns einige Pferde getötet und viele von uns verwundet und uns schlecht behandelt hätten, was Montezuma bedrückt habe.[NEWLINE]--- Reisebericht von Bernardino Vázquez de Tapia, Begleiter von Cortés bei der Eroberung des Aztekenreiches, 1519</German>
		<Italian>Le unità dei nativi non badano a cose ridicole come i tuoi "confini" ed entreranno liberamente nei tuoi territori e insediamenti.</Italian>
		<Spanish>A las unidades nativas les importan un comino las tontas fronteras, y entrarán libremente en vuestro territorio y asentamiento.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_37</Tag>
		<English>Realizing the greed of the Spanish, Atahualpa tried to bargain for his life. He offered to fill the room he was being held in with gold up to the reach of his arm, and two other rooms with silver in exchange for his freedom. The excited Spanish agreed, and with word to a messenger, the gold and silver was brought over the coming months to the ransom room until it was filled.[NEWLINE]--- Antonio Toledo, "Diary about the Conquest of the Incan Empire" (1532)</English>
		<French>Il arrivera parfois que vos frontières évoluent de manière erratique, voire n'évoluent pas du tout. Cela sera probablement dû à l'influence d'une colonie indigène situé dans les environs. Si les colonies indigènes n'ont pas de frontières, elles exercent par contre une influence certaine sur l'expansion des vôtres.</French>
		<German>Da Atahualpa die allgemeine Gier nicht verborgen geblieben ist, hat er Pizarro ein Angebot gemacht: Er will einen großen Raum bis zur Höhe einer ausgestreckten Hand mit Gold füllen lassen, dazu zwei weitere mit Silber - wenn er im Gegenzug seine Freiheit erhält.[NEWLINE]--- Tagebuch des Paters Antonio Toledo (1532), Begleiter von Pizarro bei der Eroberung des Inkareiches</German>
		<Italian>Alle volte ti sembrerà che i confini si espandano in modo strano, oppure per niente. Probabilmente capita a causa dell'influenza di un vicino insediamento nativo. Pur non avendo confini, infatti, gli insediamenti nativi esercitano un'influenza sui tuoi.</Italian>
		<Spanish>A veces puede parecer que las fronteras tienen una expansión errática o no se amplían en absoluto. Esto es posible que se deba a la influencia de algún Asentamiento indígena cercano. Aunque los asentamientos indígenas no tienen fronteras, sí que influyen en la extensión de las vuestras.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_38</Tag>
		<English>If you try to build a colony too close to a Native settlement, the local chief may require you to purchase the land you are claiming. You can refuse to pay, of course, but this will certainly worsen relations between you and the Natives already established there.</English>
		<French>Si vous tentez de fonder une ville trop près d'une colonie indigène, il se peut que le chef local vous demande d'acheter les terres que vous tentez de récupérer. Vous pouvez refuser de payer, bien entendu, mais cela entachera vos relations avec les indigènes concernés.</French>
		<German>Wenn Sie versuchen, eine Kolonie zu nahe an einer Ureinwohner-Siedlung zu errichten, bietet Ihnen der einheimische Häuptling vielleicht das Land, das Sie beanspruchen, zum Kauf an. Wenn Sie sich weigern zu zahlen, so hat das eindeutig negative Auswirkungen auf Ihre Beziehung zu den Ureinwohnern.</German>
		<Italian>Se provi a costruire una colonia troppo vicino a un insediamento di nativi, il capo potrebbe chiederti di acquistare la terra che rivendichi. Puoi naturalmente rifiutarti di pagare, ma ciò peggiorerà le relazioni con i nativi.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Si intentáis construir una colonia demasiado cerca de un asentamiento indígena, el jefe del lugar puede que os exija comprar la tierra de las que os estáis apoderando. Obviamente, os podéis negar a pagar, pero seguro que ello empeorará vuestra relación con los Nativos.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_39</Tag>
		<English>Goods need storage. Ships need berths. Soldiers need barracks. Warehouses, docks and forts are all necessary to keep your people busy and secure. Capacity has to increase as the colony grows. Buildings need regular upgrades. Infrastructure may not be the exciting side of politics, but when it's neglected business, private and public, will grind to a halt.</English>
		<French>Sans entrepôt, une colonie ne peut stocker que 100 unités d'une marchandise, excepté pour la nourriture. Un entrepôt fait passer cette limite à 200 et une extension d'entrepôt à 300.</French>
		<German>Waren benötigen Lagerräume. Schiffe brauchen Liegeplätze. Soldaten brauchen Kasernen. Lagerhäuser, Docks und Festungen sind notwendig, um die Menschen zu beschäftigen und zu schützen.[NEWLINE]Die Kapazitäten müssen mit dem Wachstum der Kolonie mithalten und daher Gebäude regelmäßig modernisiert werden.[NEWLINE]Die Infrastruktur ist vielleicht nicht die aufregendste Seite der Politik, aber wenn sie vernachlässigt wird, kommen die privaten und öffentlichen Geschäfte zum Stillstand.</German>
		<Italian>Senza un magazzino, il tuo insediamento può mettere da parte solo 100 unità di qualsiasi bene, a parte il cibo. Un magazzino aumenta la capacità a 200. L'espansione del magazzino porta la capacità del tuo insediamento a 300.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Sin un Almacén, vuestro asentamiento solo puede guardar 100 de cualquier tipo de mercancías, excepto Alimentos. Un Almacén aumenta la capacidad a 200. El Almacén ampliado sube la capacidad de almacenamiento del asentamiento a 300.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_40</Tag>
		<English>In Europe when you recruit units with a profession that needs goods, like the veteran soldier or seasoned scout, they come fully equipped with all the horses and weapons they require, including baked goods and gunpowder.</English>
		<French>Lorsque vous recrutez en Europe des unités dont la profession nécessitent certaines marchandises (comme c'est le cas pour le soldat vétéran ou l'éclaireur aguerri), ils se joindront à vous avec tous les chevaux et/ou les armes requises.</French>
		<German>Wenn Sie in Europa Einheiten rekrutieren, die Güter benötigen, um ihrem Beruf nachzugehen (etwa einen Offizier oder einen Routinierten Späher), werden diese Einheiten voll ausgerüstet - mit den notwendigen Pferden und Schusswaffen - geliefert.</German>
		<Italian>Quando recluti in Europa unità che solitamente hanno bisogno di beni per intraprendere la professione, come per soldati veterani o scout esperti, arriveranno completamente equipaggiati con le armi e i cavalli di cui hanno bisogno.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Cuando reclutéis unidades de Europa que suelan exigir mercancías con las que llevar a cabo su profesión, como el Soldado veterano o el Batidor curtido, éstas aparecerán completamente equipadas con todos los Caballos y Mosquetes que necesiten.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_41</Tag>
		<English>When building your first settlement, it's always a good idea to keep as close to Europe as possible. Your ships will spend less time in transit between colony and mother country, lessening the chance of being attacked by enemy ships. Settle beside coast tiles rather than shallow coast. Otherwise when you get larger ships they won't be able to enter your port. It may take some searching to find a safe harbour for your settlement.</English>
		<French>Lorsque vous fondez votre première colonie, il est toujours judicieux de le faire le plus près possible de votre voie d'accès à l'Europe. Ainsi, vos navires passeront moins de temps en mer entre votre colonie et votre patrie, réduisant le risque qu'ils soient assaillis par un navire ennemi.</French>
		<German>Wenn Sie Ihre erste Siedlung errichten, ist es immer sinnvoll, diese so nah wie möglich an Ihrer Route nach Europa anzulegen. Das bedeutet, daß Ihre Schiffe benötigen weniger lange für die Reise zwischen Kolonie und Mutterland brauchen. Zudem sinkt auch die Wahrscheinlichkeit, dass sie von gegnerischen Schiffen angegriffen werden.</German>
		<Italian>Quando costruisci il tuo primo insediamento è sempre una buona idea costruirlo il più vicino possibile alla tua rotta per l'Europa. In questo modo le tue navi spenderanno meno tempo in viaggio tra la colonia e la madrepatria, riducendo le probabilità di venire attaccate dalle navi nemiche.</Italian>
		<Spanish>A la hora de construir el primer asentamiento, siempre es una buena idea hacerlo lo más cerca posible de la ruta con Europa. Esto supone que vuestros barcos pasarán menos tiempo en los tránsitos entre la colonia y la madre patria, y reducir la posibilidad de ser atacados por naves enemigas.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_42</Tag>
		<English>When building your first settlement, it's always a good idea to keep as close to Europe as possible. Your ships will spend less time in transit between colony and mother country, lessening the chance of being attacked by enemy ships. Settle beside coast tiles rather than shallow coast. Otherwise when you get larger ships they won't be able to enter your port. It may take some searching to find a safe harbour for your settlement.</English>
		<French>Lorsque vous fondez votre première colonie, il est toujours judicieux de le faire le plus près possible de votre voie d'accès à l'Europe. Ainsi, vos navires passeront moins de temps en mer entre votre colonie et votre patrie, réduisant le risque qu'ils soient assaillis par un navire ennemi.</French>
		<German>Wenn Sie Ihre erste Siedlung errichten, ist es immer sinnvoll, diese so nah wie möglich an Ihrer Route nach Europa anzulegen. Das bedeutet, daß Ihre Schiffe benötigen weniger lange für die Reise zwischen Kolonie und Mutterland brauchen. Zudem sinkt auch die Wahrscheinlichkeit, dass sie von gegnerischen Schiffen angegriffen werden.</German>
		<Italian>Quando costruisci il tuo primo insediamento è sempre una buona idea costruirlo il più vicino possibile alla tua rotta per l'Europa. In questo modo le tue navi spenderanno meno tempo in viaggio tra la colonia e la madrepatria, riducendo le probabilità di venire attaccate dalle navi nemiche.</Italian>
		<Spanish>A la hora de construir el primer asentamiento, siempre es una buena idea hacerlo lo más cerca posible de la ruta con Europa. Esto supone que vuestros barcos pasarán menos tiempo en los tránsitos entre la colonia y la madre patria, y reducir la posibilidad de ser atacados por naves enemigas.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_43</Tag>
		<English>Galleons are the finest transport ships available and the only ships capable of transporting treasure units to Europe. However they cannot transport any other units. Once you have enough treasures, the King may offer you a special price on a galleon to carry them, but he'll wait until you have enough gold on hand.</English>
		<French>Les galions sont les navires de transport disponibles les plus performants. Ils sont notamment les seuls à pouvoir transporter les trésors en Europe.</French>
		<German>Galeonen sind die besten verfügbaren Transportschiffe und die einzigen, die Schatzeinheiten nach Europa bringen können. Allerdings können sie keine anderen Einheiten transportieren.</German>
		<Italian>I galeoni sono le migliori navi da trasporto disponibili e sono le uniche in grado di trasportare i tesori in Europa.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Los Galeones son los mejores barcos de transporte y los únicos capaces de llevar unidades de Tesoro a Europa. Por otro lado, no pueden transportar otros tipos de unidades.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_45</Tag>
		<English>To load goods onto a transport, you must move the transport unit into the same tile as the goods and press the "Load Goods" icon. You can also do it from the "Transport" section of the Settlement Screen. You can unload goods one of two ways - by selecting the good you would like to unload from the unit stack and pressing "Unload" from the orders display or by activating the transport unit and clicking "Unload All." You can only unload goods in settlements (or in Europe).Soldiers need guns and gunpowder. </English>
		<French>Pour charger des marchandises dans une unité de transport, vous devez déplacer cette dernière sur la même case que les marchandises puis cliquer sur l'icône Charger des marchandises. Vous pouvez également le faire depuis l'espace Transport de l'écran de colonie.</French>
		<German>Um Güter auf ein Transportmittel zu laden, müssen Sie die Transporteinheit auf dasselbe Geländefeld wie die Güter bewegen und auf "Beladen" klicken. Dies ist ebenfalls im Menü "Transport" im Siedlungsbildschirm möglich.</German>
		<Italian>Per caricare dei beni su un trasporto devi prima spostare l'unità da trasporto nella stessa casella in cui si trovano i beni, per poi cliccare sull'icona "Carica beni". Puoi anche farlo dalla sezione "Trasporti" nella schermata dell'insediamento.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Para cargar mercancías en un transporte, debéis llevar la unidad de transporte a la misma casilla en la que estén las mercancías y pulsar en el icono "Cargar mercancías". También podéis hacerlo en la sección de "Transporte", en la pantalla del asentamiento.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_46</Tag>
		<English>Pioneers and scouts need provisions to go with their tools and horses. To keep costs down the baker's house and the powder maker's house should be among your first buildings.</English>
		<French>Il existe deux manières de décharger des marchandises : en sélectionnant la marchandise à décharger dans la pile d'unités puis en appuyant sur Décharger dans la boîte d'ordre, ou en activant l'unité de transport puis en cliquant sur Décharger tout. Vous ne pouvez décharger des marchandises que dans les colonies et en Europe.</French>
		<German>Sie können Güter auf zwei verschiedene Arten entladen : indem Sie das gewünschte Gut aus den Einheiten auswählen und in der Befehlsanzeige "Entladen" anklicken oder indem Sie die Transporteinheit aktivieren und "Alle entladen" anklicken. Sie können Güter nur in Siedlungen (oder in Europa) entladen.</German>
		<Italian>Puoi scaricare i beni in due modi: selezionando il bene che vuoi scaricare dal gruppo e scegliendo "Scarica" nella finestra degli ordini, oppure attivando l'unità di trasporto e cliccando su "Scarica tutto". Puoi scaricare i beni solo negli insediamenti (o in Europa).</Italian>
		<Spanish>Hay dos maneras de descargar mercancías: seleccionando la mercancía que os gustaría descargar y pulsando "Desembarcar" en el visor de órdenes; o activando la unidad de transporte y haciendo clic en "Desembarcar todas". Solo podéis descargar mercancías en los asentamientos (o en Europa).</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_48</Tag>
		<English>You cannot build a settlement directly next to another European settlement. You can, however, build directly next to a Native settlement. You will have to pay for any of their land you claim, or risk incurring their wrath.</English>
		<French>Il est impossible d'accoler une nouvelle colonie à une autre colonie européenne. Vous pouvez, en revanche, l'accoler à une colonie indigène. Vous devrez alors leur acheter toute case de terre que vous désirez saisir, ou risquer de subir leur courroux.</French>
		<German>Sie können nicht direkt neben einer anderen europäischen Siedlung eine Siedlung errichten. Direkt neben einer Ureinwohner-Siedlung ist dies zwar möglich, Sie müssen jedoch entweder für das Land, das Sie beanspruchen, bezahlen oder das Risiko eingehen, sich den Zorn der Ureinwohner zuzuziehen.</German>
		<Italian>Non puoi costruire un insediamento adiacente a un altro insediamento europeo. Però puoi costruirlo direttamente adiacente a un insediamento nativo. Dovrai pagare per la terra che occupi, oppure rischiare di scatenare le loro ire.</Italian>
		<Spanish>No podéis construir un asentamiento justo al lado de otro asentamiento europeo. No obstante, podéis construirlo al lado de un asentamiento indígena. Tendréis que pagar por cada tierra que les quitéis u os arriesgáis a despertar su ira.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_1</Tag>
		<English>They brought us sticks of the cotton candy thread and parrots and other little things which it would be tedious to list, and exchanged everything for whatever we offered them.[NEWLINE]--- Christopher Columbus, about Arawak Indians (October 13, 1492)</English>
		<French>Maintenez la touche [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ALT &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] enfoncée pour que la colonie construise indéfiniment l'élément choisi.</French>
		<German>Sie sind naiv und großzügig mit ihrem Eigentum. Wenn man um etwas bittet, das sie besitzen, sagen sie nie nein.[NEWLINE]--- Christoph Kolumbus, über die Arawak-Indianer auf den Bahamas</German>
		<Italian>Tieni premuto [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ALT &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] per fare in modo che un insediamento costruisca un oggetto all'infinito...</Italian>
		<Spanish>Mantener Pulsara la tecla [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ALT &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] para hacer que el asentamiento construya un elemento indefinidamente.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_2</Tag>
		<English>Press [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + I &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] to play with a minimized interface. Press [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ALT + I &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] to play with no interface.</English>
		<French>Appuyez sur [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + I &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] pour jouer avec une interface réduite. Appuyez sur [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ALT + I &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] pour jouer sans interface.</French>
		<German>Drücken Sie [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; STRG + I &gt;[COLOR_REVERT], wenn Sie mit minimiertem Menü spielen möchten. Mit [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ALT + I &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] können Sie das Menü ausblenden.</German>
		<Italian>Premi [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + I &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] per giocare con l'interfaccia minimizzata. Premi [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ALT + I &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] per giocare senza interfaccia.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pulsar [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + I &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] para jugar con una interfaz minimizada. Pulsar [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ALT + I &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] para jugar sin interfaz.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_3</Tag>
		<English>You can use the mouse wheel or [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; PAGE UP &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] and [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; PAGE DOWN &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] to zoom the camera in and out.</English>
		<French>Vous pouvez utiliser la molette de la souris ou les touches [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; PAGE HAUT &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] et [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; PAGE BAS &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] pour zoomer en avant ou en arrière.</French>
		<German>Drehen Sie das Mausrad oder drücken Sie [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; BILD AUF &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] oder [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; BILD AB &gt;[COLOR_REVERT], um den Zoomfaktor der Kamera zu ändern.</German>
		<Italian>Puoi usare i tasti [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; PAG SU &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] e [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; PAG GIÙ &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] per zoomare la visuale avanti e indietro.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Se puede usar la rueda del ratón o [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; RE PÁG &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] y [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; AV PÁG &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] para acercar y alejar la cámara.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_4</Tag>
		<English>Press [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + S &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] to save the game and [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + L &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] to load a saved game.</English>
		<French>Appuyez sur [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + S &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] pour sauvegarder la partie, sur [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + L &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] pour charger une sauvegarde.</French>
		<German>Drücken Sie [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; STRG + S &gt;[COLOR_REVERT], um das Spiel zu speichern. Mit [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; STRG + L &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] können Sie ein gespeichertes Spiel laden.</German>
		<Italian>Premi [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + S &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] per salvare la partita e [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + L &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] per caricare una partita salvata.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pulsar [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + S &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] para guardar la partida y [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + L &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] para cargar una guardada.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_5</Tag>
		<English>Press [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + (LEFT ARROW) &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] or [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + (RIGHT ARROW) &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] to rotate and set the camera by 45 degrees.</English>
		<French>Appuyez sur [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + (FLECHE GAUCHE) &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] ou [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + (FLECHE DROITE) &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] pour faire pivoter la caméra de 45 degrés.</French>
		<German>Drücken Sie [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; STRG + PFEIL LINKS &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] oder [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; STRG + PFEIL RECHTS &gt;[COLOR_REVERT], um die Kamera in 45-Grad-Schritten zu drehen.</German>
		<Italian>Premi [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + (FRECCIA SINISTRA) &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] o [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + (FRECCIA DESTRA) &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] per ruotare la visuale e impostarla a 45 gradi.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pulsar [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + (FLECHA IZQ.) &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] o [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + (FLECHA DER.) &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] para girar la cámara 45 grados.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_6</Tag>
		<English>Double clicking on a stack of units will group them together.</English>
		<French>Double-cliquez sur des unités empilées pour les regrouper.</French>
		<German>Doppelklicken Sie auf mehrere Einheiten, um diese zu gruppieren.</German>
		<Italian>Doppio clic su un gruppo di unità per unirle.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Hacer doble clic en un apilamiento de unidades las agrupará.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_7</Tag>
		<English>Hold down [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ALT &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] and click on a stack to select all units.</English>
		<French>Pour sélectionner toutes les unités, maintenez la touche [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ALT &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] enfoncée et cliquez sur une pile.</French>
		<German>Halten Sie [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ALT &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] gedrückt und klicken Sie auf einen Stapel, um alle Einheiten auszuwählen.</German>
		<Italian>Tieni premuto [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ALT &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] e clicca su una pila per selezionare tutte le unità.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Mantener Pulsaro [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ALT &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] y hacer clic en un apilamiento selecciona a todas las unidades.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_8</Tag>
		<English>Hold down [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] and click on a stack to select all units of the same type.</English>
		<French>Pour sélectionner toutes les unités de même type, maintenez la touche [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] enfoncée et cliquez sur une pile.</French>
		<German>Halten Sie [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; STRG &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] gedrückt und klicken Sie auf einen Stapel, um alle Einheiten eines Typs auszuwählen.</German>
		<Italian>Tieni premuto [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] e clicca su una pila per selezionare tutte le unità dello stesso tipo.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Mantener Pulsaro [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] y hacer clic en un apilamiento selecciona a todas las unidades del mismo tipo.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_9</Tag>
		<English>With multiple units selected, you can give the group orders that they will conduct together.</English>
		<French>Si vous avez sélectionné plusieurs unités, vous pouvez leur donner des ordres de groupe.</French>
		<German>Haben Sie mehrere Einheiten ausgewählt, können Sie der gesamten Gruppe Befehle erteilen.</German>
		<Italian>Quando più unità sono selezionate, puoi impartire ordini a tutto il gruppo.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Con varias unidades seleccionadas, se pueden dar órdenes de grupo que éstas llevarán a cabo a la vez.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_10</Tag>
		<English>[COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; RIGHT-CLICKING &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] on a transport will automatically load the units onto it.</English>
		<French>[COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CLIQUEZ DROIT &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] sur un transport pour charger automatiquement les unités sélectionnées à bord.</French>
		<German>Nach einem [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; RECHTSKLICK &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] auf ein Transportschiff gehen die Einheiten automatisch an Bord.</German>
		<Italian>Clicca con il [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; PULSANTE DESTRO &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] su un mezzo di trasporto per caricare automaticamente le unità a bordo.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Hacer [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CLIC DERECHO &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] en un transporte embarcará directamente las unidades en él.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_11</Tag>
		<English>With a transport selected, [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; RIGHT-CLICKING &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] on an adjacent land square will automatically unload the units.</English>
		<French>Pour décharger des unités d'un transport, sélectionnez-le et [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CLIQUEZ DROIT &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] sur une case de terrain adjacente.</French>
		<German>Haben Sie ein Transportschiff ausgewählt, gehen alle Einheiten nach einem [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; RECHTSKLICK &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] auf ein angrenzendes Geländefeld automatisch von Bord.</German>
		<Italian>Quando hai selezionato un mezzo di trasporto, clicca con il [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; PULSANTE DESTRO &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] del mouse su una casella adiacente per sbarcare automaticamente le unità a bordo.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Con un transporte seleccionado, hacer [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CLIC DERECHO &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] en una casilla de tierra adyacente desembarcará automáticamente a las unidades.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_12</Tag>
		<English>Press [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; F12 &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] to access the Colopedia.</English>
		<French>Appuyez sur [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; F12 &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] pour ouvrir la Colopedia.</French>
		<German>Drücken Sie [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; F12 &gt;[COLOR_REVERT], wenn Sie die Colopedia öffnen möchten.</German>
		<Italian>Premi [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; F12 &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] per accedere alla Colopedia.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pulsar [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; F12 &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] para acceder a la Colopedia.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_13</Tag>
		<English>Press [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; PRINT SCREEN &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] to take a screenshot (It will be saved in your Colonization\Screenshots folder).</English>
		<French>Appuyez sur [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; IMPR ECRAN &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] pour faire une capture d'écran (sauvegardée dans le répertoire Colonization\Screenshots).</French>
		<German>Drücken Sie [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; DRUCK &gt;[COLOR_REVERT], um einen Screenshot zu machen und unter "Colonization\Screenshots" zu speichern.</German>
		<Italian>Premi [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; STAMP &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] per scattare una foto che verrà salvata in Colonization\Screenshots...</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pulsar [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; PRINT SCREEN &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] para hacer una captura de pantalla (se guardará en la carpeta Colonization\Screenshots).</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_14</Tag>
		<English>Press [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ESC &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] to bring up the in-game Options Menu.</English>
		<French>Appuyez sur [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ECHAP &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] pour ouvrir le menu Options de jeu.</French>
		<German>Drücken Sie [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ESC &gt;[COLOR_REVERT], um das Pausemenü zu öffnen.</German>
		<Italian>Premi [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ESC &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] per richiamare il menu di opzioni mentre stai giocando.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pulsar [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ESC &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] para que aparezca el menú Opciones durante la partida.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_15</Tag>
		<English>Press [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + O &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] to bring up the Options Menu.</English>
		<French>Appuyez sur [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + O &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] pour ouvrir le menu Options.</French>
		<German>Drücken sie [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; STRG + O &gt;[COLOR_REVERT], um das Optionen-Menü zu öffnen.</German>
		<Italian>Premi [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + O &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] per richiamare il menu di opzioni.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pulsar [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + O &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] para que aparezca el menú Opciones.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_16</Tag>
		<English>Press the middle mouse button to center the camera on the active unit.</English>
		<French>Appuyez sur le bouton central de la souris pour centrer la caméra sur l'unité active.</French>
		<German>Drücken Sie die mittlere Maustaste, um die Kamera über der aktiven Einheit zu zentrieren.</German>
		<Italian>Premi il pulsante centrale del mouse per centrare la visuale sull'unità attiva.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pulsar el botón central del ratón para centrar la cámara en la unidad activa.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_17</Tag>
		<English>Press [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; SHIFT + F5 &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] (Single Player Only) to Quick Save.</English>
		<French>Appuyez sur [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; MAJ + F5 &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] (Solo uniquement) pour une sauvegarde rapide.</French>
		<German>Drücken Sie (nur im Einzelspieler-Modus) [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; UMSCHALTEN + F5 &gt;[COLOR_REVERT], um das Spiel schnell zu speichern.</German>
		<Italian>Premi [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; MAIUSC + F5 &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] (solo Giocatore Singolo) per effettuare un salvataggio rapido.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pulsar [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; MAYÚS + F5 &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] (solo en partidas de un jugador) para hacer un guardado rápido.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_18</Tag>
		<English>Press [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; SHIFT + F8 &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] (Single Player Only) to Quick Load.</English>
		<French>Appuyez sur [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; MAJ + F8 &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] (Solo uniquement) pour un chargement rapide.</French>
		<German>Drücken Sie (nur im Einzelspieler-Modus) [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; UMSCHALTEN + F8 &gt;[COLOR_REVERT], um ein Spiel schnell zu laden.</German>
		<Italian>Premi [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; MAIUSC + F8 &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] (solo Giocatore Singolo) per effettuare un caricamento rapido.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pulsar [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; MAYÚS + F8 &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] (solo en partidas de un jugador) para hacer una carga rápida.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_19</Tag>
		<English>Press [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + P &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] to ping the map and provide info to teammates.</English>
		<French>Appuyez sur [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + P &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] pour marquer la carte et fournir des infos à vos coéquipiers.</French>
		<German>Drücken Sie [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; STRG + P &gt;[COLOR_REVERT], um die Karte anzupingen und Ihren Teammitgliedern Informationen zu senden.</German>
		<Italian>Premi [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + P &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] per segnare un punto sulla mappa e fornire informazioni ai tuoi compagni di squadra.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pulsar [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + P &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] para hacer una señal en el mapa y dar información a los compañeros de equipo.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_20</Tag>
		<English>Press [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + # key &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] to bind the selected unit to that # key. For example: [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + 3 &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] would make it so any time [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; 3 &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] is pressed, that unit is automatically selected.</English>
		<French>Appuyez sur [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + touche numérique &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] pour affecter l'unité sélectionnée à cette touche. Par exemple, avec [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + 3 &gt;[COLOR_REVERT], l'unité sera automatiquement sélectionnée à chaque fois que vous appuierez sur la touche [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; 3 &gt;[COLOR_REVERT].</French>
		<German>Drücken Sie [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; STRG + Zahl &gt;[COLOR_REVERT], um der gewählten Einheit die Zahl zuzuweisen. Beispiel: Drücken Sie [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; STRG + 3 &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] wird die entsprechende Einheit ausgewählt, sobald Sie die [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; 3 &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] drücken.</German>
		<Italian>Premi [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + # &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] per assegnare l'unità selezionata al tasto #. Per esempio, premendo [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + 3 &gt;[COLOR_REVERT], ogni volta che si premerà il tasto [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; 3 &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] quell'unità verrà automaticamente selezionata.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pulsar [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + número &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] para vincular la unidad seleccionada a ese número. Por ejemplo: [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + 3 &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] hará que la unidad quede seleccionada automáticamente cada vez que se pulse el [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; 3 &gt;[COLOR_REVERT].</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_21</Tag>
		<English>While in the settlement screen, press [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + # &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] to save the production queue. This queue can be loaded in any other settlement by pressing the [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; # &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] key.</English>
		<French>A partir de l'écran des colonies, appuyez sur [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + # &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] pour sauvegarder la file d'attente de production. Cette file d'attente peut être chargée dans n'importe quelle autre colonie en appuyant sur la touche [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; # &gt;[COLOR_REVERT].</French>
		<German>Drücken Sie im Siedlungsbildschirm [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; STRG + Zifferntaste &gt;[COLOR_REVERT], um die Produktionsliste zu speichern. Drücken Sie in einer beliebigen anderen Siedlung die gewünschte Zifferntaste, wenn Sie die Produktionsliste laden möchten.</German>
		<Italian>Mentre ti trovi nella schermata dell'insediamento, [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + # &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] per salvare la coda di produzione. Questa coda può essere caricata in qualsiasi altro insediamento premendo il tasto [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; # &gt;[COLOR_REVERT].</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pulsar [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + número &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] en la pantalla del asentamiento para guardar la cola de producción. Se podrá cargar esa cola en cualquier otro asentamiento pulsando dicho número.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_22</Tag>
		<English>Press [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; F11 &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] to quickly switch in and out of Globe View.</English>
		<French>Appuyez sur [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; F11 &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] pour passer rapidement à la vue du Globe.</French>
		<German>Drücken Sie [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; F11 &gt;[COLOR_REVERT], um zur Welt-Ansicht zu wechseln.</German>
		<Italian>Premi [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; F11 &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] per attivare/disattivare la visuale globale.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pulsar [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; F11 &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] para entrar y salir de la Vista global.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_23</Tag>
		<English>While in the settlement screen, you can use [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; LEFT ARROW &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] and [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; RIGHT ARROW &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] to cycle between settlements.</English>
		<French>Lorsque l'écran de colonie est affiché, vous pouvez utiliser les touches [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; FLECHE GAUCHE &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] et [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; FLECHE DROITE &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] pour faire défiler les colonies.</French>
		<German>Im Siedlungsbildschirm können Sie mit [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; PFEIL LINKS &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] und [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; PFEIL RECHTS &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] durch Ihre Siedlungen schalten.</German>
		<Italian>Quando sei nella schermata dell'insediamento, puoi usare la [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; FRECCIA SINISTRA &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] e la [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; FRECCIA DESTRA &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] per scorrere gli insediamenti...</Italian>
		<Spanish>En la pantalla del asentamiento se puede usar la [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; FLECHA IZQUIERDA &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] y la [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; FLECHA DERECHA &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] para pasar de un asentamiento a otro.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_24</Tag>
		<English>Press [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + B &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] to toggle Bare Map view.</English>
		<French>Appuyez sur [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + B &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] pour afficher ou masquer la carte vierge.</French>
		<German>Drücken Sie [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; STRG + B &gt;[COLOR_REVERT], um die Kartenansicht zu aktivieren.</German>
		<Italian>Premi [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + B &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] per attivare/disattivare la visuale mappa semplificata.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pulsar [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + B &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] para activar la vista del mapa limpio.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_25</Tag>
		<English>Press [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + R &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] to toggle Flag Resources view.</English>
		<French>Appuyez sur [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + R &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] pour afficher ou masquer les ressources.</French>
		<German>Drücken Sie [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; STRG + R &gt;[COLOR_REVERT], um in die Ressourcen-Ansicht zu wechseln.</German>
		<Italian>Premi [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + R &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] per visualizzare/nascondere la segnalazione risorse.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pulsar [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + R &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] para activar las marcas de recursos.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_26</Tag>
		<English>Press [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + Y &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] to toggle Show Yields view.</English>
		<French>Appuyez sur [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + Y &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] pour afficher ou masquer les icones de production.</French>
		<German>Drücken Sie [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; STRG + Y &gt;[COLOR_REVERT], um in die Einkünfte-Ansicht zu wechseln.</German>
		<Italian>Premi [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + Y &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] per visualizzare/nascondere la produzione.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pulsar [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + Y &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] para activar la vista Mostrar rendimientos.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_27</Tag>
		<English>Press [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + A &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] to force all units with queued orders to move.</English>
		<French>Appuyez sur [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + A &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] pour forcer toutes les unités ayant des ordres en attente à se déplacer.</French>
		<German>Drücken Sie [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; STRG + A &gt;[COLOR_REVERT], um alle Einheiten mit einer Befehlsliste zu bewegen.</German>
		<Italian>Premi [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + A &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] per forzare il movimento di tutte le unità con ordini in coda.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pulsar [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + A &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] para obligar a moverse a todas las unidades con órdenes en cola.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_28</Tag>
		<English>Press [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + T &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] to toggle the Tile Grid</English>
		<French>Appuyez sur [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + T &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] pour afficher ou masquer la grille.</French>
		<German>Blenden Sie das Geländeraster mit [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; STRG + T &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] ein/aus.</German>
		<Italian>Premi [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + T &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] per attivare la griglia delle caselle.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pulsar [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + T &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] para activar la cuadrícula.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_29</Tag>
		<English>Press [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ALT + Q &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] to retire from the game. In multiplayer this automatically gives control of your colonies to an AI.</English>
		<French>Appuyez sur [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ALT + Q &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] pour abandonner le jeu. En mode multijoueur, cette action confère automatiquement le contrôle de vos colonies à une IA.</French>
		<German>Drücken Sie [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ALT + Q &gt;[COLOR_REVERT], um das Spiel zu verlassen. Im Multiplayer-Modus übernimmt nun die KI die Kontrolle über Ihre Kolonien.</German>
		<Italian>Premi [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ALT + Q &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] per ritirarti dalla partita. Nel multigiocatore, il controllo della tua colonia viene automaticamente assegnato alla IA.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pulsar [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ALT + Q &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] para retirarse de la partida. En el modo para varios jugadores esto le dará el control de las colonias a la IA.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_30</Tag>
		<English>Press [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; PAUSE &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] to interrupt the Turn Timer.</English>
		<French>Appuyez sur [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; PAUSE &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] pour interrompre le chronomètre de tour.</French>
		<German>Drücken Sie [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; PAUSE &gt;[COLOR_REVERT], um den Runden-Timer anzuhalten.</German>
		<Italian>Premi [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; PAUSA &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] per interrompere il timer del turno.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pulsar [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; PAUSA &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] para interrumpir el contador del turno.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_31</Tag>
		<English>Press [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; SHIFT + TAB &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] to chat to All in multiplayer.</English>
		<French>Appuyez sur [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; MAJ + TAB &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] en mode Multijoueur pour parler à tous les autres joueurs.</French>
		<German>Drücken Sie im Multiplayer-Modus [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; UMSCHALTEN + TAB &gt;[COLOR_REVERT], um mit allen Anwesenden zu chatten.</German>
		<Italian>Premi [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; MAIUSC + TAB &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] per comunicare via chat con tutti in Multigiocatore.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pulsar [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; MAYÚS + TAB &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] para charlar con todos en el modo multijugador.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_32</Tag>
		<English>Press [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; TAB &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] to chat to teammates in Multiplayer.</English>
		<French>Appuyez sur [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; TAB &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] en mode Multijoueur pour parler à vos coéquipiers.</French>
		<German>Drücken Sie im Multiplayer-Modus [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; TAB &gt;[COLOR_REVERT], um mit den Mitgliedern Ihres Teams zu chatten.</German>
		<Italian>Premi [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; TAB &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] per comunicare via chat con gli alleati in Multigiocatore.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pulsar [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; TAB &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] para charlar con los compañeros de equipo en el modo multijugador.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_33</Tag>
		<English>Press [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + W &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] to access the Worldbuilder.</English>
		<French>Appuyez sur [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + Z &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] pour ouvrir l'éditeur de mondes.</French>
		<German>Rufen Sie mit [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + W &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] den Weltenbauer auf.</German>
		<Italian>Premi [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + W &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] per accedere all'editor.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pulsar [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + W &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] para acceder al creador de mundos.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_34</Tag>
		<English>Press [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; W &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] or [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ENTER &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] to cycle through your active units.</English>
		<French>Appuyez sur [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; Z &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] ou [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ENTREE &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] pour parcourir les unités actives.</French>
		<German>Drücken Sie [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; W &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] oder [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; EINGABETASTE &gt;[COLOR_REVERT], um durch Ihre aktiven Einheiten zu schalten.</German>
		<Italian>Premi [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; W &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] o [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; INVIO &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] per scorrere le unità attive.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pulsar [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; W &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] o [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; INTRO &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] para pasar de una unidad activa a otra.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_36</Tag>
		<English>Press [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; COMMA &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] and [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; PERIOD &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] to scroll though units on the same square.</English>
		<French>Appuyez sur [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; POINT-VIRGULE &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] et [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; DEUX POINTS &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] pour parcourir les unités sur la même case.</French>
		<German>Drücken Sie [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; KOMMA &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] und [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; PUNKT &gt;[COLOR_REVERT], um durch die Einheiten auf einem Geländefeld zu schalten.</German>
		<Italian>Premi [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; , &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] e [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; . &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] per scorrere tra le unità che si trovano nella stessa casella.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pulsar [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; , (coma) &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] y [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; . (punto) &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] para desplazarse por las unidades que estén en la misma casilla.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_37</Tag>
		<English>Press [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; SHIFT + ENTER &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] to force the turn to end.</English>
		<French>Appuyez sur [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; MAJ + ENTREE &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] pour forcer la fin du tour.</French>
		<German>Drücken Sie [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; UMSCHALTEN + EINGABETASTE &gt;[COLOR_REVERT], um die aktuelle Runde zu beenden.</German>
		<Italian>Premi [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; MAIUSC + INVIO &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] per forzare la fine del turno.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pulsar [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; MAYÚS + INTRO &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] para forzar el final del turno.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_38</Tag>
		<English>Hold down the [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ALT &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] key while mousing-over a plot to view the combat odds for an attack.</English>
		<French>Maintenez la touche [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ALT &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] enfoncée quand le curseur est sur une case pour connaître les chances de réussite en cas d'attaque.</French>
		<German>Halten Sie [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ALT &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] gedrückt und bewegen Sie die Maus über eine Position, um Ihre Chancen im Falle eines Angriffs zu betrachten.</German>
		<Italian>Tieni premuto [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ALT &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] e punta con il mouse una casella per visualizzare le probabilità di vittoria in caso di attacco.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Mantener Pulsara la tecla [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ALT &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] mientras se señala una casilla con el cursor para ver las probabilidades de un ataque.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_39</Tag>
		<English>To view combat odds, hold down the right mouse button on the target tile.</English>
		<French>Pour connaître vos chances en cas de combat, maintenez le bouton droit de la souris enfoncé sur la case visée.</French>
		<German>Möchten Sie Ihre Kampfchancen betrachten, halten Sie die rechte Maustaste über dem gewünschten Geländefeld gedrückt.</German>
		<Italian>Per visualizzare le probabilità di vittoria di uno scontro, tieni premuto il pulsante destro del mouse su una casella bersaglio.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Mantener el cursor encima de la casilla objetivo para ver las probabilidades del combate.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_40</Tag>
		<English>Press [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; HOME &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] and [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; END &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] to cycle through your settlements.</English>
		<French>Appuyez sur [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ORIGINE &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] et [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; FIN &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] pour faire défiler vos colonies.</French>
		<German>Drücken Sie [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; POS1 &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] und [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ENDE &gt;[COLOR_REVERT], um durch Ihre Siedlungen zu schalten.</German>
		<Italian>Premi [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; HOME &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] e [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; FINE &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] per scorrere i tuoi insediamenti...</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pulsar [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; INICIO &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] y [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; FIN &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] para pasar de un asentamiento a otro.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_41</Tag>
		<English>Press [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; INSERT &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] to open up the nearest friendly settlement.</English>
		<French>Appuyez sur [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; INSERT &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] pour afficher le territoire ami le plus proche.</French>
		<German>Drücken Sie [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; EINFG &gt;[COLOR_REVERT], um einen Blick auf die nächstgelegene verbündete Siedlung zu werfen.</German>
		<Italian>Premi [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; INS &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] per aprire la schermata dell'insediamento alleato più vicino.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pulsar [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; INSERT &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] para abrir el asentamiento amistoso más cercano.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_42</Tag>
		<English>Hold down the [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; SHIFT &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] key to add items to the end of your settlement's build queue.</English>
		<French>Maintenez la touche [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; MAJ &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] enfoncée pour ajouter des éléments à la fin de la file d'attente des bâtiments à construire dans votre colonie.</French>
		<German>Halten Sie [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; UMSCHALTEN &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] gedrückt, um Objekte dem Ende der Bauliste Ihrer Siedlung hinzuzufügen.</German>
		<Italian>Tieni premuto [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; MAIUSC &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] per aggiungere degli oggetti in fondo alla coda di costruzione del tuo insediamento.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Mantener Pulsara la tecla [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; MAYÚS &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] para añadir elementos al final de la cola de construcción del asentamiento.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_43</Tag>
		<English>Hold down the [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] key to insert items at the beginning of your settlement's build queue.</English>
		<French>Maintenez la touche [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] enfoncée pour insérer des éléments au début de la file d'attente des bâtiments à construire dans votre colonie.</French>
		<German>Halten Sie [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; STRG &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] gedrückt, um Objekte dem Anfang der Bauliste Ihrer Siedlung hinzuzufügen.</German>
		<Italian>Tieni premuto [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] per aggiungere degli oggetti all'inizio della coda di costruzione del tuo insediamento.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Mantener Pulsara la tecla [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] para insertar elementos al principio de la cola de construcción del asentamiento.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_45</Tag>
		<English>Press the forward and back buttons on your mouse to cycle through units on the same plot.</English>
		<French>Appuyez sur le bouton Suivant et Précédent de votre souris pour faire défiler les unités stationnées sur la même case.</French>
		<German>Drücken Sie die Vorwärts-/Rückwärts-Tasten Ihrer Maus, um durch alle Einheiten auf einem Geländefeld zu schalten.</German>
		<Italian>Premi i pulsanti su e giù sul mouse per scorrere le unità sulla stessa casella.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pulsar los botones de adelante y atrás del ratón para pasar de una unidad a otra en la misma casilla.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_46</Tag>
		<English>Hold down the [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] key and spin the mouse-wheel to cycle through units on the same plot.</English>
		<French>Maintenez la touche [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] enfoncée et utilisez la molette de la souris pour parcourir les unités sur la même case.</French>
		<German>Halten Sie [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; STRG &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] gedrückt und schalten Sie mit dem Mausrad durch alle Einheiten auf dem gewünschten Geländefeld.</German>
		<Italian>Tieni premuto il tasto [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] e usa la rotellina del mouse per scorrere tra le unità sulla stessa casella.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Mantener Pulsara la tecla [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] y girar la rueda del ratón para pasar de una unidad a otra en la misma casilla.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_47</Tag>
		<English>Press [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + M &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] to toggle the music on and off.</English>
		<French>Appuyez sur [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + VIRGULE &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] pour activer ou désactiver la musique.</French>
		<German>Drücken Sie [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; STRG + M &gt;[COLOR_REVERT], um die Musik ein- oder auszublenden.</German>
		<Italian>Premi [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + M &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] per attivare e disattivare la musica.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pulsar [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + M &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] para encender o apagar la música.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_48</Tag>
		<English>Move units to a distant tile by a [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; RIGHT-CLICK &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] on the destination.</English>
		<French>Déplacez les unités vers une tuile éloignée en faisant un [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CLIC DROIT &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] sur la destination.</French>
		<German>Per [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; RECHTSKLICK &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] schicken Sie Ihre Einheiten auf das gewünschte Geländefeld.</German>
		<Italian>Muovi le unità su una casella lontana cliccandoci sopra con il [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; PULSANTE DESTRO &gt;[COLOR_REVERT].</Italian>
		<Spanish>Se pueden mover unidades a una casilla lejana haciendo [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CLIC DERECHO &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] en ella.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_49</Tag>
		<English>You can group move all units of the same type by a [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + RIGHT-CLICK &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] on the destination.</English>
		<French>Pour regrouper et déplacer toutes les unités du même type, appuyez sur [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] et faites un [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CLIC DROIT &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] sur la destination.</French>
		<German>Mit [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; STRG + RECHTSKLICK &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] schicken Sie alle Einheiten eines Typs zum gewünschten Geländefeld.</German>
		<Italian>Puoi muovere un gruppo di unità dello stesso tipo con [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + PULSANTE DESTRO &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] sulla destinazione.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Se pueden mover en grupo todas las unidades del mismo tipo pulsando [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + CLIC DERECHO &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] en el lugar de destino.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_50</Tag>
		<English>You can group move all units on the same tile by a [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ALT + RIGHT-CLICK &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] on the destination.</English>
		<French>Pour regrouper et déplacer toutes les unités sur la même case, appuyez sur touche [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ALT &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] et faites un [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CLIC DROIT &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] sur la destination.</French>
		<German>Sie können alle Einheiten eines Feldes mit [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ALT + RECHTSKLICK &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] auf die gewünschte Position bewegen.</German>
		<Italian>Puoi muovere un gruppo di unità sulla stessa casella con [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ALT + PULSANTE DESTRO &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] sulla destinazione.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Se pueden mover en grupo todas las unidades de la misma casilla pulsando [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ALT + CLIC DERECHO &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] en el lugar de destino.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_51</Tag>
		<English>Enter "Go-To" Mode by pressing [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; G &gt;[COLOR_REVERT].</English>
		<French>Pour activer le mode "Aller vers", appuyez sur [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; G &gt;[COLOR_REVERT].</French>
		<German>Drücken Sie [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; G &gt;[COLOR_REVERT], um den "Gehe zu"-Modus zu aktivieren.</German>
		<Italian>Passa alla modalità "Vai a" premendo [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; G &gt;[COLOR_REVERT].</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pulsar [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; G &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] para entrar en el modo "Ir a".</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_52</Tag>
		<English>Enter "Go-To (Same Unit Type)" Mode by pressing [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + G &gt;[COLOR_REVERT].</English>
		<French>Pour activer le mode "Aller vers (même type d'unité)", appuyez sur [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + G &gt;[COLOR_REVERT].</French>
		<German>Drücken Sie [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; STRG + G &gt;[COLOR_REVERT], um den "Gehe zu"-Modus für alle Einheiten eines Typs zu aktivieren.</German>
		<Italian>Passa alla modalità "Vai a (unità dello stesso tipo)" premendo [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + G &gt;[COLOR_REVERT].</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pulsar [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + G &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] para entrar en el modo "Ir a (mismo tipo de unidad)".</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_53</Tag>
		<English>Enter "Go-To (All Units)" Mode by pressing [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ALT + G &gt;[COLOR_REVERT].</English>
		<French>Pour activer le mode "Aller vers (toutes unités)", appuyez sur [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ALT + G &gt;[COLOR_REVERT].</French>
		<German>Drücken Sie [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ALT + G &gt;[COLOR_REVERT], um den "Gehe zu"-Modus für alle Einheiten zu aktivieren.</German>
		<Italian>Passa alla modalità "Vai a (tutte le unità)" premendo [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ALT + G &gt;[COLOR_REVERT].</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pulsar [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ALT + G &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] para entrar en el modo "Ir a (todas las unidades)".</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_54</Tag>
		<English>Press [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; C &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] to center the camera on the active unit.</English>
		<French>Appuyez sur [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; C &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] pour centrer la caméra sur l'unité active.</French>
		<German>Drücken Sie [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; C &gt;[COLOR_REVERT], um die Kamera auf die aktive Einheit zu zentrieren.</German>
		<Italian>Premi [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; C &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] per centrare la visuale sull'unità attiva.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pulsar [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; C &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] para centrar la cámara en la unidad activa.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_56</Tag>
		<English>Press [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ALT + C &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] to select all units on the same tile as the active unit.</English>
		<French>Appuyez sur [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ALT + C &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] pour sélectionner toutes les unités sur la même case que l'unité active.</French>
		<German>Drücken Sie [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ALT + C &gt;[COLOR_REVERT], um die aktive Einheit und alle Einheiten auf demselben Feld auszuwählen.</German>
		<Italian>Premi [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ALT + C &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] per selezionare tutte le unità sulla stessa casella di quella attiva.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pulsar [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ALT + C &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] para seleccionar todas las unidades de la misma casilla que la unidad activa.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_62</Tag>
		<English>Hold down [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; SHIFT &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] and click on a tile to open a context menu.</English>
		<French>Maintenez la touche [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; MAJ &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] enfoncée et cliquez sur une case pour ouvrir un menu contextuel.</French>
		<German>Halten Sie die [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; UMSCHALT-Taste &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] gedrückt und klicken Sie auf ein Geländefeld, um ein Kontextmenü zu öffnen.</German>
		<Italian>Tieni premuto il tasto [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; MAIUSC &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] e clicca su una casella per aprire un menu contestuale.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Mantener Pulsara la tecla [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; MAYÚS &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] y hacer clic en una casilla para abrir un menú contextual.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_64</Tag>
		<English>Press [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; \ &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] to jump back to the last selected unit.</English>
		<French>Appuyez sur [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; \ &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] pour revenir à la dernière unité sélectionnée.</French>
		<German>Drücken Sie [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; # &gt;[COLOR_REVERT], um zur letzten gewählten Einheit zu springen.</German>
		<Italian>Premi [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; \ &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] per tornare all'ultima unità selezionata.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pulsar [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; \ &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] para volver a la anterior unidad seleccionada.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_65</Tag>
		<English>Press [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + TAB &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] to view the turn event log.</English>
		<French>Appuyez sur [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + TAB &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] pour afficher le journal des événements du tour.</French>
		<German>Drücken Sie [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; STRG + TAB &gt;[COLOR_REVERT], um das Rundenereignis-Log aufzurufen.</German>
		<Italian>Premi [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + TAB &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] per vedere il registro degli eventi.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pulsar [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + TAB &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] para ver el historial de sucesos del turno.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_66</Tag>
		<English>Press [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ALT + S &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] to add a sign to the map that you and your teammates can see.</English>
		<French>Appuyez sur [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ALT + S &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] pour ajouter un panneau sur la carte pour vous et vos coéquipiers...</French>
		<German>Drücken Sie [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ALT + S &gt;[COLOR_REVERT], um ein Zeichen auf der Karte zu platzieren, das nur Sie und Ihre Teammitglieder sehen können.</German>
		<Italian>Premi [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ALT + S &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] per aggiungere sulla mappa un segnale visibile soltanto a te e ai tuoi alleati.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pulsa [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; ALT + S &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] para añadir al mapa un letrero que podáis ver tus compañeros y tú.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_INTERFACE_67</Tag>
		<English>Press [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + H &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] to select all wounded units in a tile.</English>
		<French>Appuyez sur [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + H &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] pour sélectionner toutes les unités blessées dans une case.</French>
		<German>Drücken Sie [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; STRG + H &gt;[COLOR_REVERT], um alle verwundeten Einheiten auf einem Geländefeld zu markieren.</German>
		<Italian>Premi [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + H &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] per selezionare tutte le unità ferite sulla casella.</Italian>
		<Spanish>Pulsa [COLOR:140:255:40:255]&lt; CTRL + H &gt;[COLOR_REVERT] para seleccionar todas las unidades heridas en una casilla.</Spanish>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>
