<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_CITY_RUINS</Tag>
        <English>Ruins</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Ruines</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Ruinen</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Rovina:Rovine</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Ruina:Ruinas</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_CITY_RUINS_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Ruins[COLOR_REVERT] are the remnants of a city or improvement that has been abandoned or destroyed. They do not serve any in-game function other than decoration.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Background[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Ruins are the remains of human-made architecture: once complete structures that have fallen into a state of disrepair, either from lack of maintenance or deliberate acts of destruction. Disasters, war and depopulation are the most common causes, after which structures become derelict over time from weather and scavenging.</English>
        <French>[TAB]Les ruines sont les restes d'architecture humaine passée : des structures autrefois complètes qui, par abandon, se sont désagrégés pour atteindre un état difficilement réparable. Les désastres naturels, la guerre ou le dépeuplement sont les causes principales de tels abandons. Les conditions climatiques et le pillage sont les principales causes de délabrement de ces structures.</French>
        <German>[TAB]Ruinen sind die Reste menschlicher Architektur: Strukturen, die einst vollständig waren, dann aber durch den Einfluss der Umwelt, wie Pflanzen, Regen oder Wind, über die Zeit zerfielen. Gründe für die Verwahrlosung können Kriege, Katastrophen Disasters, Krankheiten und vieles mehr gewesen sein.</German>
        <Italian>[TAB]Ruins are the remains of human-made architecture: structures that were once complete, as time went by, have fallen into a state of partial or complete disrepair, due to lack of maintenance or deliberate acts of destruction. Disasters, war and depopulation are the most common root causes, with many structures becoming progressively derelict over time due to long-term weathering and scavenging.</Italian>
        <Spanish>[TAB]Ruins are the remains of human-made architecture: structures that were once complete, as time went by, have fallen into a state of partial or complete disrepair, due to lack of maintenance or deliberate acts of destruction. Disasters, war and depopulation are the most common root causes, with many structures becoming progressively derelict over time due to long-term weathering and scavenging.</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_COCOA_PLANTATION</Tag>
        <English>Cocoa Plantation</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Plantation de cacao</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Kakaoplantage</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Cocoa Plantation</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Plantación de Cacao</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_COCOA_PLANTATION_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Cocoa Plantations[COLOR_REVERT] can be built only in [LINK=FEATURE_JUNGLE]Jungles[\LINK]. They increase the production of [LINK=YIELD_COCOA_FRUITS]Cocoa Pods[\LINK] and [LINK=YIELD_FOOD]Food[\LINK].[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Background[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Cocoa Plantations are usually a mixture of many different kinds of trees and not a monoculture. This ensures a healthy environment for the precious fruits.</English>
        <French>[TAB]Les plantations de cacao sont généralement un mélange de plusieurs types d'arbres et non pas une monoculture. C'est ce qui assure un environnement sain pour les fruits précieux.</French>
        <German>[TAB]Kakaoplantangen sind normalerweise eine Mischung verschiedenster Bäume und Sträucher. Dies ermöglicht ein gesundes Umfeld für die wertvollen Früchte.</German>
        <Italian>[TAB]Cocoa Plantations are usually a mixture of many different kinds of trees and not a monoculture. This ensures a healthy environment for the precious fruits.</Italian>
        <Spanish>[TAB]Cocoa Plantations are usually a mixture of many different kinds of trees and not a monoculture. This ensures a healthy environment for the precious fruits.</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_COLLECTORS_DEPOT</Tag>
        <English>Collectors Depot</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Dépôt de collecte</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Sammeldepot</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Collectors Depot</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Collectors Depot</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_COLLECTORS_DEPOT2</Tag>
        <English>Coca Depot:Coca Depots</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Dépôt de coca:Dépôts de coca</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Coca Depot:Coca Depots</Text>
            <Gender>Neuter</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Coca Depot:Coca Depots</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Coca Depot:Coca Depots</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_COLLECTORS_DEPOT2_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]The [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Coca Depot[COLOR_REVERT] is the upgrade of the [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_COLLECTORS_POST2]Coca Post[\LINK]. It gives a production bonus to [LINK=YIELD_COCA_LEAVES]Coca Leaves[\LINK] and [LINK=YIELD_FOOD]Food[\LINK].[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Background[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Coca Leaves can refer to leaves of all four cultivated plants of the Coca family (Erythoxylaceae) native to western South America. In times both ancient and modern, these plants have been valued for their psychoactive properties, which can be experienced by chewing the leaves, making coca tea ("Mate de coca") out of it and, in modern times, chemically extracting the psychoactive agents to produce the drug Cocaine. Coca Leaves are an effective remedy against altitude sickness, giving the consumer a greater tolerance for hunger, thirst and fatigue. Apart from that, coca is an anaesthetic and, due to its religious significance in indigenous cultures, many other properties are ascribed to it, some of which are supported by modern science.[PARAGRAPH:1] Coca Leaves have been used for medicinal, nutritional and religious purposes in the Andean region since prehistoric times, possibly as long as 8,000 years ago. Over this long period the ancestral coca plant was domesticated, and diversified into the four modern species. In the Incan Empire the plant was thought to have a divine origin, and its leaves were used as offerings, as a method of divination, similar to the reading of tea leaves in the Old World, and also as preparation for prayers or religious ceremonies. It eventually spread over a large area, from Colombia in the north to Chile in the south. [PARAGRAPH:2] After the Spanish conquest of the Incan Empire, the use of the leaf was tolerated by the Spanish, because it enhanced the performance of forced labourers, but its religious use was prohibited, and the Spanish themselves were discouraged from using it. Though it was introduced in Europe in the 16th Century, it never became popular until the 19th century when the first cocaine was produced.</English>
        <French>[TAB]La coca est une plante d'Amérique du Sud de la famille des Érythroxylacées. Elle joue un rôle important dans la culture andine, à travers ses utilisations rituelles ou médicinales des [LINK=YIELD_COCA_LEAVES]feuilles de coca[\LINK]. [PARAGRAPH:1] Elle pousse à l'état sauvage dans la cordillère des Andes à des altitudes variant de 300 à 2 000 m. Comme toutes les espèces du genre Erythroxylum, elle apprécie particulièrement les sols acides. [PARAGRAPH:1]C'est un fondement culturel pour l'Amérique latine - notamment les hauts plateaux andins - où son usage remonte à près de 5 000 ans2. Du fait de ses différentes vertus, c'est une plante sacrée pour certains peuples amérindiens. Pour ces derniers, Mama Coca est la fille de Pachamama. Elle est ainsi utilisée traditionnellement de la Colombie jusqu'au Chili aussi bien pour ses vertus stimulantes que dans le cadre de cérémonies religieuses, elle aurait même servi de taxe d'imposition. Dans l'Empire inca, la coca issue de l'actuel Pérou (tupa coca) servait aux cérémonies religieuses et aux dignitaires alors que la coca issue de l'actuelle Bolivie (muma coca) servait aux fonctionnaires voire au peuple. Son usage est signalé par les conquérants espagnols dès le XVIe siècle qui en condamnent d'abord l'usage la qualifiant de « satanique » avant de l'encourager en constatant l'efficacité en termes de rentabilité sur les travailleurs3. C'est Nicolas Monardés de Séville, un naturaliste espagnol qui en donne la première description dans les années 1580 même si la plante ne sera vraiment connue sur le plan scientifique qu'au XVIIIe siècle3.</French>
        <German>[TAB]Der Begriff [LINK=YIELD_COCA_LEAVES]Cocablätter[\LINK] bezieht sich meist auf Blätter der kultivierten Planzen aus der Familie der Cocapflanzen (Erythoxylaceae), welche im westlichen Teil Südamerikas beheimatet sind. Sowohl in der alten Geschichte, wie auch in der modernen Zeit wurden diese Pflanzen sehr hoch geschätzt, da sie psychoaktive Substanzen beinhalten, die man durch das Kauen der Blätter oder durch den Konsum des daraus aufgebrühten Tees aufnehmen kann. In der heutigen Zeit, wird aus diesen Blättern auch die Droge Kokain gewonnen. Weniger bedenkliche Anwirkungen der Cocablätter sind aber beispielsweise die Anwendung in geringeren Mengen als Mittel gegen Höhenkrankheit oder gegen Hungergefühle, Durstgefühle oder Müdigkeit. Ausserdem kann Coca auch zur Betäubung von Schmerzen verwendet werden.[PARAGRAPH:1] Cocablätter wurden jeher in den Regionen der Anden zu relgiösen, medizinischen und nahrungsergänzenden Zwecken eingesetzt. Wahrscheinlich sogar weit länger als 8000 Jahre. In dieser langen Zeitperiode wurde die Cocapflanze irgendwann domestiziert. Heutzutage wird sie in vier unterschiedlichen Gattungen bzw. Unterarten gezüchtet. Das Imperium der Inkas glaubte an einen göttlichen Ursprung der Planze und verwendeten die Blätter als Opfergaben, aber auch als Mittel um die Zukunft voherzusagen oder einfach nur um Gebete und Zeremonien vorzubereiten. Die Pflanze breitete sich schliesslich über ein sehr grosses Gebiet von Kolumbien im Norden bis Chile im Süden aus. [PARAGRAPH:2] Nach der spanischen Eroberung des Inkareiches wurde die Einnahme der Pflanze weiterhin von den Spaniern toleriert, da sie die Leistung der Zwangsarbeiter steigerte. Die religiöse Verwendung der Pflanze wurde aber verboten. Den Spaniern selbst wurde davon abgeraten die Blätter zu konsumieren. Obwohlb bereits im 16ten Jahrhundert Cocablätter in Europa bekannt waren, erlangten diese dort zu dieser Zeit nie Beliebtheit. Dies änderte sich erst als im 19ten Jahrhundert Kokain entdeckt wurde.</German>
        <Italian>[TAB]Coca Leaves can refer to leaves of all four cultivated plants of the Coca family (Erythoxylaceae), native to western South America. In times both ancient and modern, these plants have been highly valued for their psychoactive properties, which can be experienced by chewing the leaves, making coca tea ("Mate de coca") out of it and, in modern times, chemically extracting the psychoactive agents to produce the drug Cocaine. Coca Leaves are an effective remedy against altitude sickness, and bestows upon its consumer a greater tolerance for hunger, thirst and fatigue. Apart from that, coca can be used as an anaesthetic as well, and due to its religious significance in indigenous cultures, many other properties are ascribed to it, some of which are supported by modern science.[PARAGRAPH:1] Coca Leaves have been used for medicinal, nutritional and religious purposes in the Andean region since prehistoric times, possibly as long as 8000 years before present time. It was during this long period that the ancestral coca plant was eventually domesticated, after which it diversified into the four modern species. In the Incan Empire, the plant was thought to have a divine origin, and its leaves were used as offerings, as a method of divination, similar to the reading of tea leaves in the old world, and also as preparation for prayers or religious ceremonies. It eventually spread to a large area, ranging from Colombia in the north to Chile in the south. [PARAGRAPH:2] After the Spanish conquest of the Incan Empire, the use of the leaf was tolerated by the Spanish, as it also enhanced the performance of forced laborers, but its religious use was prohibited, and the Spanish themselves were discouraged from using it. Though it was introduced in Europe in the 16th Century, it did not actually become popular until the 19th Century, when the first cocaine was produced.</Italian>
        <Spanish>[TAB]Coca Leaves can refer to leaves of all four cultivated plants of the Coca family (Erythoxylaceae), native to western South America. In times both ancient and modern, these plants have been highly valued for their psychoactive properties, which can be experienced by chewing the leaves, making coca tea ("Mate de coca") out of it and, in modern times, chemically extracting the psychoactive agents to produce the drug Cocaine. Coca Leaves are an effective remedy against altitude sickness, and bestows upon its consumer a greater tolerance for hunger, thirst and fatigue. Apart from that, coca can be used as an anaesthetic as well, and due to its religious significance in indigenous cultures, many other properties are ascribed to it, some of which are supported by modern science.[PARAGRAPH:1] Coca Leaves have been used for medicinal, nutritional and religious purposes in the Andean region since prehistoric times, possibly as long as 8000 years before present time. It was during this long period that the ancestral coca plant was eventually domesticated, after which it diversified into the four modern species. In the Incan Empire, the plant was thought to have a divine origin, and its leaves were used as offerings, as a method of divination, similar to the reading of tea leaves in the old world, and also as preparation for prayers or religious ceremonies. It eventually spread to a large area, ranging from Colombia in the north to Chile in the south. [PARAGRAPH:2] After the Spanish conquest of the Incan Empire, the use of the leaf was tolerated by the Spanish, as it also enhanced the performance of forced laborers, but its religious use was prohibited, and the Spanish themselves were discouraged from using it. Though it was introduced in Europe in the 16th Century, it did not actually become popular until the 19th Century, when the first cocaine was produced.</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_COLLECTORS_DEPOT_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Collector's Depots[COLOR_REVERT] are upgrades of [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_COLLECTORS_POST]Collector's Posts[\LINK]. The [LINK=YIELD_FOOD]Food[\LINK] and [LINK=YIELD_RED_PEPPER]Red Pepper[\LINK] production on such tiles is increased.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Background[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Posts start small, just a location indicated by a post, then a shed and, in time, as big as business justifies.</English>
        <French>[TAB]Les piments font partie de l'alimentation des Amériques depuis au moins 9 500 ans. Des traces archéologiques de domestication ont été trouvées dans le sud-ouest de l'équateur il y a plus de 6 000 ans. Le piment semble avoir été une des premières plantes cultivées autogames en Amérique centrale et du Sud.</French>
        <German>[TAB]Eine Sammelstelle ist ein Gebäude, dass der Zwischenlagerung von Gütern für ihren Weitertransport dient.</German>
        <Italian>[TAB](dwelling) Building use for collecting holding food animals tools etc.</Italian>
        <Spanish>[TAB](dwelling) Building use for collecting holding food animals tools etc.</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_COLLECTORS_POST</Tag>
        <English>Collector's Post</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Poste de Collection</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Sammelstelle</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Collector's Post</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Collectors Post</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_COLLECTORS_POST2</Tag>
        <English>Coca Post</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Poste de coca</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Coca Lager</Text>
            <Gender>Neuter</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Coca Post</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Coca Post</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_COLLECTORS_POST2_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]The [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Coca Post[COLOR_REVERT] can be built only on hilly [LINK=TERRAIN_SAVANNAH]Savannah[\LINK] terrain. It gives a production bonus to [LINK=YIELD_COCA_LEAVES]Coca Leaves[\LINK] and [LINK=YIELD_FOOD]Food[\LINK].[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Background[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Coca Leaves can refer to leaves of all four cultivated plants of the Coca family (Erythoxylaceae), native to western South America. In times both ancient and modern, these plants have been highly valued for their psychoactive properties, which can be experienced by chewing the leaves, making coca tea ("Mate de coca") out of it and, in modern times, chemically extracting the psychoactive agents to produce the drug Cocaine. Coca Leaves are an effective remedy against altitude sickness, and give its consumer a greater tolerance for hunger, thirst and fatigue. Apart from that, coca can be used as an anaesthetic and, due to its religious significance in indigenous cultures, many other properties are ascribed to it, some of which are supported by modern science.[PARAGRAPH:1] Coca Leaves have been used for medicinal, nutritional and religious purposes in the Andean region since prehistoric times, possibly as long as 8,000 years ago. It was during this long period that the ancestral coca plant was domesticated, after which it diversified into the four modern species. In the Incan Empire the plant was thought to have a divine origin, and its leaves were used as offerings, as a method of divination similar to the reading of tea leaves in the Old World, and also as preparation for prayers or religious ceremonies. It eventually spread over a large area, from Colombia in the north to Chile in the south. [PARAGRAPH:2] After the Spanish conquest of the Incan Empire, the use of the leaf was tolerated by the Spanish because it enhanced the performance of forced labourers, but its religious use was prohibited, and the Spanish themselves were discouraged from using it. Though it was introduced in Europe in the 16th Century, it never became popular until the 19th century when the first cocaine was produced.</English>
        <French>[TAB]La coca est une plante d'Amérique du Sud de la famille des Érythroxylacées. Elle joue un rôle important dans la culture andine, à travers ses utilisations rituelles ou médicinales des [LINK=YIELD_COCA_LEAVES]feuilles de coca[\LINK]. [PARAGRAPH:1] Elle pousse à l'état sauvage dans la cordillère des Andes à des altitudes variant de 300 à 2 000 m. Comme toutes les espèces du genre Erythroxylum, elle apprécie particulièrement les sols acides. [PARAGRAPH:1]C'est un fondement culturel pour l'Amérique latine - notamment les hauts plateaux andins - où son usage remonte à près de 5 000 ans2. Du fait de ses différentes vertus, c'est une plante sacrée pour certains peuples amérindiens. Pour ces derniers, Mama Coca est la fille de Pachamama. Elle est ainsi utilisée traditionnellement de la Colombie jusqu'au Chili aussi bien pour ses vertus stimulantes que dans le cadre de cérémonies religieuses, elle aurait même servi de taxe d'imposition. Dans l'Empire inca, la coca issue de l'actuel Pérou (tupa coca) servait aux cérémonies religieuses et aux dignitaires alors que la coca issue de l'actuelle Bolivie (muma coca) servait aux fonctionnaires voire au peuple. Son usage est signalé par les conquérants espagnols dès le XVIe siècle qui en condamnent d'abord l'usage la qualifiant de « satanique » avant de l'encourager en constatant l'efficacité en termes de rentabilité sur les travailleurs3. C'est Nicolas Monardés de Séville, un naturaliste espagnol qui en donne la première description dans les années 1580 même si la plante ne sera vraiment connue sur le plan scientifique qu'au XVIIIe siècle3.</French>
        <German>[TAB]Der Begriff [LINK=YIELD_COCA_LEAVES]Cocablätter[\LINK] bezieht sich meist auf Blätter der kultivierten Planzen aus der Familie der Cocapflanzen (Erythoxylaceae), welche im westlichen Teil Südamerikas beheimatet sind. Sowohl in der alten Geschichte, wie auch in der modernen Zeit wurden diese Pflanzen sehr hoch geschätzt, da sie psychoaktive Substanzen beinhalten, die man durch das Kauen der Blätter oder durch den Konsum des daraus aufgebrühten Tees aufnehmen kann. In der heutigen Zeit, wird aus diesen Blättern auch die Droge Kokain gewonnen. Weniger bedenkliche Anwirkungen der Cocablätter sind aber beispielsweise die Anwendung in geringeren Mengen als Mittel gegen Höhenkrankheit oder gegen Hungergefühle, Durstgefühle oder Müdigkeit. Ausserdem kann Coca auch zur Betäubung von Schmerzen verwendet werden.[PARAGRAPH:1] Cocablätter wurden jeher in den Regionen der Anden zu relgiösen, medizinischen und nahrungsergänzenden Zwecken eingesetzt. Wahrscheinlich sogar weit länger als 8000 Jahre. In dieser langen Zeitperiode wurde die Cocapflanze irgendwann domestiziert. Heutzutage wird sie in vier unterschiedlichen Gattungen bzw. Unterarten gezüchtet. Das Imperium der Inkas glaubte an einen göttlichen Ursprung der Planze und verwendeten die Blätter als Opfergaben, aber auch als Mittel um die Zukunft voherzusagen oder einfach nur um Gebete und Zeremonien vorzubereiten. Die Pflanze breitete sich schliesslich über ein sehr grosses Gebiet von Kolumbien im Norden bis Chile im Süden aus. [PARAGRAPH:2] Nach der spanischen Eroberung des Inkareiches wurde die Einnahme der Pflanze weiterhin von den Spaniern toleriert, da sie die Leistung der Zwangsarbeiter steigerte. Die religiöse Verwendung der Pflanze wurde aber verboten. Den Spaniern selbst wurde davon abgeraten die Blätter zu konsumieren. Obwohlb bereits im 16ten Jahrhundert Cocablätter in Europa bekannt waren, erlangten diese dort zu dieser Zeit nie Beliebtheit. Dies änderte sich erst als im 19ten Jahrhundert Kokain entdeckt wurde.</German>
        <Italian>[TAB]Coca Leaves can refer to leaves of all four cultivated plants of the Coca family (Erythoxylaceae), native to western South America. In times both ancient and modern, these plants have been highly valued for their psychoactive properties, which can be experienced by chewing the leaves, making coca tea ("Mate de coca") out of it and, in modern times, chemically extracting the psychoactive agents to produce the drug Cocaine. Coca Leaves are an effective remedy against altitude sickness, and bestows upon its consumer a greater tolerance for hunger, thirst and fatigue. Apart from that, coca can be used as an anaesthetic as well, and due to its religious significance in indigenous cultures, many other properties are ascribed to it, some of which are supported by modern science.[PARAGRAPH:1] Coca Leaves have been used for medicinal, nutritional and religious purposes in the Andean region since prehistoric times, possibly as long as 8000 years before present time. It was during this long period that the ancestral coca plant was eventually domesticated, after which it diversified into the four modern species. In the Incan Empire, the plant was thought to have a divine origin, and its leaves were used as offerings, as a method of divination, similar to the reading of tea leaves in the old world, and also as preparation for prayers or religious ceremonies. It eventually spread to a large area, ranging from Colombia in the north to Chile in the south. [PARAGRAPH:2] After the Spanish conquest of the Incan Empire, the use of the leaf was tolerated by the Spanish, as it also enhanced the performance of forced laborers, but its religious use was prohibited, and the Spanish themselves were discouraged from using it. Though it was introduced in Europe in the 16th Century, it did not actually become popular until the 19th Century, when the first cocaine was produced.</Italian>
        <Spanish>[TAB]Coca Leaves can refer to leaves of all four cultivated plants of the Coca family (Erythoxylaceae), native to western South America. In times both ancient and modern, these plants have been highly valued for their psychoactive properties, which can be experienced by chewing the leaves, making coca tea ("Mate de coca") out of it and, in modern times, chemically extracting the psychoactive agents to produce the drug Cocaine. Coca Leaves are an effective remedy against altitude sickness, and bestows upon its consumer a greater tolerance for hunger, thirst and fatigue. Apart from that, coca can be used as an anaesthetic as well, and due to its religious significance in indigenous cultures, many other properties are ascribed to it, some of which are supported by modern science.[PARAGRAPH:1] Coca Leaves have been used for medicinal, nutritional and religious purposes in the Andean region since prehistoric times, possibly as long as 8000 years before present time. It was during this long period that the ancestral coca plant was eventually domesticated, after which it diversified into the four modern species. In the Incan Empire, the plant was thought to have a divine origin, and its leaves were used as offerings, as a method of divination, similar to the reading of tea leaves in the old world, and also as preparation for prayers or religious ceremonies. It eventually spread to a large area, ranging from Colombia in the north to Chile in the south. [PARAGRAPH:2] After the Spanish conquest of the Incan Empire, the use of the leaf was tolerated by the Spanish, as it also enhanced the performance of forced laborers, but its religious use was prohibited, and the Spanish themselves were discouraged from using it. Though it was introduced in Europe in the 16th Century, it did not actually become popular until the 19th Century, when the first cocaine was produced.</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_COLLECTORS_POST_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Collector's Posts[COLOR_REVERT] can be built only on hilly [LINK=TERRAIN_PLAINS]Prairie[\LINK] terrain. The [LINK=YIELD_FOOD]Food[\LINK] and [LINK=YIELD_RED_PEPPER]Red Pepper[\LINK] production on such tiles is increased.</English>
        <French>[TAB]Les piments font partie de l'alimentation des Amériques depuis au moins 9 500 ans. Des traces archéologiques de domestication ont été trouvées dans le sud-ouest de l'équateur il y a plus de 6 000 ans. Le piment semble avoir été une des premières plantes cultivées autogames en Amérique centrale et du Sud.</French>
        <German>[TAB]Eine Sammelstelle ist ein Gebäude, dass der Zwischenlagerung von Gütern für ihren Weitertransport dient.</German>
        <Italian>[TAB](dwelling) Building use for collecting holding food animals tools etc.</Italian>
        <Spanish>[TAB](dwelling) Building use for collecting holding food animals tools etc.</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_DEEP_MINE</Tag>
        <English>Large Mine</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Grande mine</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Große Mine</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Large Mine</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Large Mine</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_DEEP_MINE_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Large Mines[COLOR_REVERT] are the upgrades of [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_MINE]Mines[\LINK]. They increase the production of [LINK=YIELD_ORE]Ore[\LINK], [LINK=YIELD_RAW_SALT]Rock Salt[\LINK], [LINK=YIELD_SILVER]Silver[\LINK], [LINK=YIELD_GEMS]Gems[\LINK] and [LINK=YIELD_GOLD]Gold[\LINK].[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Background[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]A pick and shovel can start a mine. If the site is right and the wealth is there, that's good news for the owners. However the engineering challenges become complex. Workers' lives will be balanced against the need for minerals.</English>
        <French>[TAB]Une mine est un gisement exploité de matériaux (par exemple d'or, d'argent, de diamants, de fer, de sel, etc.). Elle peut être à ciel ouvert ou souterraine.</French>
        <German>[TAB]Der Begriff 'Miene' bezieht sich auf eine Abbaufläche für Metalle, Edelsteine oder Mineralien. Eine Miene kann sowohl oberirdisch, wie auch unterirdisch angelegt sein.</German>
        <Italian>[TAB]Mine or mines can refer to: Mining, extraction of mineral resources from the ground.</Italian>
        <Spanish>[TAB]Mine or mines can refer to: Mining, extraction of mineral resources from the ground.</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_FARM</Tag>
        <English>Farm</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Ferme</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Bauernhof</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Fattoria:Fattorie</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Granja:Granjas</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_FARM_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Farms[COLOR_REVERT] can be built on all flat, unvegetated [LINK=TERRAIN_GRASS]Grassland[\LINK], [LINK=TERRAIN_PLAINS]Prairie[\LINK], [LINK=TERRAIN_SAVANNAH]Savannah[\LINK] and [LINK=TERRAIN_MARSH]Marsh[\LINK] terrain. The production of [LINK=YIELD_FOOD]Food[\LINK] and [LINK=YIELD_BARLEY]Barley[\LINK] there is increased.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Background[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]A farm is an area of land, including structures, devoted producing and managing food (produce, grains, or livestock), fibres and, increasingly, fuel. It is the basic production facility in food production. Farms may be owned and operated by a single individual, family, community, corporation or a company. A farm can be a holding of any size from a fraction of a hectare to several thousand hectares.</English>
        <French>[TAB]Une ferme, ou exploitation agricole, est une entreprise (ou partie d'une entreprise) constituée en vue de la production agricole et caractérisée par une gestion unique et des moyens de production propres.</French>
        <German>[TAB]Eine Farm ist ein Stück Land, dass verschiedenste Gebäude und Anbauflächen beinhalten kann, aber primär der Produktion von Nahrung dient. Oft in Form von Getreideanbau oder Viehzucht. Der Begriff 'Farm' sagt allerdings noch nichts über die Grösse aus, die von sehr klein, bis geradezu reisig variieren kann.</German>
        <Italian>[TAB]A farm is an area of land, including various structures, devoted primarily to the practice of producing and managing food (produce, grains, or livestock), fibres and, increasingly, fuel. It is the basic production facility in food production. Farms may be owned and operated by a single individual, family, community, corporation or a company. A farm can be a holding of any size from a fraction of a hectare to several thousand hectares.</Italian>
        <Spanish>[TAB]A farm is an area of land, including various structures, devoted primarily to the practice of producing and managing food (produce, grains, or livestock), fibres and, increasingly, fuel. It is the basic production facility in food production. Farms may be owned and operated by a single individual, family, community, corporation or a company. A farm can be a holding of any size from a fraction of a hectare to several thousand hectares.</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_FORT</Tag>
        <English>Fort</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Fort</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Fort</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Fort</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Fort</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_FORT_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Forts[COLOR_REVERT] only work if a [LINK=CONCEPT_MILITARY_UNITS]Military Unit[\LINK] is stationed inside. To do this, [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Fortify[COLOR_REVERT] a military unit on the plot where the Fort is located.[NEWLINE]For more information on working Forts, see [LINK=CONCEPT_FORTS]Forts[\LINK].[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Background[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Fortifications are military constructions and buildings designed for defence in warfare and military bases. Humans have constructed defensive works for many thousands of years, using increasingly complex designs. The term is derived from the Latin fortis (strong) and facere (to make).</English>
        <French>[TAB]La fortification (du latin fortificatio « action de fortifier ») est l'art militaire de renforcer une position ou un lieu par des ouvrages de défense en prévision de leur éventuelle attaque par un ennemi hostile. Par extension, la fortification désigne ces ouvrages de défense eux-mêmes.</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Forts[COLOR_REVERT] sind nur aktiv, wenn eine [LINK=CONCEPT_MILITARY_UNITS]Militäreinheit[\LINK] darin stattioniert ist. Dafür muss diese Einheit in dem Fort [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]befestigt[COLOR_REVERT] werden.[NEWLINE]Für weitere Informationen siehe [LINK=CONCEPT_FORTS]Forts[\LINK].[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Hintergrund[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Befestigungen sind Konstruktionen mit militärischen Zweck oder dienen schlicht der Verteidigung vor Feinden. Defensive Anlagen wurden von der Menschheit schon seit tausenden von Jahren geschaffen. Der Begriff 'Fort' leitet sich vom Lateinischen Wort 'fortis' ab, welches übersetzt 'stark' bedeutet.</German>
        <Italian>[TAB]Fortifications are military constructions and buildings designed for defence in warfare and military bases. Humans have constructed defensive works for many thousands of years, in a variety of increasingly complex designs. The term is derived from the Latin fortis (strong) and facere (to make).</Italian>
        <Spanish>[TAB]Fortifications are military constructions and buildings designed for defence in warfare and military bases. Humans have constructed defensive works for many thousands of years, in a variety of increasingly complex designs. The term is derived from the Latin fortis (strong) and facere (to make).</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_GOODY_HUT</Tag>
        <English>TXT_KEY_GOODY_BURIAL_GROUNDS</English>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_GOODY_HUT2</Tag>
        <English>Ancient Ruins</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Ruines antiques</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>Antike Ruinen</German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Antiche rovine</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Ruinas antiguas</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_GOODY_HUT2_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]In [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Ancient Ruins[COLOR_REVERT] you may find treasures, useful information or even units. Beware though: the natives regard them as sacred, and they may not approve of you looting the graves of their ancestors. Only [LINK=UNIT_SCOUT]Seasoned Scouts[\LINK] are experienced enough not to invoke their ire.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Background[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Ruins are the remains of human architecture: structures once complete that have fallen into a state of disrepair. Natural disaster, war and depopulation are the most common causes, with many structures degteriorating over time from weather and scavenging.</English>
        <French>[TAB]Les ruines sont les restes d'architecture humaine passée : des structures autrefois complètes qui, par abandon, se sont désagrégés pour atteindre un état difficilement réparable. Les désastres naturels, la guerre ou le dépeuplement sont les causes principales de tels abandons. Les conditions climatiques et le pillage sont les principales causes de délabrement de ces structures.</French>
        <German>[TAB]Ruinen sind die Reste menschlicher Architektur: Strukturen, die einst vollständig waren, dann aber durch den Einfluss der Umwelt, wie Pflanzen, Regen oder Wind, über die Zeit zerfielen. Gründe für die Verwahrlosung können Kriege, Katastrophen Disasters, Krankheiten und vieles mehr gewesen sein. In diesen Ruinen können sich manchmal noch wertvolle Dinge befinden.</German>
        <Italian>[TAB]Ruins are the remains of human-made architecture: structures that were once complete, as time went by, have fallen into a state of partial or complete disrepair, due to lack of maintenance or deliberate acts of destruction. Natural disaster, war and depopulation are the most common root causes, with many structures becoming progressively derelict over time due to long-term weathering and scavenging.</Italian>
        <Spanish>[TAB]Ruins are the remains of human-made architecture: structures that were once complete, as time went by, have fallen into a state of partial or complete disrepair, due to lack of maintenance or deliberate acts of destruction. Natural disaster, war and depopulation are the most common root causes, with many structures becoming progressively derelict over time due to long-term weathering and scavenging.</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_GOODY_HUT3</Tag>
        <English>Ship Wreckage</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Epave de navire</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>Schiffsüberreste</German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Ship Wreckage</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Ship Wreckage</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_GOODY_HUT3_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[TAB][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Ship Wrecks[COLOR_REVERT] indicates that there must have been a ship nearby. Either it sank or it lost something in the storm. In any case, the flotsam may still contain valuable items. Maps or gold might be found among the wreckage.</English>
        <French>[TAB][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Ship Wrecks[COLOR_REVERT] indicates that there must have been a ship nearby. Either it sank or it lost something in the storm. In any case, the flotsam may still contain valuable items. Maps or gold might be found among the wreckage.</French>
        <German>[TAB][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Treibgut[COLOR_REVERT] zeugt davon, dass sich ganz in der Nähe ein Schiff befunden haben muss. Entweder ist es gesunken oder es hat im Sturm etwas verloren. Jedenfalls kann man in dem Treibgut vielleicht noch wertvolle Dinge finden. </German>
        <Italian>[TAB][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Ship Wrecks[COLOR_REVERT] indicates that there must have been a ship nearby. Either it sank or it lost something in the storm. In any case, the flotsam may still contain valuable items. Maps or gold might be found among the wreckage.</Italian>
        <Spanish>[TAB][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Ship Wrecks[COLOR_REVERT] indicates that there must have been a ship nearby. Either it sank or it lost something in the storm. In any case, the flotsam may still contain valuable items. Maps or gold might be found among the wreckage.</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_GOODY_HUT_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]In [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Burial Grounds[COLOR_REVERT] you can often find treasures, useful information or even units. Beware though: the natives regard them as sacred, and they may not approve of you looting the graves of their ancestors. Only [LINK=UNIT_SCOUT]Seasoned Scouts[\LINK] are experienced enough to escape their ire.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Background[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]After funeral rites native dead may be put to rest on raised platforms on a burial ground, often with their possessions to accompany them into the hereafter, thus the attraction to scouts. A cemetery is more commonly where European people are interred. In the colonies settlers rarely buried their wealth so looting those graves would be mainly for medical training, as Dickens describes in "A Tale of Two Cities".</English>
        <French>[TAB]Un cimetière est un endroit spécifiquement dédié au repos des personnes décédés. Ces dernières sont généralement enterrées ou incinérées.</French>
        <German>[TAB]Eine [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Begräbnisstätte[COLOR_REVERT] oder ein Friedhof sind Orte, an denen Verstorbene begraben werden. In manchen Kulturen war und ist es üblich den Toten reiche Grabbeigaben mitzugeben. Sie gelten in den meisten Kulturen als geheiligte Orte.</German>
        <Italian>[TAB]A burial ground or cemetery is a spatially defined area where the remains of deceased people are buried or are otherwise interred. The term "cemetery" implies that the land is specifically designated as a burial ground. The intact or cremated remains of deceased people may be interred. The remains may be interred in a grave, commonly referred to as burial, or may be interred in a tomb, an "above-ground grave" (resembling a sarcophagus), a mausoleum, columbarium, or other edifice. In Western cultures, funeral ceremonies are often observed in cemeteries. These ceremonies or rites of passage differ according to cultural practices and religious beliefs. Modern cemeteries often include crematoria, and some grounds previously used for both, continue as crematoria as a principal use long after the interment areas have been filled.</Italian>
        <Spanish>[TAB]A burial ground or cemetery is a spatially defined area where the remains of deceased people are buried or are otherwise interred. The term "cemetery" implies that the land is specifically designated as a burial ground. The intact or cremated remains of deceased people may be interred. The remains may be interred in a grave, commonly referred to as burial, or may be interred in a tomb, an "above-ground grave" (resembling a sarcophagus), a mausoleum, columbarium, or other edifice. In Western cultures, funeral ceremonies are often observed in cemeteries. These ceremonies or rites of passage differ according to cultural practices and religious beliefs. Modern cemeteries often include crematoria, and some grounds previously used for both, continue as crematoria as a principal use long after the interment areas have been filled.</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
   <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_GOODY_HUT4</Tag>
        <English>Ship Wreck</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Ship Wreck</Text>
            <Gender>Neutral</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>Schiffswrack</German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Ship Wreck</Text>
            <Gender>Neutral</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Ship Wrecke</Text>
            <Gender>Neutral</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_GOODY_HUT4_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[TAB][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Ship Wrecks[COLOR_REVERT] are scattered across the Ocean. Maps, gold and even survivors from the crew might be found among the wreckage.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Background[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]A shipwreck is what remains of a destroyed ship. Shipwrecks are either beached (on land) or sunk (at the bottom of a body of water). Whatever the cause, a sunken ship or a wrecked ship can be looted or recovered. The United Nations estimates that there are more than 3 million shipwrecks on the ocean floor.</English>
        <French>[TAB]Dans le domaine maritime, une épave est ce qui reste d'un navire en mer (épave dérivante), sur le rivage ou au fond de la mer, après qu'il a été abandonné, qu'il s'est échoué ou a coulé, à la suite d'un « événement de mer » (naufrage, avarie, collision, erreur de navigation, etc.) ou d'un sabordage. L' UNESCO évalue à 3 millions leur nombre total, mais dont à peine un millier seraient rentables économiquement.</French>
        <German>[TAB]Unter einem [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT] Schiffswrack[COLOR_REVERT] versteht man die Überreste eines verunglückten Schiffes. Manchmal kann man darin noch wertvolle Dinge finden. Ist man schnell Genug am Ort des Unglücks, gelingt es vielleicht sogar überlebenede zu retten.</German>
        <Italian>[TAB]A shipwreck is the remains of a ship that has wrecked. Shipwrecks are found either beached (on land) or sunk (at the bottom of a body of water). Whatever the cause, a sunken ship or a wrecked ship is a physical example of the event: this explains why the two concepts are often overlapping in English. The United Nations estimates that there are more than 3 million shipwrecks on the ocean floor.</Italian>
        <Spanish>[TAB]A shipwreck is the remains of a ship that has wrecked. Shipwrecks are found either beached (on land) or sunk (at the bottom of a body of water). Whatever the cause, a sunken ship or a wrecked ship is a physical example of the event: this explains why the two concepts are often overlapping in English. The United Nations estimates that there are more than 3 million shipwrecks on the ocean floor.</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
	<TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_GOODY_HUT5</Tag>
        <English>Camp Fire</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Feu de camp</Text>
            <Gender>Neutral</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>Lagerfeuer</German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Fuoco da campo</Text>
            <Gender>Neutral</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Fogata</Text>
            <Gender>Neutral</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_GOODY_HUT5_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[TAB]A [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT] Camp Fire[COLOR_REVERT] testifies to the fact that people must have stayed at night. If the fire is still warm, they may still be nearby. Are they friend or foe? In any case, it is worth looking. Maybe they are abandoned settlers who want to join us.</English>
        <French>[TAB]A [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT] Camp Fire[COLOR_REVERT] testifies to the fact that people must have stayed at night. If the fire is still warm, they may still be nearby. Are they friend or foe? In any case, it is worth looking. Maybe they are abandoned settlers who want to join us.</French>
        <German>[TAB]Ein [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Lagerfeuer[COLOR_REVERT] zeugt davon, dass sich Menschen in der Näche aufgehalten haben müssen. Ist das Feuer noch warm, sind sie vielleicht noch in der Nähe. Sind sie Freund oder Feind? Es lohnt sich auf jeden Fall nachzusehen. Vielleicht sind es zurückgelassene Siedler, die sich uns anschließen möchten.  </German>
        <Italian>[TAB]A [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT] Camp Fire[COLOR_REVERT] testifies to the fact that people must have stayed at night. If the fire is still warm, they may still be nearby. Are they friend or foe? In any case, it is worth looking. Maybe they are abandoned settlers who want to join us.</Italian>
        <Spanish>[TAB]A [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT] Camp Fire[COLOR_REVERT] testifies to the fact that people must have stayed at night. If the fire is still warm, they may still be nearby. Are they friend or foe? In any case, it is worth looking. Maybe they are abandoned settlers who want to join us.</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
	<TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LAND_WORKED</Tag>
        <English>Land Worked</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Terre travaillée</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Bearbeitetes Land</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Terreno bonificato:Terreni bonificati</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Tierra trabajada:Tierras trabajadas</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LAND_WORKED_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[TAB]Land is the part of the Earth not covered by water. Terrestrial ecoregion, an ecoregion based on soil instead of water.</English>
        <French>[TAB]La terre peut faire référence à : la partie du sol qui n'est pas couverte par l'eau. Il s'agit d'une écorégion terrestre basée sur un sol ferme et non sur de l'eau</French>
        <German>[TAB]Der Begriff 'Land' kann sich auf den Teil der Erde beziehen, der nicht von Wasser überzogen ist bzw. ein ökologisches System, dass auf Grundboden basiert anstatt auf Wasser.</German>
        <Italian>[TAB]Land may refer to: The part of the Earth that is not covered by water. Terrestrial ecoregion, an ecoregion based on soil instead of water.</Italian>
        <Spanish>[TAB]Land may refer to: The part of the Earth that is not covered by water. Terrestrial ecoregion, an ecoregion based on soil instead of water.</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LARGE_COCOA_PLANTATION</Tag>
        <English>Large Cocoa Plantation</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Grande plantation de cacao</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Große Kakaoplantage</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Large Cocoa Plantation</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Large Cocoa Plantation</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LARGE_COCOA_PLANTATION_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Large Cocoa Plantations[COLOR_REVERT] are upgrades of [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_COCOA_PLANTATION]Cocoa Plantations[\LINK]. They increase the production of [LINK=YIELD_COCOA_FRUITS]Cocoa Pods[\LINK] and [LINK=YIELD_FOOD]Food[\LINK].[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Background[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Cocoa Plantations are usually a mixture of many different kinds of trees and not a monoculture. This ensures a healthy environment for the precious fruits.</English>
        <French>[TAB]Les plantations de cacao sont généralement un mélange de plusieurs types d'arbres et non pas une monoculture. C'est ce qui assure un environnement sain pour les fruits précieux.</French>
        <German>[TAB]Kakaoplantangen sind normalerweise eine Mischung verschiedenster Bäume und Sträucher. Dies ermöglicht ein gesundes Umfeld für die wertvollen Früchte.</German>
        <Italian>[TAB]Cocoa Plantations are usually a mixture of many different kinds of trees and not a monoculture. This ensures a healthy environment for the precious fruits.</Italian>
        <Spanish>[TAB]Cocoa Plantations are usually a mixture of many different kinds of trees and not a monoculture. This ensures a healthy environment for the precious fruits.</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LARGE_FARM</Tag>
        <English>Large Farm</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Grande ferme</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Große Farm</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Large Farm</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Large Farm</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LARGE_FARM_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Large Farms[COLOR_REVERT] are the upgrades of [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_FARM]Farms[\LINK]. The production of [LINK=YIELD_FOOD]Food[\LINK] and [LINK=YIELD_BARLEY]Barley[\LINK] there is increased.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Background[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]A farm is an area of land, including structures, devoted to producing food (produce, grains, or livestock), fibres and, increasingly, fuel. It is the basic facility in food production. Farms may be owned and operated by a single individual, family, community, corporation or a company. A farm can be a holding of any size from a fraction of a hectare to several thousand hectares.</English>
        <French>[TAB]Une ferme, ou exploitation agricole, est une entreprise (ou partie d'une entreprise) constituée en vue de la production agricole et caractérisée par une gestion unique et des moyens de production propres.</French>
        <German>[TAB]Eine Farm ist ein Stück Land, dass verschiedenste Gebäude und Anbauflächen beinhalten kann, aber primär der Produktion von Nahrung dient. Oft in Form von Getreideanbau oder Viehzucht. Der Begriff 'Farm' sagt allerdings noch nichts über die Grösse aus, die von sehr klein, bis geradezu reisig variieren kann.</German>
        <Italian>[TAB]A farm is an area of land, including various structures, devoted primarily to the practice of producing and managing food (produce, grains, or livestock), fibres and, increasingly, fuel. It is the basic production facility in food production. Farms may be owned and operated by a single individual, family, community, corporation or a company. A farm can be a holding of any size from a fraction of a hectare to several thousand hectares.</Italian>
        <Spanish>[TAB]A farm is an area of land, including various structures, devoted primarily to the practice of producing and managing food (produce, grains, or livestock), fibres and, increasingly, fuel. It is the basic production facility in food production. Farms may be owned and operated by a single individual, family, community, corporation or a company. A farm can be a holding of any size from a fraction of a hectare to several thousand hectares.</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LARGE_FORT</Tag>
        <English>Large Fort</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Grand Fort</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Großes Fort</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Large Fort</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Large Fort</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LARGE_FORT_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Large Forts[COLOR_REVERT], the upgrades of [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_FORT]Forts[\LINK], only function while a [LINK=CONCEPT_MILITARY_UNITS]Military Unit[\LINK] is stationed inside. To do this, [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Fortify[COLOR_REVERT] a military unit on the plot with the Large Fort.[NEWLINE]For more information on using Large Forts, see [LINK=CONCEPT_FORTS]Forts[\LINK].[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Background[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Fortifications are military constructions for defence in warfare. People have made defensive works for many thousands of years, in increasingly complex designs. The term is derived from the Latin fortis (strong) and facere (to make).</English>
        <French>[TAB]La fortification (du latin fortificatio « action de fortifier ») est l'art militaire de renforcer une position ou un lieu par des ouvrages de défense en prévision de leur éventuelle attaque par un ennemi hostile. Par extension, la fortification désigne ces ouvrages de défense eux-mêmes.</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Grosse Forts[COLOR_REVERT], die Ausbaustufe der [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_FORT]Forts[\LINK], sind nur aktiv, wenn eine [LINK=CONCEPT_MILITARY_UNITS]Militäreinheit[\LINK] darin stattioniert ist. Dafür muss diese Einheit in dem Fort [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]befestigt[COLOR_REVERT] werden.[NEWLINE]Für weitere Informationen siehe [LINK=CONCEPT_FORTS]Forts[\LINK].[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Hintergrund[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Befestigungen sind Konstruktionen mit militärischen Zweck oder dienen schlicht der Verteidigung vor Feinden. Defensive Anlagen wurden von der Menschheit schon seit tausenden von Jahren geschaffen. Der Begriff 'Fort' leitet sich vom Lateinischen Wort 'fortis' ab, welches übersetzt 'stark' bedeutet.</German>
        <Italian>[TAB]Fortifications are military constructions and buildings designed for defence in warfare and military bases. Humans have constructed defensive works for many thousands of years, in a variety of increasingly complex designs. The term is derived from the Latin fortis (strong) and facere (to make).</Italian>
        <Spanish>[TAB]Fortifications are military constructions and buildings designed for defence in warfare and military bases. Humans have constructed defensive works for many thousands of years, in a variety of increasingly complex designs. The term is derived from the Latin fortis (strong) and facere (to make).</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LARGE_MONASTERY</Tag>
        <English>Large Monastery</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Grand Monastère</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Großes Kloster</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Large Monastery</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Large Monastery</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LARGE_MONASTERY_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]The [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Large Monastery[COLOR_REVERT] is the upgrade of the [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_MONASTERY]Monastery[\LINK].[NEWLINE]Monasteries only work when inhabited by monks. A colonist with the [LINK=PROFESSION_MISSIONARY]Missionary[\LINK] profession needs to be fortified on the plot with the Monastery. Employing [LINK=UNIT_CHRISTIAN_MISSIONARY]Jesuit Missionaries[\LINK] or [LINK=UNIT_CHRISTIAN_MISSIONARY_PROT]Evangelists[\LINK] increases the effectiveness of the Monastery.[NEWLINE]For more information on using Monasteries, see [LINK=CONCEPT_MONASTERIES]Monasteries[\LINK].[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Background[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Monastery denotes the building, or complex of buildings, comprising the domestic quarters of monastics, whether monks or nuns, and whether living in community or alone (hermits). The monastery generally includes a place reserved for prayer which may be a chapel, church or temple, and may also serve as an oratory. A monastery complex typically has buildings which include a church, dormitory, cloister, refectory, library, balneary and infirmary. Depending on the location, the monastic order and the occupation of its inhabitants, the complex may also include buildings to aid self-sufficiency and service to the community. These could include a hospice, a school, and agricultural and manufacturing buildings such as a barn, forge or brewery.</English>
        <French>[TAB]Un monastère (du grec monos, « seul ») est un ensemble de bâtiments où habite une communauté religieuse de moines ou de moniales. On parle également d'abbaye s'il est dirigé par un abbé ou de prieuré s'il est dépendant ou de moindre importance. Souvent, le prieuré est dépendant d'une abbaye ou monastère. Les monastères des ordres militaires du Moyen âge sont appelés commanderies. On parle de couvent pour les résidences de Franciscains et Dominicains, ainsi que d'autres ordres, tandis que les Bénédictins ou Prémontrés habitent des abbayes ou prieurés.</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Das [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Große Kloster[COLOR_REVERT] ist die Ausbaustufe des [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_MONASTERY]Klosters[\LINK].[NEWLINE]Ein [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Kloster[COLOR_REVERT] ist nur aktiv, wenn Mönche darin leben. Dafür muss ein Kolonist im Beruf [LINK=PROFESSION_MISSIONARY]Missionar[\LINK] im Kloster befestigt werden. Wird ein [LINK=UNIT_CHRISTIAN_MISSIONARY]Jesuiten Missionar[\LINK] ode einr [LINK=UNIT_CHRISTIAN_MISSIONARY_PROT]Evangelist[\LINK] eingesetzt, erhöht sich die Effektivität des Klosters.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE] Für weitere Informationen siehe [LINK=CONCEPT_MONASTERIES]Klöster[\LINK].[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Hintergrund[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Der Begriff 'Kloster' steht für ein Gebäude oder einen Komplex mehrerer Gebäude, welches üblicherweise von Mönchen oder Nonnen bewohnt wird. Ein Kloster beinhaltet üblicherweise Gebetsstellen, wie eine Kapelle, eine Kirche oder einen Tempel, aber auch Räume oder Gebäude für den Alltag und die Selbstversorgung, wie einen Schlafsaal, Speisesaal, Werkstellen, Scheunen, Schmieden und manchmal Brauereien. In manchen größeren Klöstern findet man auch Büchereien, Schulen oder Krankenhäuser, die dann auch oft den umliegenden Gemeinden Dienste anbieten.</German>
        <Italian>[TAB]Monastery denotes the building, or complex of buildings, comprising the domestic quarters and workplace(s) of monastics, whether monks or nuns, and whether living in community or alone (hermits). The monastery generally includes a place reserved for prayer which may be a chapel, church or temple, and may also serve as an oratory. A monastery complex typically comprises a number of buildings which include a church, dormitory, cloister, refectory, library, balneary and infirmary. Depending on the location, the monastic order and the occupation of its inhabitants, the complex may also include a wide range of buildings that facilitate self-sufficiency and service to the community. These may include a hospice, a school and a range of agricultural and manufacturing buildings such as a barn, a forge or a brewery.</Italian>
        <Spanish>[TAB]Monastery denotes the building, or complex of buildings, comprising the domestic quarters and workplace(s) of monastics, whether monks or nuns, and whether living in community or alone (hermits). The monastery generally includes a place reserved for prayer which may be a chapel, church or temple, and may also serve as an oratory. A monastery complex typically comprises a number of buildings which include a church, dormitory, cloister, refectory, library, balneary and infirmary. Depending on the location, the monastic order and the occupation of its inhabitants, the complex may also include a wide range of buildings that facilitate self-sufficiency and service to the community. These may include a hospice, a school and a range of agricultural and manufacturing buildings such as a barn, a forge or a brewery.</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LARGE_PASTURE</Tag>
        <English>Large Pasture</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Grand pâturage</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Große Ranch</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Large Pasture</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Large Pasture</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LARGE_PASTURE_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Large Pastures[COLOR_REVERT] are the upgrades of [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_PASTURE]Pastures[\LINK]. The production of [LINK=YIELD_HORSES]Horses[\LINK], [LINK=YIELD_CATTLE]Cattle[\LINK] and [LINK=YIELD_SHEEP]Sheep[\LINK] is increased on those tiles.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Background[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Pasture is land with forage for livestock either as part of a farm or in ranching on open range, or where wild animals can graze or browse. Before factory farming, pasture was where grazing animals such as cattle and horses fed. It is still used extensively, particularly in arid regions where pasture land is unsuitable for any other agricultural production. In wetter climates pasture is valued for free range and organic farming.</English>
        <French>[TAB]Le pâturage est une forme d'alimentation des animaux herbivores qui se nourrissent de plantes (telles que les graminées). Le pâturage diffère de la prédation parce que l'organisme mangé n'est généralement pas tué, et du parasitisme parce que les deux organismes n'ont pas de relation symbiotique et que le « brouteur » n'est généralement pas limité dans le choix des espèces qu'il peut consommer (voir espèces généraliste et spécialisée).</French>
        <German>[TAB]Als 'Weideland' bezeichnet man Flächen mit Vegetation, die der Viehzucht dienen. Oft gehören diese Flächen zu einer Farm oder einer Ranch. In vielen Fällen dient dazu Land, dass ansonsten für den Anbau von Nutzpflanzen nicht geeignet ist.</German>
        <Italian>[TAB]Pasture is land with vegetation cover used for grazing of livestock as part of a farm, or in ranching or other unenclosed pastoral systems or used by wild animals for grazing or browsing. Prior to the advent of factory farming, pasture was the primary source of food for grazing animals such as cattle and horses. It is still used extensively, particularly in arid regions where pasture land is unsuitable for any other agricultural production. In more humid regions, pasture grazing is exploited extensively for free range and organic farming.</Italian>
        <Spanish>[TAB]Pasture is land with vegetation cover used for grazing of livestock as part of a farm, or in ranching or other unenclosed pastoral systems or used by wild animals for grazing or browsing. Prior to the advent of factory farming, pasture was the primary source of food for grazing animals such as cattle and horses. It is still used extensively, particularly in arid regions where pasture land is unsuitable for any other agricultural production. In more humid regions, pasture grazing is exploited extensively for free range and organic farming.</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LARGE_PLANTATION</Tag>
        <English>Large Plantation</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Grande plantation</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Große Plantage</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Large Plantation</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Large Plantation</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LARGE_PLANTATION_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Large Plantations[COLOR_REVERT] are upgraded versions of the [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_PLANTATION]Plantation[\LINK]. The production of any raw materials other than [LINK=CONCEPT_CATTLE_OR_SHEEP_BREEDING]Livestock[\LINK], [LINK=YIELD_FOOD]Food[\LINK] or [LINK=YIELD_BARLEY]Barley[\LINK] there is increased.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Background[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]A plantation is a large artificially established forest, farm or estate, where crops are grown for sale, intended for distant markets rather than local consumption.</English>
        <French>[TAB]Une plantation est une exploitation agricole en monoculture de cultures à forte valeur économique destinées à la vente vers des marchés internationaux. La plantation est souvent associée à certaines cultures tels le coton, la canne à sucre, le tabac, le café, la banane, le cacao ou le chanvre.</French>
        <German>[TAB]Eine Plantage ist üblicherweise ein grösseres Anbaugebiet von Pflanzen für den Verkauf oder deren Weiterverarbeitung.</German>
        <Italian>[TAB]A plantation is a large artificially established forest, farm or estate, where crops are grown for sale, often in distant markets rather than for local on-site consumption. The term plantation is informal and not precisely defined.</Italian>
        <Spanish>[TAB]A plantation is a large artificially established forest, farm or estate, where crops are grown for sale, often in distant markets rather than for local on-site consumption. The term plantation is informal and not precisely defined.</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LARGE_QUARRY</Tag>
        <English>Large Quarry</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Grande carrière</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Großer Steinbruch</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Large Quarry</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Large Quarry</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LARGE_QUARRY_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Large Quarries[COLOR_REVERT] are the upgrades of [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_QUARRY]Quarries[\LINK]. They increase the production of [LINK=YIELD_STONE]Stone[\LINK].[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Background[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]A quarry is an open-pit mine from which rock is extracted. Quarries are generally used for building materials such as dimension stone, construction aggregate, riprap, sand and gravel. They are often co-located with concrete and asphalt plants since large amounts of aggregate are used in those materials. The word "quarry" can include underground quarrying for stone, such as Bath stone.</English>
        <French>[TAB]Une carrière est un endroit d'où sont extraits des matériaux de construction à partir de roche. Le chantier se fait à ciel ouvert, soit « à flanc de coteau », soit « en fosse » (jusqu'à une centaine de mètres de profondeur parfois). Les carrières exploitent des roches meubles (éboulis, alluvionnaires) ou massives (roches consolidées sédimentaire (calcaires et grès), éruptive ou métamorphique (granites, porphyres, gneiss, amphibolites, quartzites, schistes, basaltes.).</French>
        <German>[TAB]Ein Steinbruch ist meist eine grubenähnliche Anlage, die dazu dient Fels oder Mineralien abzubauen. In vielen Fällen dient dieses Gestein als Baumaterial.</German>
        <Italian>[TAB]A quarry is a type of open-pit mine from which rock or minerals are extracted. Quarries are generally used for extracting building materials, such as dimension stone, construction aggregate, riprap, sand, and gravel. They are often colocated with concrete and asphalt plants due to the requirement for large amounts of aggregate in those materials. The word quarry can include underground quarrying for stone, such as Bath stone.</Italian>
        <Spanish>[TAB]A quarry is a type of open-pit mine from which rock or minerals are extracted. Quarries are generally used for extracting building materials, such as dimension stone, construction aggregate, riprap, sand, and gravel. They are often colocated with concrete and asphalt plants due to the requirement for large amounts of aggregate in those materials. The word quarry can include underground quarrying for stone, such as Bath stone.</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LARGE_VINEYARD</Tag>
        <English>Mature Vineyard</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Vigne mature</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Alter Weinberg</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Mature Vineyard</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Mature Vineyard</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LARGE_VINEYARD_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Mature Vineyards[COLOR_REVERT] are the upgrades of [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_VINEYARD]Vineyards[\LINK]. The production of [LINK=YIELD_FOOD]Food[\LINK] and [LINK=YIELD_GRAPES]Grapes[\LINK] is increased by the Mature Vineyard.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Background[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Wine, a beverage from fermented grapes, was first produced as early as 6000 BC. Its use spread throughout the Middle East and Egypt, and it quickly became a popular beverage of the ancient world. The grapes used for the making of wine are grown in many different regions of the world. Most vineyards are located in hills and valleys of temperate regions. Wine making as an industry has been perfected over several centuries. Many regions such as the Rhine and Loire valleys of Europe are well-known for their fine wines, and derive a significant portion of their economy from wine making.</English>
        <French>[TAB]Le vin est une boisson obtenue par la fermentation du raisin. Sa production débute dès 6 000 ans av. J.-C. Sa consommation se répand à travers tout le Moyen-Orient et l'Egypte, et il devient rapidement une boisson très populaire dans le monde antique. Le raisin utilisé dans la fabrication du vin est cultivé dans de nombreuses régions du monde. Les vignes sont généralement situées sur les coteaux et dans les vallées des régions tempérées. Les procédés de fabrication du vin ont été perfectionnés au cours des siècles. De nombreuses régions, comme les vallées du Rhin et de la Loire, sont réputées pour leurs bons vins, et une grande partie de leur économie est liée à la fabrication du vin.</French>
        <German>[TAB]Der aus fermentierten Trauben hergestellte Wein wurde erstmals um 6000 vor Christus produziert und war im Nahen Osten und in Ägypten weit verbreitet. Das Getränk entwickelte sich schnell zu einem der beliebtesten kulinarischen Genüsse der Antike. Die für die Weinherstellung benötigten Trauben werden in vielen verschiedenen Gebieten der Welt angebaut, die meisten Weinhänge befinden sich jedoch in den Hügeln und Tälern von Regionen mit gemäßigtem Klima. Im Laufe mehrerer Jahrhunderte wurde die industrielle Weinherstellung immer weiter perfektioniert. Viele Anbaugebiete wie die Rhein- und Loiretäler in Europa sind für ihre feinen Weine bekannt und beziehen einen Großteil ihrer wirtschaftlichen Erträge aus der Weinproduktion.</German>
        <Italian>[TAB]Realizzato dalla fermentazione dell'uva, il primo vino risale circa al 6000 a. C. e si diffuse rapirdamente attraverso il Medio Oriente e l'Egitto, diventando una delle bevande più popolari del mondo antico. Le qualità d'uva usate per la realizzazione del vino crescono in differenti zone del mondo; la maggior parte delle vigne si possono trovare sulle colline e nelle vallate di regioni dal clima temperato. L'industria del vino è andata perfezionandosi nel corso dei secoli: molte regioni europee, come le vallate del Reno e della Loira, sono rinomate per la produzione di ottimi vini, principale forma di economia della zona.</Italian>
        <Spanish>[TAB]El vino, una bebida preparada a partir de uvas fermentadas, se elaboró por vez primera ya en el 6000 a. C. Su consumo se extendió rápidamente por Oriente Medio y Egipto, y pronto se convirtió en una popular bebida en el mundo antiguo. Las uvas empleadas en la fabricación del vino crecen en muchas y muy distintas partes del mundo. La mayoría de las viñas están en colinas y valles de regiones templadas. La vinicultura se ha perfeccionado como industria a lo largo de varios siglos. Muchas regiones, como los valles del Rin y del Loira en Europa, son conocidas por sus grandes vinos y obtienen una parte significativa de sus ingresos de la vinicultura.</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LODGE</Tag>
        <English>Lodge</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Abri:Abris</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>Holzfällerhütte</German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Capanno</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Pabellón:Pabellones</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LODGE_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Lodges[COLOR_REVERT] can be built in [LINK=FEATURE_FOREST]Forests[\LINK], [LINK=FEATURE_LIGHT_FOREST]Light Forests[\LINK], [LINK=FEATURE_FOREST_TUNDRA]Taiga[\LINK] and [LINK=FEATURE_JUNGLE]Jungle[\LINK]. The production of [LINK=YIELD_LUMBER]Lumber[\LINK] and [LINK=YIELD_VALUABLE_WOOD]Valuable Wood[\LINK] there is increased.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Background[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]At first a lodge will be a small, makeshift shelter of boughs, poles, skins, earth or rough boards; but over time it can become permanent, even luxurious.</English>
        <French>[TAB]Un abri est un logement temporaire dont a besoin pour répondre aux besoins naturels de sécurité, d'hygiène et de confort. Il peut prendre la forme d'une cabine ou d'une hutte.</French>
        <German>[TAB]Ein kleines Gebäude, eine kleine Hütte oder ein behelfsmässiger Unterschlupf.</German>
        <Italian>[TAB]A small, makeshift or crude shelter or habitation, as of boughs, poles, skins, earth, or rough boards; cabin or hut.</Italian>
        <Spanish>[TAB]A small, makeshift or crude shelter or habitation, as of boughs, poles, skins, earth, or rough boards; cabin or hut.</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LUMBERJACK_CAMP</Tag>
        <English>Lumberjack Camp</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Camp de bûcherons</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Holzfäller Camp</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Lumberjack Camp</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Lumberjack Camp</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LUMBERJACK_CAMP_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Lumberjack Camps[COLOR_REVERT] are the upgrades of [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_LODGE]Lodges[\LINK], that can be built in [LINK=FEATURE_FOREST]Forests[\LINK], [LINK=FEATURE_LIGHT_FOREST]Light Forests[\LINK], [LINK=FEATURE_FOREST_TUNDRA]Taiga[\LINK] and [LINK=FEATURE_JUNGLE]Jungle[\LINK]. The production of [LINK=YIELD_LUMBER]Lumber[\LINK] and [LINK=YIELD_VALUABLE_WOOD]Valuable Wood[\LINK] there is increased.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Background[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]At first a lodge will be a small, makeshift shelter of boughs, poles, skins, earth or rough boards; but a lumberjack camp is industrial and efficient. Lumberjacks are known for their music and cameraderie at the end of a hard day's work.</English>
        <French>[TAB]Un abri est un logement temporaire dont a besoin pour répondre aux besoins naturels de sécurité, d'hygiène et de confort. Il peut prendre la forme d'une cabine ou d'une hutte.</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategy[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Holzfäller Camps[COLOR_REVERT] sind die höhere Stufe einer [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_LODGE]Holzfällerhütte[\LINK]. Diese können in [LINK=FEATURE_FOREST]Wäldern[\LINK], [LINK=FEATURE_LIGHT_FOREST]Buschland[\LINK], [LINK=FEATURE_FOREST_TUNDRA]Taiga[\LINK] und [LINK=FEATURE_JUNGLE]Dschungel[\LINK] errichtet werden. Die Produktion von [LINK=YIELD_LUMBER]Holz[\LINK] und [LINK=YIELD_VALUABLE_WOOD]Edelholz[\LINK] erhöht sich deutlich.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]</German>
        <Italian>[TAB]A small, makeshift or crude shelter or habitation, as of boughs, poles, skins, earth, or rough boards; cabin or hut.</Italian>
        <Spanish>[TAB]A small, makeshift or crude shelter or habitation, as of boughs, poles, skins, earth, or rough boards; cabin or hut.</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LUMBERMILL</Tag>
        <English>Sawmill</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Sawmill</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Sägemühle</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Sawmill</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Sawmill</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LUMBERMILL_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Sawmills[COLOR_REVERT] are [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]upgrades[COLOR_REVERT] of [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_LUMBERJACK_CAMP]Lumberjack Camps[\LINK]. They can not be directly built in [LINK=FEATURE_FOREST]Forests[\LINK], [LINK=FEATURE_LIGHT_FOREST]Light Forests[\LINK], [LINK=FEATURE_FOREST_TUNDRA]Taiga[\LINK] and [LINK=FEATURE_JUNGLE]Jungle[\LINK] but develop over time through work. The production of [LINK=YIELD_LUMBER]Lumber[\LINK] and [LINK=YIELD_VALUABLE_WOOD]Valuable Wood[\LINK] is increased even more than by the Lodge or Lumberjack Camp.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]</English>
        <French>[BOLD]Strategy[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Sawmills[COLOR_REVERT] are [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]upgrades[COLOR_REVERT] of [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_LUMBERJACK_CAMP]Lumberjack Camps[\LINK]. They can not be directly built in [LINK=FEATURE_FOREST]Forests[\LINK], [LINK=FEATURE_LIGHT_FOREST]Light Forests[\LINK], [LINK=FEATURE_FOREST_TUNDRA]Taiga[\LINK] and [LINK=FEATURE_JUNGLE]Jungle[\LINK] but grow over time  by working them. The production of [LINK=YIELD_LUMBER]Lumber[\LINK] and [LINK=YIELD_VALUABLE_WOOD]Valuable Wood[\LINK] there is more increased as if a Lodge or Lumberjack Camp is built.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategy[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Sägemühlen[COLOR_REVERT] sind [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Upgrade[COLOR_REVERT] eines [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_LUMBERJACK_CAMP]Holzfäller Camps[\LINK]. Sägemühlen können nicht direkt in [LINK=FEATURE_FOREST]Wäldern[\LINK], [LINK=FEATURE_LIGHT_FOREST]Buschland[\LINK], [LINK=FEATURE_FOREST_TUNDRA]Taiga[\LINK] und [LINK=FEATURE_JUNGLE]Dschungel[\LINK] errichtet werden, sondern entsehen durch längere Nutzung. Die Produktion von [LINK=YIELD_LUMBER]Holz[\LINK] und [LINK=YIELD_VALUABLE_WOOD]Edelholz[\LINK] erhöht sich gegenüber einer Holzfällerhütte oder einem Holzfällercamp deutlich.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]</German>
        <Italian>[BOLD]Strategy[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Sawmills[COLOR_REVERT] are [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]upgrades[COLOR_REVERT] of [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_LUMBERJACK_CAMP]Lumberjack Camps[\LINK]. They can not be directly built in [LINK=FEATURE_FOREST]Forests[\LINK], [LINK=FEATURE_LIGHT_FOREST]Light Forests[\LINK], [LINK=FEATURE_FOREST_TUNDRA]Taiga[\LINK] and [LINK=FEATURE_JUNGLE]Jungle[\LINK] but grow over time  by working them. The production of [LINK=YIELD_LUMBER]Lumber[\LINK] and [LINK=YIELD_VALUABLE_WOOD]Valuable Wood[\LINK] there is more increased as if a Lodge or Lumberjack Camp is built.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]</Italian>
        <Spanish>[BOLD]Strategy[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Sawmills[COLOR_REVERT] are [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT][COLOR_REVERT] of [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_LUMBERJACK_CAMP]Lumberjack Camps[\LINK]. They can not be directly built in [LINK=FEATURE_FOREST]Forests[\LINK], [LINK=FEATURE_LIGHT_FOREST]Light Forests[\LINK], [LINK=FEATURE_FOREST_TUNDRA]Taiga[\LINK] and [LINK=FEATURE_JUNGLE]Jungle[\LINK] but grow over time by working them. The production of [LINK=YIELD_LUMBER]Lumber[\LINK] and [LINK=YIELD_VALUABLE_WOOD]Valuable Wood[\LINK] there is more increased as if a Lodge or Lumberjack Camp is built.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_MINE</Tag>
        <English>Mine</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Mine</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Mine</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Miniera:Miniere</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Mina:Minas</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_MINE_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Mines[COLOR_REVERT] can be built on all unvegetated Hills and Peaks, as well as on [LINK=TERRAIN_DESERT]Desert[\LINK] terrain. Mines increase the production of [LINK=YIELD_ORE]Ore[\LINK], [LINK=YIELD_RAW_SALT]Rock Salt[\LINK], [LINK=YIELD_SILVER]Silver[\LINK], [LINK=YIELD_GEMS]Gems[\LINK] and [LINK=YIELD_GOLD]Gold[\LINK].[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Background[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]A pick and shovel can start a mine. If the site is right and the wealth is there, that's good news for the owners. However the engineering challenges become complex. Workers' lives will be balanced against the need for minerals.</English>
        <French>[TAB]Une mine est un gisement exploité de matériaux (par exemple d'or, d'argent, de diamants, de fer, de sel, etc.). Elle peut être à ciel ouvert ou souterraine.</French>
        <German>[TAB]Der Begriff 'Miene' bezieht sich auf eine Abbaufläche für Metalle, Edelsteine oder Mineralien. Eine Miene kann sowohl oberirdisch, wie auch unterirdisch angelegt sein.</German>
        <Italian>[TAB]Mine or mines can refer to: Mining, extraction of mineral resources from the ground.</Italian>
        <Spanish>[TAB]Mine or mines can refer to: Mining, extraction of mineral resources from the ground.</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_MONASTERY</Tag>
        <English>Monastery</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Monastère</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Kloster</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Monastery</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Monastery</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_MONASTERY_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Monasteries[COLOR_REVERT] only function when inhabited by monks. A colonist with the [LINK=PROFESSION_MISSIONARY]Missionary[\LINK] profession needs to be fortified in the Monastery. Employing [LINK=UNIT_CHRISTIAN_MISSIONARY]Jesuit Missionaries[\LINK] or [LINK=UNIT_CHRISTIAN_MISSIONARY_PROT]Evangelists[\LINK] increases the effectiveness of the Monastery.[NEWLINE]For more information on working Monasteries, see [LINK=CONCEPT_MONASTERIES]Monasteries[\LINK].[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Background[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Monastery denotes the building, or complex of buildings, comprising the domestic quarters and workplace(s) of monastics, whether monks or nuns, and whether living in community or alone (hermits). The monastery generally includes a place reserved for prayer which may be a chapel, church or temple, and may also serve as an oratory. A monastery complex can include a church, dormitory, cloister, refectory, library, balneary and infirmary. Depending on the location, the monastic order and the occupation of its inhabitants, the complex may also have buildings to aid self-sufficiency and community service. These may include a hospice, a school, and agricultural and manufacturing buildings such as a barn, a forge or a brewery.</English>
        <French>[TAB]Un monastère (du grec monos, « seul ») est un ensemble de bâtiments où habite une communauté religieuse de moines ou de moniales. On parle également d'abbaye s'il est dirigé par un abbé ou de prieuré s'il est dépendant ou de moindre importance. Souvent, le prieuré est dépendant d'une abbaye ou monastère. Les monastères des ordres militaires du Moyen âge sont appelés commanderies. On parle de couvent pour les résidences de Franciscains et Dominicains, ainsi que d'autres ordres, tandis que les Bénédictins ou Prémontrés habitent des abbayes ou prieurés.</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Ein [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Kloster[COLOR_REVERT] ist nur aktiv, wenn Mönche darin leben. Dafür muss ein Kolonist im Beruf [LINK=PROFESSION_MISSIONARY]Missionar[\LINK] im Kloster befestigt werden. Wird ein [LINK=UNIT_CHRISTIAN_MISSIONARY]Jesuiten Missionar[\LINK] ode einr [LINK=UNIT_CHRISTIAN_MISSIONARY_PROT]Evangelist[\LINK] eingesetzt, erhöht sich die Effektivität des Klosters.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE] Für weitere Informationen siehe [LINK=CONCEPT_MONASTERIES]Klöster[\LINK].[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Hintergrund[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Der Begriff 'Kloster' steht für ein Gebäude oder einen Komplex mehrerer Gebäude, welches üblicherweise von Mönchen oder Nonnen bewohnt wird. Ein Kloster beinhaltet üblicherweise Gebetsstellen, wie eine Kapelle, eine Kirche oder einen Tempel, aber auch Räume oder Gebäude für den Alltag und die Selbstversorgung, wie einen Schlafsaal, Speisesaal, Werkstellen, Scheunen, Schmieden und manchmal Brauereien. In manchen größeren Klöstern findet man auch Büchereien, Schulen oder Krankenhäuser, die dann auch oft den umliegenden Gemeinden Dienste anbieten.</German>
        <Italian>[TAB]Monastery denotes the building, or complex of buildings, comprising the domestic quarters and workplace(s) of monastics, whether monks or nuns, and whether living in community or alone (hermits). The monastery generally includes a place reserved for prayer which may be a chapel, church or temple, and may also serve as an oratory. A monastery complex typically comprises a number of buildings which include a church, dormitory, cloister, refectory, library, balneary and infirmary. Depending on the location, the monastic order and the occupation of its inhabitants, the complex may also include a wide range of buildings that facilitate self-sufficiency and service to the community. These may include a hospice, a school and a range of agricultural and manufacturing buildings such as a barn, a forge or a brewery.</Italian>
        <Spanish>[TAB]Monastery denotes the building, or complex of buildings, comprising the domestic quarters and workplace(s) of monastics, whether monks or nuns, and whether living in community or alone (hermits). The monastery generally includes a place reserved for prayer which may be a chapel, church or temple, and may also serve as an oratory. A monastery complex typically comprises a number of buildings which include a church, dormitory, cloister, refectory, library, balneary and infirmary. Depending on the location, the monastic order and the occupation of its inhabitants, the complex may also include a wide range of buildings that facilitate self-sufficiency and service to the community. These may include a hospice, a school and a range of agricultural and manufacturing buildings such as a barn, a forge or a brewery.</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_PASTURE</Tag>
        <English>Pasture</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Pâturage</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Ranch</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Pasture</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Pasture</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_PASTURE_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Pastures[COLOR_REVERT] can be built on unvegetated terrain that is either flat or hilly, and where [LINK=CONCEPT_CATTLE_OR_SHEEP_BREEDING]Livestock[\LINK] can be bred. The production of [LINK=YIELD_HORSES]Horses[\LINK], [LINK=YIELD_CATTLE]Cattle[\LINK] and [LINK=YIELD_SHEEP]Sheep[\LINK] is increased on those tiles.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Background[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Pasture is land with forage for livestock either as part of a farm or in ranching on open range, or where wild animals can graze or browse. Before factory farming, pasture was where grazing animals such as cattle and horses fed. It is still used extensively, particularly in arid regions where pasture land is unsuitable for any other agricultural production. In wetter climates pasture is valued for free range and organic farming.</English>
        <French>[TAB]Le pâturage est une forme d'alimentation des animaux herbivores qui se nourrissent de plantes (telles que les graminées). Le pâturage diffère de la prédation parce que l'organisme mangé n'est généralement pas tué, et du parasitisme parce que les deux organismes n'ont pas de relation symbiotique et que le « brouteur » n'est généralement pas limité dans le choix des espèces qu'il peut consommer (voir espèces généraliste et spécialisée).</French>
        <German>[TAB]Als 'Weideland' bezeichnet man Flächen mit Vegetation, die der Viehzucht dienen. Oft gehören diese Flächen zu einer Farm oder einer Ranch. In vielen Fällen dient dazu Land, dass ansonsten für den Anbau von Nutzpflanzen nicht geeignet ist.</German>
        <Italian>[TAB]Pasture is land with vegetation cover used for grazing of livestock as part of a farm, or in ranching or other unenclosed pastoral systems or used by wild animals for grazing or browsing. Prior to the advent of factory farming, pasture was the primary source of food for grazing animals such as cattle and horses. It is still used extensively, particularly in arid regions where pasture land is unsuitable for any other agricultural production. In more humid regions, pasture grazing is exploited extensively for free range and organic farming.</Italian>
        <Spanish>[TAB]Pasture is land with vegetation cover used for grazing of livestock as part of a farm, or in ranching or other unenclosed pastoral systems or used by wild animals for grazing or browsing. Prior to the advent of factory farming, pasture was the primary source of food for grazing animals such as cattle and horses. It is still used extensively, particularly in arid regions where pasture land is unsuitable for any other agricultural production. In more humid regions, pasture grazing is exploited extensively for free range and organic farming.</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_PLANTATION</Tag>
        <English>Plantation</English>
        <French>Plantation</French>
        <German>
            <Text>Plantage</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>Piantagione</Italian>
        <Spanish>Plantacion</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_PLANTATION_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Plantations[COLOR_REVERT] can be built on all flat [LINK=TERRAIN_GRASS]Grassland[\LINK], [LINK=TERRAIN_PLAINS]Prairie[\LINK], [LINK=TERRAIN_SAVANNAH]Savannah[\LINK] and [LINK=TERRAIN_MARSH]Marsh[\LINK] terrain. The production of raw materials other than [LINK=CONCEPT_CATTLE_OR_SHEEP_BREEDING]Livestock[\LINK], [LINK=YIELD_FOOD]Food[\LINK] or [LINK=YIELD_BARLEY]Barley[\LINK] there is increased.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Background[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]A plantation is a large artificially established forest, farm or estate, where crops are grown for sale, intended for distant markets rather than local consumption.</English>
        <French>[TAB]Une plantation est une exploitation agricole en monoculture de cultures à forte valeur économique destinées à la vente vers des marchés internationaux. La plantation est souvent associée à certaines cultures tels le coton, la canne à sucre, le tabac, le café, la banane, le cacao ou le chanvre.</French>
        <German>[TAB]Eine Plantage ist üblicherweise ein grösseres Anbaugebiet von Pflanzen für den Verkauf oder deren Weiterverarbeitung.</German>
        <Italian>[TAB]A plantation is a large artificially established forest, farm or estate, where crops are grown for sale, often in distant markets rather than for local on-site consumption. The term plantation is informal and not precisely defined.</Italian>
        <Spanish>[TAB]A plantation is a large artificially established forest, farm or estate, where crops are grown for sale, often in distant markets rather than for local on-site consumption. The term plantation is informal and not precisely defined.</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_QUARRY</Tag>
        <English>Quarry</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Carrière</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Steinbruch</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Quarry</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Quarry</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_QUARRY_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Quarries[COLOR_REVERT] can be built only on Peaks. They increase the production of [LINK=YIELD_STONE]Stone[\LINK].[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Background[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]A quarry is an open-pit mine from which rock is extracted. Quarries are generally used for building materials such as dimension stone, construction aggregate, riprap, sand and gravel. They are often co-located with concrete and asphalt plants since large amounts of aggregate are used in those materials. The word "quarry" can include underground quarrying for stone, such as Bath stone.</English>
        <French>[TAB]Une carrière est un endroit d'où sont extraits des matériaux de construction à partir de roche. Le chantier se fait à ciel ouvert, soit « à flanc de coteau », soit « en fosse » (jusqu'à une centaine de mètres de profondeur parfois). Les carrières exploitent des roches meubles (éboulis, alluvionnaires) ou massives (roches consolidées sédimentaire (calcaires et grès), éruptive ou métamorphique (granites, porphyres, gneiss, amphibolites, quartzites, schistes, basaltes.).</French>
        <German>[TAB]Ein Steinbruch ist meist eine grubenähnliche Anlage, die dazu dient Fels oder Mineralien abzubauen. In vielen Fällen dient dieses Gestein als Baumaterial.</German>
        <Italian>[TAB]A quarry is a type of open-pit mine from which rock or minerals are extracted. Quarries are generally used for extracting building materials, such as dimension stone, construction aggregate, riprap, sand, and gravel. They are often colocated with concrete and asphalt plants due to the requirement for large amounts of aggregate in those materials. The word quarry can include underground quarrying for stone, such as Bath stone.</Italian>
        <Spanish>[TAB]A quarry is a type of open-pit mine from which rock or minerals are extracted. Quarries are generally used for extracting building materials, such as dimension stone, construction aggregate, riprap, sand, and gravel. They are often colocated with concrete and asphalt plants due to the requirement for large amounts of aggregate in those materials. The word quarry can include underground quarrying for stone, such as Bath stone.</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_TRAPPER_CAMP</Tag>
        <English>Trapper Camp</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Camp de trappeurs</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Trapper Camp</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Trapper Camp</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Trapper Camp</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_TRAPPER_CAMP_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Trapper Camps[COLOR_REVERT] are the upgrades of [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_TRAPPER_HUT]Trapper huts[\LINK]. They boost the production of [LINK=YIELD_FUR]Fur[\LINK] and [LINK=YIELD_PREMIUM_FUR]Premium Fur[\LINK].[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Background[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Hunting wild animals like Deer and Beaver is a lonely job far from civilization and cities. During the trapping season hunters and trappers lived in their trappers' huts, leaving only to sell their furs.</English>
        <French>[TAB]Chasser et trapper les animaux sauvages comme les cerfs ou les visons a été pendant longtemp un travail solitaire loin de la civilization et des grandes villes. Pendant les mois de chasse, les chasseurs et trappeurs vivaient dans des huttes qu'ils ne quittaient que pour vendre leurs fourrures.</French>
        <German>[TAB]Die Jagd auf Rehe, Biber und andere Tiere fand meist weit abseits der Städte statt. Während der Jagdsaison lebten die Jäger und Trapper oft monatelang in einsamen Jagdhütten und verliessen diese nur zum Verkauf ihrer Waren in den Städten.</German>
        <Italian>[TAB]Hunting and Trapping wild animals like Deers and Beavers used to be a very lonely job far away from civlization and people in the cities. During the months of the hunting seasons the hunters and trappers lived in their trappers huts and left usually left those only for selling their furs.</Italian>
        <Spanish>[TAB]Hunting and Trapping wild animals like Deers and Beavers used to be a very lonely job far away from civlization and people in the cities. During the months of the hunting seasons the hunters and trappers lived in their trappers huts and left usually left those only for selling their furs.</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_TRAPPER_HUT</Tag>
        <English>Trapperhut</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Hutte du trappeur</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Jagdhütte</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Trapperhut</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Trapperhut</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_TRAPPER_HUT_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Trapper huts[COLOR_REVERT] can be built in [LINK=FEATURE_FOREST]Forests[\LINK], [LINK=FEATURE_LIGHT_FOREST]Light Forests[\LINK] and [LINK=FEATURE_FOREST_TUNDRA]Taiga[\LINK], on [LINK=TERRAIN_TUNDRA]Tundra[\LINK] and [LINK=TERRAIN_SNOW]Permafrost[\LINK] terrain, as well as tiles with the [LINK=BONUS_BISON]Bisons[\LINK] bonus. They boost the production of [LINK=YIELD_FUR]Fur[\LINK] and [LINK=YIELD_PREMIUM_FUR]Premium Fur[\LINK].[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Background[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Hunting wild animals like Deer and Beaver is a lonely job far from civilization and cities. During the trapping season hunters and trappers lived in their trappers' huts, leaving only to sell their furs.</English>
        <French>[TAB]Chasser et trapper les animaux sauvages comme les cerfs ou les visons a été pendant longtemp un travail solitaire loin de la civilization et des grandes villes. Pendant les mois de chasse, les chasseurs et trappeurs vivaient dans des huttes qu'ils ne quittaient que pour vendre leurs fourrures.</French>
        <German>[TAB]Die Jagd auf Rehe, Biber und andere Tiere fand meist weit abseits der Städte statt. Während der Jagdsaison lebten die Jäger und Trapper oft monatelang in einsamen Jagdhütten und verliessen diese nur zum Verkauf ihrer Waren in den Städten.</German>
        <Italian>[TAB]Hunting and Trapping wild animals like Deers and Beavers used to be a very lonely job far away from civlization and people in the cities. During the months of the hunting seasons the hunters and trappers lived in their trappers huts and left usually left those only for selling their furs.</Italian>
        <Spanish>[TAB]Hunting and Trapping wild animals like Deers and Beavers used to be a very lonely job far away from civlization and people in the cities. During the months of the hunting seasons the hunters and trappers lived in their trappers huts and left usually left those only for selling their furs.</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_VINEYARD</Tag>
        <English>Vineyard</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Vigne</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Weinberg</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Vineyard:Vineyards</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Vineyard:Vineyards</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_VINEYARD_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Vineyards[COLOR_REVERT] can be built only on hilly [LINK=TERRAIN_GRASS]Grass[\LINK] terrain. The production of [LINK=YIELD_FOOD]Food[\LINK] and [LINK=YIELD_GRAPES]Grapes[\LINK] is increased by the Vineyard.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][BOLD]Background[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Wine, a beverage made from fermented grapes, was first produced as early as 6000 BC. Its use spread throughout the Middle East and Egypt, and it quickly became a popular beverage of the ancient world. The grapes used for wine making are grown in many different regions of the world. Most vinyards are located in the hills and valleys of temperate regions. Wine making as an industry has been perfected over several centuries. Many regions such as the Rhine and Loire valleys of Europe are well-known for their fine wines, and derive a significant portion of their economy from wine making.</English>
        <French>[TAB]Le vin est une boisson obtenue par la fermentation du raisin. Sa production débute dès 6 000 ans av. J.-C. Sa consommation se répand à travers tout le Moyen-Orient et l'Egypte, et il devient rapidement une boisson très populaire dans le monde antique. Le raisin utilisé dans la fabrication du vin est cultivé dans de nombreuses régions du monde. Les vignes sont généralement situées sur les coteaux et dans les vallées des régions tempérées. Les procédés de fabrication du vin ont été perfectionnés au cours des siècles. De nombreuses régions, comme les vallées du Rhin et de la Loire, sont réputées pour leurs bons vins, et une grande partie de leur économie est liée à la fabrication du vin.</French>
        <German>[TAB]Der aus fermentierten Trauben hergestellte Wein wurde erstmals um 6000 vor Christus produziert und war im Nahen Osten und in Ägypten weit verbreitet. Das Getränk entwickelte sich schnell zu einem der beliebtesten kulinarischen Genüsse der Antike. Die für die Weinherstellung benötigten Trauben werden in vielen verschiedenen Gebieten der Welt angebaut, die meisten Weinhänge befinden sich jedoch in den Hügeln und Tälern von Regionen mit gemäßigtem Klima. Im Laufe mehrerer Jahrhunderte wurde die industrielle Weinherstellung immer weiter perfektioniert. Viele Anbaugebiete wie die Rhein- und Loiretäler in Europa sind für ihre feinen Weine bekannt und beziehen einen Großteil ihrer wirtschaftlichen Erträge aus der Weinproduktion.</German>
        <Italian>[TAB]Realizzato dalla fermentazione dell'uva, il primo vino risale circa al 6000 a. C. e si diffuse rapirdamente attraverso il Medio Oriente e l'Egitto, diventando una delle bevande più popolari del mondo antico. Le qualità d'uva usate per la realizzazione del vino crescono in differenti zone del mondo; la maggior parte delle vigne si possono trovare sulle colline e nelle vallate di regioni dal clima temperato. L'industria del vino è andata perfezionandosi nel corso dei secoli: molte regioni europee, come le vallate del Reno e della Loira, sono rinomate per la produzione di ottimi vini, principale forma di economia della zona.</Italian>
        <Spanish>[TAB]El vino, una bebida preparada a partir de uvas fermentadas, se elaboró por vez primera ya en el 6000 a. C. Su consumo se extendió rápidamente por Oriente Medio y Egipto, y pronto se convirtió en una popular bebida en el mundo antiguo. Las uvas empleadas en la fabricación del vino crecen en muchas y muy distintas partes del mundo. La mayoría de las viñas están en colinas y valles de regiones templadas. La vinicultura se ha perfeccionado como industria a lo largo de varios siglos. Muchas regiones, como los valles del Rin y del Loira en Europa, son conocidas por sus grandes vinos y obtienen una parte significativa de sus ingresos de la vinicultura.</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_WATER_WORKED</Tag>
        <English>Water Worked</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Mer travaillée</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Bearbeitetes Wasser</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Irrigazione:Irrigazioni</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Agua faenada:Aguas faenadas</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_WATER_WORKED_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[TAB]Water has the chemical formula H2O:  one oxygen and two hydrogen ions connected by covalent bonds. Water is a liquid at ambient conditions, but it often co-exists on Earth with its solid state, ice, and gaseous state (water vapor or steam). Water also exists in a liquid crystal state near hydrophilic surfaces.</English>
        <French>[TAB]L'eau est un composé chimique ubiquitaire sur la Terre, essentiel pour tous les organismes vivants connus. C'est le milieu de vie de la plupart des êtres vivants. Elle se trouve en général dans son état liquide répondant à la formule chimique H2O : la molécule contient un atome d'oxygène et deux atomes d'hydrogène.</French>
        <German>[TAB]Wasser ist eine chemische Substanz mit der Formel H2O. Es enthält also Sauerstoff und Wasserstoff. Bei Raumtemperatur ist es flüssig, existiert aber auf der Erde auch oft in gefrorener Form als Eis oder Schnee oder in Gasform als Wasserdampf.</German>
        <Italian>[TAB]Water is a chemical substance with the chemical formula H2O. Its molecule contains one oxygen and two hydrogen atoms connected by covalent bonds. Water is a liquid at ambient conditions, but it often co-exists on Earth with its solid state, ice, and gaseous state (water vapor or steam). Water also exists in a liquid crystal state near hydrophilic surfaces.</Italian>
        <Spanish>[TAB]Water is a chemical substance with the chemical formula H2O. Its molecule contains one oxygen and two hydrogen atoms connected by covalent bonds. Water is a liquid at ambient conditions, but it often co-exists on Earth with its solid state, ice, and gaseous state (water vapor or steam). Water also exists in a liquid crystal state near hydrophilic surfaces.</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_RAFT_STATION</Tag>
        <English>River Ferry Station</English>
        <German>
            <Text>Flussfährenstation</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_RAFT_STATION_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[TAB][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]River Ferries[COLOR_REVERT] and Rafts were the most used means of transportation to cross [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]large rivers[COLOR_REVERT] and streams in the new world before technological advances allowed the construction of larger and more solid bridges.</English>
        <German>[TAB][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Flussfähren[COLOR_REVERT] und Flösse waren die am meisten genutzen Transportmittel um [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]große Flüsse[COLOR_REVERT] und Ströme in der neuen Welt zu überqueren, bevor der technische Fortschritt es erlaubte größere uns tabilere Brücken zu bauen.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_ALLOWS_CROSSING_OF_LARGE_RIVERS</Tag>
        <English>[ICON_BULLET]Allows all Land Units to cross [LINK=TERRAIN_LARGE_RIVERS]Large Rivers[\LINK]</English>
        <German>[ICON_BULLET]Erlaubt es allen Landeinheiten einen [LINK=TERRAIN_LARGE_RIVERS]Großen Fluss[\LINK] zu überqueren.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_BUILD_ONLY_LARGE_RIVERS</Tag>
        <English>[ICON_BULLET]Can only be built on [LINK=TERRAIN_LARGE_RIVERS]Large Rivers[\LINK]</English>
        <German>[ICON_BULLET]Kann nur auf [LINK=TERRAIN_LARGE_RIVERS]Großen Flüssen[\LINK] gebaut werden.</German>
    </TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>
