<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_TERRAIN_COAST</Tag>
        <English>Coast</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Côte</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Küste</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Costa:Coste</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Costa:Costas</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_TERRAIN_COAST_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>The coastline is where the land meets the sea or ocean. A precise line that can be called a coastline cannot be determined due to the dynamic nature of tides. The term "coastal zone" can be used instead, which is a spatial zone where interaction of the sea and land occurs. Both the terms coast and coastal are often used to describe a geographic location or region; for example, New Zealand's West Coast, or the East and West Coasts of the United States.</English>
        <French>Le littoral est la bande de terre qui sépare la zone comprise entre une étendue maritime et le continent, ou l'arrière-pays. Selon les échelles retenues, le littoral peut s'étendre de quelques centaines de mètres à plusieurs kilomètres de part et d'autre de la limite terre-eau ou au sens strict, correspondre à l'estran.</French>
        <German>Als Küste bezeichnet man das Gebiet, wo Land auf Ozean trifft.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_TERRAIN_DESERT</Tag>
        <English>Desert</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Désert</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Wüste</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Deserto:Deserti</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Desierto:Desiertos</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_TERRAIN_DESERT_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>A desert is a landscape or region that receives an extremely low amount of precipitation, less than enough to support growth of most plants. Deserts are defined as areas with an average annual precipitation of less than 250 millimetres (10 in) per year, or as areas where more water is lost by evaporation than falls as precipitation. In the Köppen climate classification system, deserts are classed as BWh (hot desert) or BWk (temperate desert). In the Thornthwaite climate classification system, deserts would be classified as arid megathermal climates.</English>
        <French>Le mot désert désigne aujourd'hui une zone stérile ou peu propice à la vie, en raison du sol impropre, ou de la faiblesse des précipitations (moins de 250 mm par an). Un paysage désertique se reconnaît à son aspect dénudé sur de vastes surfaces, sans présence humaine réellement importante.</French>
        <German>Eine Wüste ist ein Landstrich oder eine Region mit wenig Niederschlägen, wodurch kaum Wachstum von Pflanzen möglich ist.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_TERRAIN_GRASS</Tag>
        <English>Grassland</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Prairie</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Grasland</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Prateria:Praterie</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Pradera:Praderas</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_TERRAIN_GRASS_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>Grasslands are areas where the vegetation is dominated by grasses (Poaceae) and other herbaceous (non-woody) plants (forbs). However, sedge (Cyperaceae) and rush (Juncaceae) families can also be found. Grasslands occur naturally on all continents except Antarctica. In temperate latitudes, such as northwest Europe and the Great Plains and California in North America, native grasslands are dominated by perennial bunch grass species, whereas in warmer climates annual species form a greater component of the vegetation.</English>
        <French>Les prairies forment un biome terrestre qui regroupe les étendues herbacées au climat tempéré. Le paysage naturel est celui d'une immense étendue d'herbes dont les arbres sont le plus souvent complètement absents, sauf le long des cours d'eau.</French>
        <German>Als Grasland bezeichnet man Gebiete, in denen niedrige Vegetation vorherrscht, die von Gräsern dominiert wird.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_TERRAIN_HILL</Tag>
        <English>Hill</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Colline</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Hügel</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Collina:Colline</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Colina:Colinas</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_TERRAIN_HILL_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>A hill is a landform that extends above the surrounding terrain. Hills often have a distinct summit, although in areas with scarp/dip topography a hill may be higher flat terrain without a distinct summit (e.g. Box Hill).</English>
        <French>Une colline est un relief généralement modéré et relativement peu étendu qui s'élève au-dessus d'une plaine ou d'un plateau et se distingue dans le paysage. Les collines peuvent être isolées ou se regrouper en champs de collines.</French>
        <German>Hügel sind eine Landform, die sich über das umgebende Terrain erhebt, jedoch noch keinen massiven Gipfel, wie einen Berg, aufweist.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_TERRAIN_MARSH</Tag>
        <English>Marsh</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Marais:Marais</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>Sumpf</German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Acquitrino</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Pantano:Pantanos</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_TERRAIN_MARSH_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>A marsh is wetland dominated by herbaceous rather than woody plant species. Marshes can often be found at the edges of lakes and streams where they form a transition between the aquatic and terrestrial ecosystems. They are often dominated by grasses, rushes or reeds. If woody plants are present they tend to be low-growing shrubs. This form of vegetation is what differentiates marshes from other types of wetland such as swamps, which are dominated by trees, and bogs, which are wetlands that have accumulated deposits of acidic peat.</English>
        <French>En géographie, un marais est un type de formation paysagère au relief peu accidenté où le sol est recouvert, en permanence ou par intermittence, d'une couche d'eau stagnante, en général peu profonde, et couverte de végétations. On parle de zone humide.</French>
        <German>Als Sumpf bezeichnet man Feuchtgebiete, die eher von niedrigen Blattpflanzen als von Bäumen dominiert werden. Sie finden sich oft angrenzend an Flüssen oder Seen.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_TERRAIN_OCEAN</Tag>
        <English>Ocean</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Océan</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Ozean</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Oceano:Oceani</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Océano:Océanos</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_TERRAIN_OCEAN_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>An ocean is a major body of saline water, and a principal component of the hydrosphere. Approximately 71% of the Earth's surface (3.6 x 10 to the 8th square km) is covered by ocean, a continuous body of water that is customarily divided into several principal oceans and smaller seas.</English>
        <French>Un océan est souvent défini, en géographie, comme une vaste étendue d'eau salée. En fait, il s'agit plutôt d'un volume, dont l'eau est en permanence renouvelée par des courants marins. Approximativement 70,7 % de la surface de la Terre est recouverte par l'océan mondial, communément divisé en cinq océans et en plusieurs dizaines de mers.</French>
        <German>Als Ozean bezeichnet man einen grosse Wasserfläche mit Salzwasser. Ungefähr 71% der Erdoberfläche ist mit Ozeanen bedeckt.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_TERRAIN_PEAK</Tag>
        <English>Peak</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Pic</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Berg</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Montagna:Montagne</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Pico:Picos</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_TERRAIN_PEAK_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>A mountain peak, in topography, is a point on a surface that is higher in elevation than all points immediately adjacent to it. Mathematically, a summit is a local maximum in elevation. The topographic terms "acme", "apex", "peak", and "zenith" are synonyms.</English>
        <French>Une montagne est une forme topographique de relief positif, à la surface de planètes telluriques (comme la Terre, Mars ou un satellite comme la Lune), et faisant partie d'un ensemble - une « chaîne de montagne » - ou formant un relief isolé.</French>
        <German>Als Gipfel oder Berg bezeichnet man einen geographischen Punkt, der höher als alle umgebenden Geländepunkte ist.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_TERRAIN_PLAINS</Tag>
        <English>Prairie</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Plaines</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Prärie</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Pianura:Pianure</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Llanura:Llanuras</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_TERRAIN_PLAINS_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>Prairies are ecosystems considered part of the temperate grasslands, savannas, and shrublands biome by ecologists, based on similar temperate climates, moderate rainfall, and a composition of grasses, herbs, and shrubs, rather than trees, as the dominant vegetation type. Temperate grassland regions include the Pampas of Argentina, Brazil and Uruguay as well as the steppes of Eurasia. Lands referred to as "prairie" tend to be in North America. The term encompasses the area referred to as the Interior Lowlands of the United States, Canada and Mexico, which includes all of the Great Plains as well as the wetter, somewhat hillier land to the east. In the U.S., the area is constituted by most or all of the states of North Dakota, South Dakota, Nebraska, Kansas, and Oklahoma, and sizable parts of the states of Montana, Wyoming, Colorado, New Mexico, Texas, Missouri, Iowa, Illinois, Indiana, Wisconsin, and western and southern Minnesota. The Central Valley of California is also a prairie. The Canadian Prairies extend across vast areas of Manitoba, Saskatchewan and Alberta.</English>
        <French>La Prairie (anglais : Tallgrass Prairie) occupe les Grandes Plaines entre les Appalaches et les Montagnes Rocheuses. Cette écorégion à prairie de zone tempérée est constituée d'une flore herbeuse de graminées, de composées et de légumineuses. Son nom lui vient des explorateurs français et n'a pas été anglicisé. Elle est l'équivalent de la steppe en Eurasie et de la pampa en Amérique du Sud. Aux États-Unis et au Canada, on fait parfois la distinction entre la végétation de taille basse des Hautes Plaines à l'ouest du 104e méridien terrestre et la végétation de taille moyenne et haute de l'est (depuis le sud du Manitoba jusqu'au centre du Texas). Lorsque cette distinction est faite, il est habituel de limiter le mot "prairie" aux zones de végétation moyenne à haute. La plus grande partie de ce territoire a été convertie en zone cultivée au cours des deux cents dernières années.</French>
        <German>Als Prärie bezeichnet man ein Gebiet, das von Gräsern und Sträuchen dominiert wird, aber durch relativ hohe Temperaturen und vergleichsweise niedrige Niederschläge keinen starken Pflanzenbewuchs, wie beispielsweise die Savanne, aufweist.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_TERRAIN_SAVANNAH</Tag>
        <English>Savannah</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Savane</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Savanne</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Prateria:Praterie</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Pradera:Praderas</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_TERRAIN_SAVANNAH_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>A savanna, or savannah, is a grassland ecosystem characterized by the trees being sufficiently widely spaced so that the canopy does not close. The open canopy allows enough light to reach the ground to support an unbroken herbaceous layer consisting primarily of grasses. Some classification systems also recognize a grassland savanna from which trees are absent. It is often believed that savannas feature widely spaced, scattered trees. However, in many savannas, tree densities are higher and trees are more regularly spaced than in forest. Savannas are also characterized by seasonal water availability, with the majority of rainfall confined to one season. Savannas are associated with several types of biomes. Savannas are frequently in a transitional zone between forest and desert or grassland. Savanna covers approximately 20% of the Earth's land area.</English>
        <French>La savane est une formation végétale propre aux régions chaudes à longue saison sèche et dominée par les plantes herbacées de la famille des Poacées. Elle est plus ou moins parsemée d'arbres ou d'arbustes. Selon la densité (dans l'ordre croissant) des espèces ligneuses, on parle de « savane herbeuse », de « savane arbustive », de « savane arborée », de « savane boisée », puis de forêt claire, la transition se faisant en général de manière progressive.</French>
        <German>Als Savanne bezeichnet man ein Grasgebiet mit ausgeprägtem Bewuchs, aber noch wenig Baumbestand und vergleichsweise hohen, wenn auch manchmal sehr saisonalen, Niederschlägen.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_TERRAIN_SNOW</Tag>
        <English>Permafrost</English>
        <French>Permafrost</French>
        <German>
            <Text>Permafrost</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>Permafrost</Italian>
        <Spanish>Permafrost</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_TERRAIN_SNOW_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>Permafrost is the part of the ground that is permanently frozen, at least for two years, and is therefore impermeable. Its formation, persistence or disappearance, and its thickness are very closely linked to climate change. This is why permafrost is studied as an indicator of global warming by a worldwide network of researchers using soundings, temperature measurements and satellite monitoring.</English>
        <French>Le permafrost, ou pergélisol, désigne la partie d'un sol gelé en permanence, au moins pendant deux ans, et de ce fait imperméable. Ses formations, persistance ou disparition, et son épaisseur sont très étroitement liées aux changements climatiques. C'est pourquoi le permafrost est étudié en tant qu'indicateur du réchauffement climatique par un réseau mondial de chercheurs s'appuyant sur des sondages, des mesures de température et un suivi satellitaire.</French>
        <German>Permafrost – auch Dauerfrostboden oder Permafrostboden – ist Boden, Sediment oder Gestein, welches in unterschiedlicher Mächtigkeit und Tiefe unter der Erdoberfläche mindestens zwei Jahre ununterbrochen Temperaturen unter dem Gefrierpunkt aufweist.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_TERRAIN_TUNDRA</Tag>
        <English>Tundra</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Toundra</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Tundra</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Tundra:Tundre</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Tundra:Tundras</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_TERRAIN_TUNDRA_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>In physical geography, tundra is a biome where the tree growth is hindered by low temperatures and short growing seasons. The term tundra comes through Russian from the Kildin Sami word tundâr "uplands," "treeless mountain tract." There are three types of tundra: Arctic tundra, alpine tundra, and Antarctic tundra. In tundra, the vegetation is composed of dwarf shrubs, sedges and grasses, mosses, and lichens. Scattered trees grow in some tundra. The ecotone (or ecological boundary region) between the tundra and the forest is known as the tree line or timberline.</English>
        <French>La toundra, terme emprunté au russe, lui-même emprunté au same désigne la formation végétale circumpolaire. Elle forme un cercle autour du pôle de plus de huit millions de km², soit 6 % des terres émergées. Du fait de la répartition des terres émergées sur la planète, la toundra n'existe pratiquement que dans l'hémisphère nord.</French>
        <German>Der Begriff 'Tundra' beschreibt eine Region, in der ausgeprägtes Wachstum von Bäumen und Pflanzen durch niedrige Temperaturen und kurze Jahreszeiten mit klimatisch günstigen Bedingungen verhindert wird. Das Wort leitet sich aus dem Russischen ab, wo es soviel wie 'Nordland' bedeutet.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_LARGE_RIVERS</Tag>
        <English>Large River</English>
        <German>
            <Text>Großer Strom</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_LARGE_RIVERS_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>Large rivers like the Mississippi, Missouri or Amazonas were crucial for the expansion and trade in the New World. They served as natural trade routes between coastal colonies and the deeper colonial heartlands. Thus many early settlements were founded along them.</English>
        <German>Große Ströme wie der Mississippi, Missouri oder Amazonas waren entscheidend für die Entwicklung der Kolonien und den Handel zwischen den Kolonien. Diese dienten als natürliche Handelsstraßen und Verkehrswege zwischen den Küstenstädten und dem wenig erschlossenen Binnenland. Daher wurden viele frühe Siedlungen entlang großer Ströme gegründet.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_LAKE</Tag>
        <English>Fresh Water Lake</English>
        <French>Lac d'eau douce</French>
        <German>Süßwassersee</German>
        <Italian>Lago d'acqua dolce</Italian>
        <Spanish>Lago de agua dulce</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_LAKE_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>Lakes are typically found in mountain ranges, or where their beds were hollowed out by glaciers at the end of the last ice age. They’re fresh water, larger than ponds, and often are part of a river system.[PARAGRAPH:1]Waterways often radiate out from mountains or run parallel along glacial gouges. Canada famously has a deranged drainage pattern because the basins are still too young.[PARAGRAPH:1]Fishing is often good and travel across lakes is calm compared to fighting river currents, though great lakes can be as stormy as the ocean.[PARAGRAPH:1]Because lakes hold enough water to moderate the local climate, they have always been a desirable place to live.</English>
        <German>Größere Süßwasserseen werden üblicherweise in der Nähe von Gebirgen gefunden. Manche finden sich auch in Regionen, in denen Gletscher in der letzten Eiszeit größere Untiefen hinterließen. Größere Süßwasserseen werden meist von Flüssen gespeist. Daher trocknen sie nicht aus und können deutlich größer als Teiche werden, die auch alleine durch Regen entstehen können.[PARAGRAPH:1]Süßwasserseen bieten oftmals hervorragende Fischfanggründe. Im Gegensatz zu schnell fließenden Flüssen gibt es auch kaum Strömungen und die ruhige Seeoberfläche zeigt kaum Wellengang. Jedoch kann es auf sehr großen Süßwasserseen bei Stürmen auch sehr windig werden.[PARAGRAPH:1]Da größere Süßwasserseen genug Wasser zur Wärmespeicherung haben, ist das Klima in ihrer Umgebung meist gemäßigt. Daher sind sie seit jeher beliebte Siedlungsgebiete.</German>
    </TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>
