<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_FEATURE_FOREST</Tag>
        <English>Forest</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Forêt</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Wald</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Foresta:Foreste</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Bosque:Bosques</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_FEATURE_FOREST_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Forests[COLOR_REVERT] grow in intermediate and high latitudes, and also on higher terrain in low latitudes. Your colonists can harvest [LINK=YIELD_FUR]fur[\LINK] and [LINK=YIELD_LUMBER]lumber[\LINK] there.[PARAGRAPH:1]Forests prevent any other resource on that plot except [LINK=YIELD_ORE]ore[\LINK], unless a bonus resource is present.[LINK=IMPROVEMENT_LODGE]Lodges[\LINK] and [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_TRAPPER_HUT]trapper huts[\LINK] can be built in forests. Putting up any other improvement clears the forest.[PARAGRAPH:1][LINK=PROFESSION_PIONEER]Pioneers[\LINK] can plant forests on both [LINK=TERRAIN_GRASS]grass[\LINK] and [LINK=TERRAIN_PLAINS]prairie[\LINK] terrain.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]A forest, also referred to as a wood or the woods and less often as a "wold" (or "weald"), "holt", or "frith" (or "firth"), means trees are the dominant plant. There are many definitions for forest. Forests cover 9.4% of the Earth's surface (or 30% of the land area), though long ago they covered much more, about 50% of the land, creating habitats for a wide range of organisms, working as hydrologic flow modulators and soil conservers, constituting one of the most important aspects of the Earth's biosphere. Although forest is primarily trees the forest ecosystem has many additional species such as fungi.</English>
        <French>[BOLD]Stratégie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]La [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Forêt[COLOR_REVERT] pousse à des lattitudes intermédiaires. Le terrain permet de produire de la [LINK=YIELD_FUR]fourrure[\LINK] et du [LINK=YIELD_LUMBER]bois de construction[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:1]La forêt empêche la production de n'importe quelle autre bien à l'exception du [LINK=YIELD_ORE]minerai[\LINK], à part si une ressource bonus y est présente. Des [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_LODGE]abris[\LINK] et des [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_TRAPPER_HUT]Huttes de trappeurs[\LINK] peuvent être construites dans la forêt.[PARAGRAPH:1]Les [LINK=PROFESSION_PIONEER]pionniers[\LINK] peuvent planter de la forêt sur les terrains de [LINK=TERRAIN_GRASS]prairie[\LINK] et de [LINK=TERRAIN_PLAINS]Plaines[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]À savoir : Une forêt ou un massif forestier est une étendue boisée, relativement grande, constituée d'un ou plusieurs peuplements d'arbres et d'espèces associées. Un boisement de faible étendue est dit bois, boqueteau ou bosquet selon son importance. Divers types de forêts existent; des forêts primaires aux forêts dites urbaines, avec les gradients intermédiaires. Il existe également de nombreux types d'exploitation des forêts (sylviculture, agrosylviculture). La forêt est aussi un milieu de vie et une source de revenus pour l'homme : au début du XXe siècle, plus de 500 millions de personnes, dont 150 millions d'autochtones vivent encore en forêt ou à ses abords. Elle abrite une grande richesse écologique composée d'une centaine d'espèces de mammifères, d'une cinquantaine d'espèces d'oiseaux, d'un millier d'espèces végétales et de plusieurs millions d'espèces d'insectes.</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Wald[COLOR_REVERT] wächst in gemäßigten und nördlichen Breitengraden, aber auch in höheren Lagen der niedrigeren Breitengrade. Die Kolonisten können dort [LINK=YIELD_FUR]Pelze[\LINK] gewinnen und [LINK=YIELD_LUMBER]Holz[\LINK] schlagen. Zur Gewinnung anderer Rohstoffe sind Wälder schlecht geeignet. Es können [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_LODGE]Holzfällerhütten[\LINK] und [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_TRAPPER_HUT]Jagdhütten[\LINK] in Wäldern gebaut werden. Andere Geländeverbesserungen entfernen den Wald.[PARAGRAPH:1][LINK=PROFESSION_PIONEER]Pioniere[\LINK] können neue Wälder auf [LINK=TERRAIN_GRASS]Grasland[\LINK] und [LINK=TERRAIN_PLAINS]Prärie[\LINK] anpflanzen.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Hintergrund :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Unter einem Wald versteht man ein Gebiet mit stark ausgeprägtem Baumbewuchs verschiendensten Alters. Die Dichte und die Baumarten und Pflanzenarten variieren von Region zu Region.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_FEATURE_FOREST_TUNDRA</Tag>
        <English>Taiga</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Taïga</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Taiga</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Taiga</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Taiga</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_FEATURE_FOREST_TUNDRA_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Taigas[COLOR_REVERT] grow predominantly in high latitudes, though they can be found on high terrain in low latitudes. Your colonists can harvest [LINK=YIELD_FUR]fur[\LINK], [LINK=YIELD_PREMIUM_FUR]premium fur[\LINK], [LINK=YIELD_VALUABLE_WOOD]valuable wood[\LINK] and [LINK=YIELD_LUMBER]lumber[\LINK] there.[PARAGRAPH:1]Taiga prevents any other resource on its plot other than [LINK=YIELD_ORE]ore[\LINK], unless a bonus resource is present.[LINK=IMPROVEMENT_LODGE]Lodges[\LINK] and [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_TRAPPER_HUT]trapper huts[\LINK] can be built in taiga. Other improvements remove the taiga.[PARAGRAPH:1][LINK=PROFESSION_PIONEER]Pioneers[\LINK] can plant taigas on [LINK=TERRAIN_TUNDRA]tundra[\LINK] terrain.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]A forest, also referred to as a wood or the woods and less often as a "wold" (or "weald"), "holt", or "frith" (or "firth"), is mainly trees. These plant communities cover approximately 9.4% of the Earth's surface, or 30% of total land area, though they once covered about 50% of the land area. The brief taiga summer is alive with colourful plants and insects, though iceworms nest only in folk songs.</English>
        <French>[BOLD]Stratégie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]La [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Taïga[COLOR_REVERT] pousse principalement dans les climats de haute lattitude, bien qu'on puisse également la trouver dans les terrains très élevées de plus basse lattitutde. Le terrain permet de produire de la [LINK=YIELD_FUR]fourrure[\LINK], de la [LINK=YIELD_PREMIUM_FUR]fourrure de qualité[\LINK], du [LINK=YIELD_VALUABLE_WOOD]bois précieux[\LINK] et du [LINK=YIELD_LUMBER]bois de construction[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:1]La taïga empêche la production de n'importe quelle autre bien à l'exception du [LINK=YIELD_ORE]minerai[\LINK], à part si une ressource bonus y est présente. Des [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_LODGE]abris[\LINK] et des [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_TRAPPER_HUT]Huttes de trappeurs[\LINK] peuvent être construites dans la taïga.[PARAGRAPH:1]Les [LINK=PROFESSION_PIONEER]pionniers[\LINK] peuvent planter de la taïga sur les terrains de [LINK=TERRAIN_TUNDRA]Tundra[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]À savoir :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]La taïga ou forêt boréale est l'un des principaux biomes terrestres. Fortement liée au climat subarctique, elle consiste en une formation végétale de type forestière parcourue par un vaste réseau lacustre résultant de l'érosion fluvioglaciaire. Sa végétation a la particularité d'être formée d'une majorité de conifères adaptés au froid (pins, épicéas, mélèzes et sapins), associée à un mélange de feuillus principalement composé de bouleaux, d'aulnes, de saules et de peupliers. Véritable désert humain, la taïga est la plus vaste continuité boisée de la planète et occupe à elle seule 10 % des terres émergées. Elle couvre la majorité des territoires intérieurs de l'Alaska, du Canada, de la Scandinavie, de la Finlande et de la Russie.</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Taiga[COLOR_REVERT] wächst in nördlichen Breitengraden, aber auch gelegentlich in höheren Lagen der gemässigten Breitengrade. Die Kolonisten können dort [LINK=YIELD_FUR]Pelze[\LINK] oder [LINK=YIELD_PREMIUM_FUR]Hochwertige Pelze[\LINK] gewinnen und [LINK=YIELD_LUMBER]Holz[\LINK] schlagen. Zur Gewinnung anderer Rohstoffe ist Taiga sehr schlecht geeignet. Es können [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_LODGE]Holzfällerhütten[\LINK] und [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_TRAPPER_HUT]Jagdhütten[\LINK] in der Taiga gebaut werden. Andere Geländeverbesserungen entfernen den Wald.[PARAGRAPH:1][LINK=PROFESSION_PIONEER]Pioniere[\LINK] können neue Wälder in der [LINK=TERRAIN_GRASS]Tundra[\LINK] anpflanzen.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Hintergrund :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Unter einem Wald versteht man ein Gebiet mit stark ausgeprägtem Baumbewuchs verschiendensten Alters. Die Dichte und die Baumarten und Pflanzenarten variieren von Region zu Region.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_FEATURE_ICE</Tag>
        <English>Polar Ice</English>
        <French>Banquise</French>
        <German>
            <Text>Polareis</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Ghiaccio:Ghiacci</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Hielo:Hielos</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_FEATURE_ICE_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Polar ice[COLOR_REVERT] is impassible terrain to all units. The only option you have is to sail around it.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Ice is water frozen solid. During the "We The People" game period ice boundaries remain stable, though later that will change. Usually ice is in the phase known as ice Ih, the most abundant of the solid phases on the Earth's surface. It can appear transparent or opaque bluish-white colour, depending on the presence of impurities or air inclusions. Other materials such as soil may further alter the appearance.</English>
        <French>[BOLD]Stratégie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]La banquise est la couche de glace qui se forme à la surface d'une étendue d'eau par solidification des premières couches d'eau, généralement la mer mais aussi les lacs et les rivières. Il ne faut pas confondre cette glace plus ou moins pérenne avec les calottes glaciaires et les inlandsis qui sont constitués quant à eux de glace continentale, c'est-à-dire de précipitations neigeuses accumulées et tassées.</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Polareis[COLOR_REVERT] tritt nur auf dem Meer auf und ist für alle Schiffe unpassierbar. Diese müssen um diese herum segeln.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Hintergrund :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Als Eis bezeichnet man gefrorenes und somit festes Wasser. Ein beachtlicher Teil der Wasservorräte der Erde liegt in Eisform vor.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_FEATURE_JUNGLE</Tag>
        <English>Jungle</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Jungle</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Dschungel</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Giungla:Giungle</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Selva:Selvas</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_FEATURE_JUNGLE_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Jungles[COLOR_REVERT] grow in tropical latitudes, and your colonists can harvest [LINK=YIELD_COCOA_FRUITS]cocoa pods[\LINK] there, as well as [LINK=YIELD_VALUABLE_WOOD]valuable wood[\LINK]. [LINK=YIELD_LUMBER]Lumber[\LINK] is also found in jungles.[PARAGRAPH:1]Unlike forests, [LINK=PROFESSION_FARMER]farmers[\LINK] can grow a little [LINK=YIELD_FOOD]food[\LINK] in jungles if the underlying terrain is capable of producing at least 3 food. [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_LODGE]Lodges[\LINK] and [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_COCOA_PLANTATION]cocoa plantations[\LINK] can be built in jungles. Other construction removes the jungle.[PARAGRAPH:1][LINK=PROFESSION_PIONEER]Pioneers[\LINK] can plant jungles on both [LINK=TERRAIN_MARSH]marsh[\LINK] and [LINK=TERRAIN_SAVANNAH]savannah[\LINK] terrain.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Jungle or tropical forest refers to the dense, impenetrable tropical rainforest biome luxuriant with animal and plant life. The term "jungle" is a synonym for tropical rainforest.[PARAGRAPH:1]The northwest Pacific coast of North America also has the characteristic rainfall and plant growth to qualify as the world's only temperate jungle.[PARAGRAPH:1]The word "jungle" originates from the Sanskrit word "jangala" which in India referred to uncultivated land. Although the Sanskrit word refers to "dry land", it has been suggested that an Anglo-Indian misinterpretation led to its use for a dense "tangled thicket". while others have argued that a cognate word in Urdu did refer to forests. The term is prevalent in many languages of South Asia, and on the Iranian plateau, particularly in Bangla, Hindi, Marathi, Urdu, Punjabi and Persian.</English>
        <French>[BOLD]Stratégie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]La jungle désigne les forêts de feuillus humides tropicales et subtropicales ou les forêts tropicales humides constituent un biome des zones intertropicales caractérisé par une formation végétale arborée haute et dense ainsi qu'un climat chaud et très humide.</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Dschungel[COLOR_REVERT] wächst in tropischen Breitengraden. Die Kolonien können dort [LINK=YIELD_COCOA_FRUITS]Kakaofrüchte[\LINK] ernten, aber auch [LINK=YIELD_VALUABLE_WOOD]Edelholz[\LINK] schlagen. Normalse [LINK=YIELD_LUMBER]Holz[\LINK] ist im Dschungel natürlich ebenfalls vorhanden.[PARAGRAPH:1]Im Gegensatz zu anderen Wäldern, kann im Dschungel auch [LINK=YIELD_FOOD]Nahrung[\LINK] geerntet werden, wenn das zugrunde liegende Gelände mindestens 3 Nahrung erzeugt. Im Dschungel können [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_LODGE]Holzfällerhütten[\LINK] und [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_COCOA_PLANTATION]Kakaoplantagen gebaut werden[\LINK]. Der Bau einer anderen Geländeverbesserung entfernt den Dschungel.[PARAGRAPH:1][LINK=PROFESSION_PIONEER]Pioniere[\LINK] können in [LINK=TERRAIN_MARSH]Sümpfen[\LINK] and [LINK=TERRAIN_SAVANNAH]Savannen[\LINK] neuen Dschungel anpflanzen.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Hintergrund :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Dschungel oder Tropischer Wald bezieht sich aufgrund seiner Dichte auf einen mehr oder weniger undurchdringlichen Regenwald mit einer Vielzahl von Pflanzen und Tieren.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_FEATURE_LIGHT_FOREST</Tag>
        <English>Light Forest</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Forêt clairsemée:Forêts clairsemées</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>Buschland</German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Foresta rada</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Bosque disperso:Bosques dispersos</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_FEATURE_LIGHT_FOREST_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Light forest[COLOR_REVERT] can grow in all latitudes. It slightly increases the production of [LINK=YIELD_FUR]fur[\LINK] and [LINK=YIELD_LUMBER]lumber[\LINK] on its plot, but also keeps all the other yields the plot has due to its base terrain, albeit in reduced numbers.[PARAGRAPH:1][LINK=IMPROVEMENT_LODGE]Lodges[\LINK] and [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_TRAPPER_HUT]trapper huts[\LINK] can be built in light forests. Other improvements remove the forest.[PARAGRAPH:1][LINK=PROFESSION_PIONEER]Pioneers[\LINK] cannot plant light forests. Once they're gone, they're gone forever.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]A forest, also referred to as a wood or the woods and less often as a "wold" (or "weald"), "holt", or "frith" (or "firth"), is an area where trees predominate. Forests cover 9.4% of the Earth's surface or 30% of total land area. They once covered much more, about 50% of total land area. They are rich habitats for organisms, hydrologic flow modulators and soil conservers, constituting one of the most important aspects of the Earth's biosphere. A forest ecosystem includes additional species such as fungi.</English>
        <French>[BOLD]Stratégie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Une forêt ou un massif forestier est une étendue boisée, relativement grande, constituée d'un ou plusieurs peuplements d'arbres et d'espèces associées. Un boisement de faible étendue est dit bois, boqueteau ou bosquet selon son importance. Les définitions de la forêt sont nombreuses en fonction des latitudes et des usages.</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Buschland[COLOR_REVERT] und lichte Wälder wachsen in allen Breitengraden. Die Kolonisten können dort ein wenig [LINK=YIELD_FUR]Felle[\LINK] gewinnen und auch etwas[LINK=YIELD_LUMBER]Holz[\LINK] schlagen. Die Gewinnung anderer Rohstoffe wird durch Buschland nur leicht behindert. Es können [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_LODGE]Holzfällerhütten[\LINK] und [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_TRAPPER_HUT]Jagdhütten[\LINK] im Buschland gebaut werden. Andere Geländeverbesserungen entfernen den Wald.[PARAGRAPH:1][LINK=PROFESSION_PIONEER]Pioniere[\LINK] können kein neues Buschland pflanzen.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Hintergrund :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Unter einem Wald versteht man ein Gebiet mit stark ausgeprägtem Baumbewuchs verschiendensten Alters. Die Dichte und die Baumarten und Pflanzenarten variieren von Region zu Region.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_FEATURE_STORM</Tag>
        <English>Storm</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Tempête</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Gewittersturm</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Tempesta:Tempesta</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>tormenta:tormenta</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_FEATURE_STORM_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Storms[COLOR_REVERT] take many movement points to get through and, on top of that, damage your ships. You want to avoid these weather systems. They occur only on [LINK=TERRAIN_OCEAN]ocean[\LINK] tiles, so on [LINK=TERRAIN_COAST]coast[\LINK] or [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]fresh water lake[COLOR_REVERT] tiles you'll be safe from them.[PARAGRAPH:1]Storms can never destroy a ship, but they can weaken it severely. For more information, see [LINK=CONCEPT_WINDS_AND_STORMS]Winds and Storms[\LINK][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]A storm is any disturbed state of an astronomical body's atmosphere especially affecting its surface, and strongly implying severe weather. It may be marked by strong wind, hail, thunder and/or lightning (a thunderstorm), heavy precipitation (snowstorm, rainstorm), heavy freezing rain (ice storm), strong winds (tropical cyclone, windstorm), or wind transporting some substance through the atmosphere as in a dust storm, blizzard or sandstorm. Storms destroy lives and property through storm surge, heavy rain flooding roads and homes, lightning, wildfires, and vertical wind shear. However heavy rainfall can alleviate drought. Heavy snowfall is good for skiing and snowboarding.</English>
        <French>[BOLD]Stratégie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Une tempête est un phénomène météorologique violent à large échelle dite synoptique, avec un diamètre compris en général entre 200 à 1 000 km, caractérisé par des vents rapides (tourbillon) et des précipitations intenses. Elle peut être accompagnée d'orages donnant des éclairs et du tonnerre ainsi que de la grêle et des tornades.</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Stürme[COLOR_REVERT] benötigen viele Bewegungspunkte, um hindurch zu segeln und beschädigen auch die Schiffe darin. Daher sollten Stürme, wenn möglich, vermieden werden. Sie kommen nur auf dem offenen [LINK=TERRAIN_COEAN]Ozean[\LINK] vor. Daher sind [LINK=TERRAIN_COAST]Küstengewässer[\LINK] für Schiffe viel sicherer.[PARAGRAPH:1]Stürme zerstören Schiffe nicht vollständig, können diese aber schwer beschädigen. Für weitere Informationen siehe [LINK=CONCEPT_WINDS_AND_STORMS]Wind und Stürme[\LINK][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Hintergrund :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Ein Sturm ist ein gestörter Zustand der Atmosphäre, der heftige Wetterbedingungen verursacht. Dazu können sehr starke Winde, Regen, Schnee, Hagel, Donner und Blitze gehören.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_FEATURE_TORNADO</Tag>
        <English>Tornado</English>
        <French>Tornade</French>
        <German>Tornado</German>
        <Italian>Tornado</Italian>
        <Spanish>Tornado</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_FEATURE_TORNADO_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Tornadoes[COLOR_REVERT] make a plot temporarily impassible to all units. They can spontaneously form on any land plot, and remain active for a few turns. During this period no resources can be won from that plot. Improvements and roads there are destroyed and, on adjacent plots, improvements and roads are endangered as well. Settlements and units will never be destroyed.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]A tornado is a violent, rotating column of air touching down on the surface of the earth. Tornadoes are typically in the form of a visible condensation funnel, whose narrow end touches the earth in a swirling cloud of debris.</English>
        <French>[BOLD]Stratégie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Une tornade est un vortex (tourbillon) de vents extrêmement violents, prenant naissance à la base d'un nuage d'orage (cumulonimbus) lorsque les conditions de cisaillement des vents sont favorables dans la basse atmosphère. De très faibles tornades peuvent également se développer sous des nuages d'averses (cumulus bourgeonnant).</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Tornados[COLOR_REVERT] sind für alle Einheiten unpassierbar. Sie können sich spontan auf dem Land bilden und bleiben einige wenige Runden aktiv. Während dieser Zeit können auf dem Feld keine Rohstoffe gewonnen werden. Geländeverbesserungen und Straßen werden zerstört. Auch auf benachbarten Geländefeldern sind Geländeverbesserungen und Straßen in Gefahr. Siedlungen sind jedoch nicht gefährdet.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Hintergrund :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Ein Tornado, auch Wind- oder Wasserhose genannt, ist ein kleinräumiger Luftwirbel in der Erdatmosphäre, der eine annähernd senkrechte Drehachse aufweist und im Zusammenhang mit konvektiver Bewölkung (Cumulus und Cumulonimbus) steht. Der Wirbel erstreckt sich hierbei durchgehend vom Boden bis zur Wolkenuntergrenze und ist von einem Staubwolke umgeben.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_FEATURE_VENT_DEF</Tag>
        <English>Unfavourable wind</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Vent défavorable</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Ungünstige Winde</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Tempesta di vento:Tempesta di vento</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>ventarron:ventarron</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_FEATURE_VENT_DEF_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Unfavourable winds[COLOR_REVERT] grant a defensive onus to all ships on the tile, but they take more movement points to sail through. This movement penalty can be reduced by the [LINK=PROMOTION_MOBILITY1]Mobility I[\LINK] and [LINK=PROMOTION_SAILING3]Naval Warfare III[\LINK] promotions.[PARAGRAPH:1]Like other weather systems, unfavourable winds occur only on [LINK=TERRAIN_COEAN]ocean[\LINK] tiles, not on [LINK=TERRAIN_COAST]coast[\LINK] or [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]fresh water lake[COLOR_REVERT] tiles.[PARAGRAPH:1]For more information, see [LINK=CONCEPT_WINDS_AND_STORMS]Winds and Storms[\LINK][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1](navigation) Unfavourable winds delay a vessel sailing in its desired direction.</English>
        <French>[BOLD]Stratégie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1](navigation) Un vent défavorable empêche un équipage de se déplacer dans la direction qu'il souhaite.</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Ungünstige Winde[COLOR_REVERT] geben den darin befindlichen Schiffen zwar kleine Vorteile bei der Verteidigung, erfordern aber mehr Bewegungspunkte, um darin zu segeln. Dieser Effekt kann aber durch die Beförderungen [LINK=PROMOTION_MOBILITY1]Mobilität I[\LINK] und [LINK=PROMOTION_SAILING3]Seekrieg III[\LINK] gesenkt werden. Ungünstige Winde kommen nur auf dem offenen [LINK=TERRAIN_COEAN]Ozean[\LINK] vor. Für weitere Informationen siehe [LINK=CONCEPT_WINDS_AND_STORMS]Wind und Stürme[\LINK][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Hintergrund :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Wind, der das Vorankommen eines Segelschiffs in einer bestimmten Richtung behindert.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_FEATURE_VENT_FAV</Tag>
        <English>Favourable wind</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Vent favorable</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Günstige Brise</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Favourable wind:Favourable wind</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Favourable wind:Favourable wind</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_FEATURE_VENT_FAV_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Favourable winds[COLOR_REVERT] impose a defensive penalty for any ships on that tile, but they allow vessels with the [LINK=PROMOTION_SEA_EXPLORER]Sea Explorer[\LINK] promotion to move at double speed. The defensive penalty can be reduced by the [LINK=PROMOTION_MOBILITY1]Mobility I[\LINK] promotions.[PARAGRAPH:1]Like other weather systems, favourable winds occur only on [LINK=TERRAIN_COEAN]ocean[\LINK] tiles, not on [LINK=TERRAIN_COAST]coast[\LINK] or [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]fresh water lake[COLOR_REVERT] tiles.[PARAGRAPH:1]For more information, see [LINK=CONCEPT_WINDS_AND_STORMS]Winds and Storms[\LINK][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1](navigation) A favourable wind is one which aids a craft in making progress in a desired direction; usually used in plural form in connection with sailing vessels; also called a fair wind.</English>
        <French>[BOLD]Stratégie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1](navigation) Un vent favorable aide un équipage à se déplacer dans la direction qu'il souhaite.</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Günstige Winde[COLOR_REVERT] erlauben es Schiffen mit der Beförderung [LINK=PROMOTION_SEA_EXPLORER]Entdecker der Meere[\LINK] mit doppelter Geschwindigkeit zu segeln. Allerdings senken sie auch die Verteidigungswerte des darin befindlichen Schiffes. Dieser Effekt kann aber durch die Beförderung [LINK=PROMOTION_MOBILITY1]Mobilität I[\LINK] gesenkt werden. Günstige Winde kommen nur auf dem offenen [LINK=TERRAIN_COEAN]Ozean[\LINK] vor. Für weitere Informationen siehe [LINK=CONCEPT_WINDS_AND_STORMS]Wind und Stürme[\LINK][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Hintergrund :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Wind, der das Vorankommen eines Segelschiffs in einer bestimmten Richtung begünstigt.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_FEATURE_VOLCANO</Tag>
        <English>Volcano</English>
        <French>Volcan</French>
        <German>Vulkan</German>
        <Italian>Vulcano</Italian>
        <Spanish>Volcán</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_FEATURE_VOLCANO_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Volcanoes[COLOR_REVERT] impassible to all units. They spontaneously erupt on plots with [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]peaks[COLOR_REVERT], and remain active for a few turns. During this period no resources can be extracted from that plot. Improvements and roads on that plot are destroyed and, on adjacent plots, improvements and roads are endangered. Settlements and units will never be destroyed.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]A volcano is a rupture in a planet's surface which allows hot molten rock, ash and gases to escape from below. Volcanic activity creates new land and can form mountains over a long enough time.</English>
        <French>[BOLD]Stratégie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Un [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]volcan[COLOR_REVERT] est un ensemble géologique terrestre, sous-marin ou extra-terrestre qui résulte de la montée d'un magma puis de l'éruption d'une partie de ce magma. Le magma provient de la fusion partielle du manteau et exceptionnellement de la croûte terrestre. L'éruption peut se manifester, de manière plus ou moins combinée, par des émissions de lave, par des émanations ou des explosions de gaz, par des projections de tephras, par des phénomènes hydromagmatiques, etc. Les laves refroidies et les retombées de tephras constituent des roches éruptives qui peuvent s'accumuler et atteindre des milliers de mètres d'épaisseur formant ainsi des montagnes ou des îles. Selon la nature des matériaux, le type d'éruption, la fréquence d'éruption et l'orogenèse, les volcans prennent des formes variées, la plus typique étant celle d'une montagne conique couronnée par un cratère ou une caldeira. La définition de ce qu'est un volcan a évolué au cours des derniers siècles en fonction de la connaissance que les géologues en avaient et de la représentation qu'ils pouvaient en donner.</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Vulkane[COLOR_REVERT] sind für alle Einheiten unpassierbar. Sie brechen spontan auf Gebirgsgipfeln aus und bleiben für einige Runden aktiv. Während dieser Zeit können keine Rohstoffe auf dem Gelände gewonnen werden. Geländeverbesserungen und Straßen werden vernichtet. Selbst auf angrenzenden Geländefeldern sind Geländeverbesserungen und Straßen gefährdet.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Hintergrund :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Ein Vulkan ist eine geologische Struktur, die entsteht, wenn Magma (Gesteinsschmelze) bis an die Oberfläche eines Planeten (z.B. der Erde) aufsteigt. Alle Begleiterscheinungen, die mit dem Aufstieg und Austritt der glutflüssigen Gesteinsschmelze verbunden sind, bezeichnet man als Vulkanismus. Bei einem Vulkanausbruch werden nicht nur glutflüssige, sondern auch feste oder gasförmige Stoffe freigesetzt (Vulkanismus). Die meisten Vulkane haben annähernd die Form eines Kegels, dessen Hangneigung von der Zähigkeit der Lava abhängt. Die Gestalt kann aber auch unregelmäßig sein oder eine kuppelförmige Aufwölbung bilden.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_FEATURE_RIVER_FORD</Tag>
        <English>River Ford</English>
        <German>Flussfurt</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_FEATURE_RIVER_FORD_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]River fords[COLOR_REVERT] allow all land units to make it across a [LINK=TERRAIN_LARGE_RIVERS]large river[\LINK] without being swept away. They form naturally from sediment deposited by the flowing river.</English>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Flussfurten[COLOR_REVERT] erlauben es allen Landeinheiten, einen [LINK=TERRAIN_LARGE_RIVERS]Großen Fluss[\LINK] zu überqueren. Sie enstehen auf natürliche Weise durch Ablagerungen von Sedimenten.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_TERRAIN_FEATURE_ALLOWS_CROSSING_OF_LARGE_RIVERS</Tag>
        <English>[ICON_BULLET]Allows all land units to cross [LINK=TERRAIN_LARGE_RIVERS]large rivers[\LINK]</English>
        <German>[ICON_BULLET]Erlaubt es allen Landeinheiten, einen [LINK=TERRAIN_LARGE_RIVERS]Großen Fluss[\LINK] zu überqueren.</German>
    </TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>
