<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_CITY_RUINS</Tag>
        <English>Ruins</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Ruines</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Ruine:Ruinen</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Rovina:Rovine</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Ruina:Ruinas</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Spanish>
        <Russian>Руины</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_CITY_RUINS_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Ruins[COLOR_REVERT] are the remnants of a city or improvement that has been abandoned. Rarely the King might sponsor a scientific study but generally they serve no in-game function but decoration.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Ruins are the remains of human architecture: once-complete structures that have fallen into a state of disrepair, either from lack of maintenance or deliberate acts of destruction. Disasters, war and depopulation are the most common causes, after which structures become derelict over time from weather and scavenging.</English>
        <French>[BOLD]Stratégie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Les [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]ruines[COLOR_REVERT] sont les restes d'architecture humaine passée : des structures autrefois complètes qui, par abandon, se sont désagrégés pour atteindre un état difficilement réparable. Les désastres naturels, la guerre ou le dépeuplement sont les causes principales de tels abandons. Les conditions climatiques et le pillage sont les principales causes de délabrement de ces structures.</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Ruinen[COLOR_REVERT] sind die Überreste einer Stadt oder einer Geländeverbesserung, die im Laufe der Zeit aufgegeben wurde. Selten mal wird Seine Majestät ein paar Forscher zu ihrer Untersuchung abordnen, aber im Allgemeinen dienen sie im Spiel nur dekorativen Zwecken.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Hintergrund :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Ruinen sind die Reste menschlicher Architektur: Strukturen, die einst vollständig waren, dann aber durch den Einfluss der Umwelt, wie Pflanzen, Regen oder Wind, über die Zeit zerfielen. Gründe für die Verwahrlosung können Kriege, Katastrophen, Krankheiten und vieles mehr gewesen sein.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_FRUIT_PLANTATION</Tag>
        <English>Fruit Plantation</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Plantation de Fruits</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Obstplantage</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Piantagione di Frutos</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Plantación de Fruto</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Spanish>
        <Russian>Фруктовая плантация</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_FRUIT_PLANTATION_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Fruit plantations[COLOR_REVERT] can be built only in [LINK=FEATURE_JUNGLE]jungles[\LINK] or on Bonus Resources for Fruits. They increase the production of [LINK=YIELD_COCOA_FRUITS]cocoa pods[\LINK], [LINK=YIELD_FRUITS]fruits[\LINK] and [LINK=YIELD_FOOD]food[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Fruit plantations are usually a mixture of many different kinds of trees and not a monoculture. This ensures a healthy environment for the precious fruits.</English>
        <French>[BOLD]Stratégie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Les [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]plantations de fruits[COLOR_REVERT] sont généralement un mélange de plusieurs types d'arbres et non pas une monoculture. C'est ce qui assure un environnement sain pour les fruits précieux.</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Obstplantagen[COLOR_REVERT] können nur im [LINK=FEATURE_JUNGLE]Dschungel[\LINK] oder auf Bonusresourcen für Früchte angelegt werden. Sie steigern die Produktion von [LINK=YIELD_COCOA_FRUITS]Kakaofrüchten[\LINK], [LINK=YIELD_FRUITS]Früchten[\LINK] und [LINK=YIELD_FOOD]Nahrung[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Hintergrund :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Im Gegensatz zu den Monokulturen anderen Plantagen sind Obstplantagen normalerweise eine Mischung verschiedenster Bäume und Sträucher. Dies ermöglicht ein gesundes Umfeld für die wertvollen Früchte.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LARGE_FRUIT_PLANTATION</Tag>
        <English>Large Fruit Plantation</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Grande plantation de fruits</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Große Obstplantage</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Grande piantagione di frutos</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Gran plantación de frutos</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Spanish>
        <Russian>Большая фруктовая плантация</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LARGE_FRUIT_PLANTATION_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Large fruit plantations[COLOR_REVERT] are upgrades of [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_FRUIT_PLANTATION]fruit plantations[\LINK]. They increase the production of [LINK=YIELD_COCOA_FRUITS]cocoa pods[\LINK], [LINK=YIELD_FRUITS]fruits[\LINK] and [LINK=YIELD_FOOD]food[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Fruit plantations are usually a mixture of many different kinds of trees and not a monoculture. This ensures a healthy environment for the precious fruits.</English>
        <French>[BOLD]Stratégie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Les [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]plantations de fruits[COLOR_REVERT] sont généralement un mélange de plusieurs types d'arbres et non pas une monoculture. C'est ce qui assure un environnement sain pour les fruits précieux.</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Große Obstplantagen[COLOR_REVERT] sind eine Erweiterung von [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_FRUIT_PLANTATION]Obstplantagen[\LINK]. Sie verbessern die Produktion von [LINK=YIELD_COCOA_FRUITS]Kakaofrüchten[\LINK], [LINK=YIELD_FRUITS]Früchten[\LINK] und [LINK=YIELD_FOOD]Nahrung[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Hintergrund :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Im Gegensatz zu den Monokulturen anderen Plantagen sind Obstplantagen normalerweise eine Mischung verschiedenster Bäume und Sträucher. Dies ermöglicht ein gesundes Umfeld für die wertvollen Früchte.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_COLLECTORS_POST</Tag>
        <English>Collector's Post</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Poste de Collection</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Sammelstelle</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Collector's Post</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Collectors Post</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Spanish>
        <Russian>Лагерь сборщиков</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_COLLECTORS_POST_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Collector's posts[COLOR_REVERT] can be built only on hilly [LINK=TERRAIN_PLAINS]prairie[\LINK] terrain. The [LINK=YIELD_FOOD]Food[\LINK] and [LINK=YIELD_RED_PEPPER]Red Pepper[\LINK] production on such tiles is increased.</English>
        <French>[BOLD]Stratégie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Les piments font partie de l'alimentation des Amériques depuis au moins 9 500 ans. Des traces archéologiques de domestication ont été trouvées dans le sud-ouest de l'équateur il y a plus de 6 000 ans. Le piment semble avoir été une des premières plantes cultivées autogames en Amérique centrale et du Sud.</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Sammelstellen[COLOR_REVERT] können nur in hügeliger [LINK=TERRAIN_PLAINS]Prärie[\LINK] errichtet werden. Die Ausbeute an [LINK=YIELD_FOOD]Nahrung[\LINK] und [LINK=YIELD_RED_PEPPER]Rotem Pfeffer[\LINK] läßt sich damit steigern.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Hintergrund :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Eine Sammelstelle ist ein Gebäude, dass der Zwischenlagerung von Gütern für ihren Weitertransport dient.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_COLLECTORS_DEPOT</Tag>
        <English>Collector's Depot</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Dépôt de collecte</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Sammeldepot</Text>
            <Gender>Neuter</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Collectors Depot</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Collectors Depot</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Spanish>
        <Russian>Хранилище сборщиков</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_COLLECTORS_DEPOT_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Collector's depots[COLOR_REVERT] are upgrades of [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_COLLECTORS_POST]collector's posts[\LINK]. The [LINK=YIELD_FOOD]food[\LINK] and [LINK=YIELD_RED_PEPPER]red pepper[\LINK] production on such tiles is increased.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Posts start small, just a location indicated by a post, then a shed and, in time, as big as business justifies.</English>
        <French>[BOLD]Stratégie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Les piments font partie de l'alimentation des Amériques depuis au moins 9 500 ans. Des traces archéologiques de domestication ont été trouvées dans le sud-ouest de l'équateur il y a plus de 6 000 ans. Le piment semble avoir été une des premières plantes cultivées autogames en Amérique centrale et du Sud.</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Sammeldepots[COLOR_REVERT] sind eine Erweiterung der [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_COLLECTORS_POST]Sammelstelle[\LINK]. Die Ausbeute an [LINK=YIELD_FOOD]Nahrung[\LINK] und [LINK=YIELD_RED_PEPPER]Rotem Pfeffer[\LINK] läßt sich damit steigern.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Hintergrund :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Eine Sammeldepot ist ein Gebäude, dass der Zwischenlagerung von Gütern für ihren Weitertransport dient.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_COLLECTORS_POST2</Tag>
        <English>Planter's Post</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Poste de planation</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Pflanzerlager</Text>
            <Gender>Neuter</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Planter's Post</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Planter's Post</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Spanish>
        <Russian>Лагерь плантаторов</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_COLLECTORS_POST2_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]The [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Planter's Post[COLOR_REVERT] can be built only on hilly [LINK=TERRAIN_SAVANNAH]savannah[\LINK] terrain. It gives a production bonus to [LINK=YIELD_COCA_LEAVES]coca leaves[\LINK] and [LINK=YIELD_FOOD]food[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Coca Leaves can refer to leaves of all four cultivated plants of the Coca family (Erythoxylaceae), native to western South America. In times both ancient and modern, these plants have been highly valued for their psychoactive properties, which can be experienced by chewing the leaves, making coca tea ("Mate de coca") out of it and, in modern times, chemically extracting the psychoactive agents to produce the drug cocaine.[PARAGRAPH:1]Coca leaves are an effective remedy against altitude sickness, and give its consumer a greater tolerance for hunger, thirst and fatigue. Apart from that, coca can be used as an anaesthetic and, due to its religious significance in Indigenous cultures, many other properties are ascribed to it, some of which are supported by modern science.[PARAGRAPH:1]Coca leaves have been used for medicinal, nutritional and religious purposes in the Andean region since prehistoric times, possibly as long as 8,000 years ago. It was during this long period that the ancestral coca plant was domesticated, after which it diversified into the four modern species.[PARAGRAPH:1]In the Incan empire the plant was thought to have a divine origin, and its leaves were used as offerings, as a method of divination similar to the reading of tea leaves in the Old World, and also as preparation for prayers or religious ceremonies. It eventually spread over a large area, from Colombia in the north to Chile in the south.[PARAGRAPH:1]After their conquest of the Incan Empire, the use of the leaf was tolerated by the Spanish because it enhanced the performance of forced labourers, but its religious use was prohibited, and the Spanish themselves were discouraged from using it. Though it was introduced in Europe in the 16th century, it never became popular until the 19th century when the first cocaine was produced.</English>
        <French>[BOLD]Stratégie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]La coca est une plante d'Amérique du Sud de la famille des Érythroxylacées. Elle joue un rôle important dans la culture andine, à travers ses utilisations rituelles ou médicinales des [LINK=YIELD_COCA_LEAVES]feuilles de coca[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:1]Elle pousse à l'état sauvage dans la cordillère des Andes à des altitudes variant de 300 à 2 000 m. Comme toutes les espèces du genre Erythroxylum, elle apprécie particulièrement les sols acides.[PARAGRAPH:1]C'est un fondement culturel pour l'Amérique latine - notamment les hauts plateaux andins - où son usage remonte à près de 5 000 ans. Du fait de ses différentes vertus, c'est une plante sacrée pour certains peuples amérindiens. Pour ces derniers, Mama Coca est la fille de Pachamama. Elle est ainsi utilisée traditionnellement de la Colombie jusqu'au Chili aussi bien pour ses vertus stimulantes que dans le cadre de cérémonies religieuses, elle aurait même servi de taxe d'imposition. Dans l'Empire inca, la coca issue de l'actuel Pérou (tupa coca) servait aux cérémonies religieuses et aux dignitaires alors que la coca issue de l'actuelle Bolivie (muma coca) servait aux fonctionnaires voire au peuple. Son usage est signalé par les conquérants espagnols dès le XVIe siècle qui en condamnent d'abord l'usage la qualifiant de « satanique » avant de l'encourager en constatant l'efficacité en termes de rentabilité sur les travailleurs. C'est Nicolas Monardés de Séville, un naturaliste espagnol qui en donne la première description dans les années 1580 même si la plante ne sera vraiment connue sur le plan scientifique qu'au XVIIIe siècle.</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Das [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Pflanzerlager[COLOR_REVERT] kann nur in hügeliger [LINK=TERRAIN_SAVANNAH]Savanne[\LINK] angelegt werden. Es gibt einen Bonus auf die Produktion von [LINK=YIELD_COCA_LEAVES]Cocablättern[\LINK] und [LINK=YIELD_FOOD]Nahrung[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Hintergrund :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Der Begriff [LINK=YIELD_COCA_LEAVES]Cocablätter[\LINK] bezieht sich meist auf Blätter der kultivierten Planzen aus der Familie der Cocapflanzen (Erythoxylaceae), welche im westlichen Teil Südamerikas beheimatet sind. Sowohl in der Antike als auch in der Moderne wurden diese Pflanzen sehr hoch geschätzt, da sie psychoaktive Substanzen beinhalten, die man durch das Kauen der Blätter oder durch den Konsum des daraus aufgebrühten Tees aufnehmen kann. Heutzutage wird aus diesen Blättern auch die Droge Kokain gewonnen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Weniger bedenkliche Anwirkungen der Cocablätter sind aber beispielsweise die Anwendung in geringeren Mengen als Mittel gegen Höhenkrankheit oder gegen Hungergefühle, Durstgefühle oder Müdigkeit. Ausserdem kann Coca auch zur Betäubung von Schmerzen verwendet werden.[PARAGRAPH:1]Cocablätter wurden jeher in den Regionen der Anden zu relgiösen, medizinischen und nahrungsergänzenden Zwecken eingesetzt. Wahrscheinlich sogar schon seit mehr als 8000 Jahren.[PARAGRAPH:1]In dieser langen Zeitperiode wurde die Cocapflanze irgendwann domestiziert. Heutzutage wird sie in vier unterschiedlichen Gattungen bzw. Unterarten gezüchtet. Die Inkas glaubten an einen göttlichen Ursprung der Planze und verwendete die Blätter als Opfergabe, aber auch als Mittel um die Zukunft vorherzusagen oder einfach nur um Gebete und Zeremonien vorzubereiten. Die Pflanze breitete sich schliesslich über ein sehr grosses Gebiet von Kolumbien im Norden bis nach Chile im Süden aus.[PARAGRAPH:1]Nach der Eroberung des Inkareiches wurde die Einnahme der Pflanze weiterhin von den Spaniern toleriert, da sie die Leistung der Zwangsarbeiter steigerte. Die religiöse Verwendung der Pflanze wurde aber verboten. Den Spaniern selbst wurde vom Konsum der Blätter abgeraten. Obwohl bereits im 16. Jahrhundert Cocablätter in Europa bekannt waren, erlangten diese dort zu dieser Zeit nie Beliebtheit. Dies änderte sich erst, als im 19. Jahrhundert Kokain entdeckt wurde.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_COLLECTORS_DEPOT2</Tag>
        <English>Planter's Depot:Planter's Depots</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Dépôt de coca:Dépôts de coca</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Pflanzerdepot:Pflanzerdepots</Text>
            <Gender>Neuter</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Planter's Depot:Planter's Depots</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Planter's Depot:Planter's Depots</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Spanish>
        <Russian>Хранилище плантаторов</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_COLLECTORS_DEPOT2_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]The [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Planter's Depot[COLOR_REVERT] is the upgrade of the [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_COLLECTORS_POST2]Planter Post[\LINK]. It gives a production bonus to [LINK=YIELD_COCA_LEAVES]coca leaves[\LINK] and [LINK=YIELD_FOOD]food[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Coca leaves can refer to leaves of all four cultivated plants of the Coca family (Erythoxylaceae) native to western South America. In times both ancient and modern, these plants have been valued for their psychoactive properties, which can be experienced by chewing the leaves, making coca tea ("Mate de coca") out of it and, in modern times, chemically extracting the psychoactive agents to produce the drug cocaine.[PARAGRAPH:1]Coca Leaves are an effective remedy against altitude sickness, giving the consumer a greater tolerance for hunger, thirst and fatigue. Apart from that, coca is an anaesthetic and, due to its religious significance in Indigenous cultures, many other properties are ascribed to it, some of which are supported by modern science.[PARAGRAPH:1]Coca leaves have been used for medicinal, nutritional and religious purposes in the Andean region since prehistoric times, possibly as long as 8,000 years ago.[PARAGRAPH:1]Over this long period the ancestral coca plant was domesticated and diversified into the four modern species. In the Incan empire the plant was thought to have a divine origin, and its leaves were used as offerings, as a method of divination, similar to the reading of tea leaves in the Old World, and also as preparation for prayers or religious ceremonies. It eventually spread over a large area, from Colombia in the north to Chile in the south.[PARAGRAPH:1]After the conquest of the Incan empire the use of the leaf was tolerated by the Spanish because it enhanced the performance of forced labourers, but its religious use was prohibited, and the Spanish themselves were discouraged from using it. Though it was introduced in Europe in the 16th century it never became popular until the 19th century when the first cocaine was produced.</English>
        <French>[BOLD]Stratégie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]La coca est une plante d'Amérique du Sud de la famille des Érythroxylacées. Elle joue un rôle important dans la culture andine, à travers ses utilisations rituelles ou médicinales des [LINK=YIELD_COCA_LEAVES]feuilles de coca[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:1]Elle pousse à l'état sauvage dans la cordillère des Andes à des altitudes variant de 300 à 2 000 m. Comme toutes les espèces du genre Erythroxylum, elle apprécie particulièrement les sols acides.[PARAGRAPH:1]C'est un fondement culturel pour l'Amérique latine - notamment les hauts plateaux andins - où son usage remonte à près de 5 000 ans. Du fait de ses différentes vertus, c'est une plante sacrée pour certains peuples amérindiens. Pour ces derniers, Mama Coca est la fille de Pachamama. Elle est ainsi utilisée traditionnellement de la Colombie jusqu'au Chili aussi bien pour ses vertus stimulantes que dans le cadre de cérémonies religieuses, elle aurait même servi de taxe d'imposition. Dans l'Empire inca, la coca issue de l'actuel Pérou (tupa coca) servait aux cérémonies religieuses et aux dignitaires alors que la coca issue de l'actuelle Bolivie (muma coca) servait aux fonctionnaires voire au peuple. Son usage est signalé par les conquérants espagnols dès le XVIe siècle qui en condamnent d'abord l'usage la qualifiant de « satanique » avant de l'encourager en constatant l'efficacité en termes de rentabilité sur les travailleurs. C'est Nicolas Monardés de Séville, un naturaliste espagnol qui en donne la première description dans les années 1580 même si la plante ne sera vraiment connue sur le plan scientifique qu'au XVIIIe siècle.</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Das [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Pflanzerdepot[COLOR_REVERT] ist die Erweiterung des [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_COLLECTORS_POST2]Pflanzerlagers[\LINK]. Es gibt einen Bonus auf die Produktion von [LINK=YIELD_COCA_LEAVES]Cocablättern[\LINK] und [LINK=YIELD_FOOD]Nahrung[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Hintergrund :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Der Begriff [LINK=YIELD_COCA_LEAVES]Cocablätter[\LINK] bezieht sich meist auf Blätter der kultivierten Planzen aus der Familie der Cocapflanzen (Erythoxylaceae), welche im westlichen Teil Südamerikas beheimatet sind. Sowohl in der Antike als auch in der Moderne wurden diese Pflanzen sehr hoch geschätzt, da sie psychoaktive Substanzen beinhalten, die man durch das Kauen der Blätter oder durch den Konsum des daraus aufgebrühten Tees aufnehmen kann. Heutzutage wird aus diesen Blättern auch die Droge Kokain gewonnen.[PARAGRAPH:1]Weniger bedenkliche Anwirkungen der Cocablätter sind aber beispielsweise die Anwendung in geringeren Mengen als Mittel gegen Höhenkrankheit oder gegen Hungergefühle, Durstgefühle oder Müdigkeit. Ausserdem kann Coca auch zur Betäubung von Schmerzen verwendet werden.[PARAGRAPH:1]Cocablätter wurden jeher in den Regionen der Anden zu relgiösen, medizinischen und nahrungsergänzenden Zwecken eingesetzt. Wahrscheinlich sogar schon seit mehr als 8000 Jahren.[PARAGRAPH:1]In dieser langen Zeitperiode wurde die Cocapflanze irgendwann domestiziert. Heutzutage wird sie in vier unterschiedlichen Gattungen bzw. Unterarten gezüchtet. Die Inkas glaubten an einen göttlichen Ursprung der Planze und verwendete die Blätter als Opfergabe, aber auch als Mittel um die Zukunft vorherzusagen oder einfach nur um Gebete und Zeremonien vorzubereiten. Die Pflanze breitete sich schliesslich über ein sehr grosses Gebiet von Kolumbien im Norden bis nach Chile im Süden aus.[PARAGRAPH:1]Nach der Eroberung des Inkareiches wurde die Einnahme der Pflanze weiterhin von den Spaniern toleriert, da sie die Leistung der Zwangsarbeiter steigerte. Die religiöse Verwendung der Pflanze wurde aber verboten. Den Spaniern selbst wurde vom Konsum der Blätter abgeraten. Obwohl bereits im 16. Jahrhundert Cocablätter in Europa bekannt waren, erlangten diese dort zu dieser Zeit nie Beliebtheit. Dies änderte sich erst, als im 19. Jahrhundert Kokain entdeckt wurde.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_FARM</Tag>
        <English>Farm</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Ferme</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Bauernhof</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Fattoria:Fattorie</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Granja:Granjas</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Spanish>
        <Russian>Ферма</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_FARM_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Farms[COLOR_REVERT] can be built on all flat, unvegetated [LINK=TERRAIN_GRASS]grassland[\LINK], [LINK=TERRAIN_PLAINS]prairie[\LINK], [LINK=TERRAIN_SAVANNAH]savannah[\LINK] and [LINK=TERRAIN_MARSH]marsh[\LINK] terrain. The production of [LINK=YIELD_FOOD]food[\LINK] and [LINK=YIELD_BARLEY]barley[\LINK] there is increased.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]A farm is an area of land, including structures, devoted to producing food (vegetables, grains, or livestock), fibres and, increasingly, fuel. It is the basic facility for food production. Farms may be owned and operated by a single individual, family, community, corporation or a company. A farm can be a holding of any size from a fraction of a hectare to several thousand hectares.</English>
        <French>[BOLD]Stratégie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Une ferme, ou exploitation agricole, est une entreprise (ou partie d'une entreprise) constituée en vue de la production agricole et caractérisée par une gestion unique et des moyens de production propres.</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Bauernhöfe[COLOR_REVERT] können auf flachem und unbewaldetem Terrain, wie z.B. [LINK=TERRAIN_GRASS]Grasland[\LINK], [LINK=TERRAIN_PLAINS]Prärie[\LINK], [LINK=TERRAIN_SAVANNAH]Savanne[\LINK] oder auch [LINK=TERRAIN_MARSH]Sumpf[\LINK], angelegt werden. Die Produktion von [LINK=YIELD_FOOD]Nahrung[\LINK] and [LINK=YIELD_BARLEY]Gerste[\LINK] ist dort erhöht.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Hintergrund :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Ein Bauernhof ist ein mit verschiedensten Gebäuden bebautes Stück Land, das von Anbauflächen umgeben ist und primär der Produktion von Nahrung dient. Oft in Form von Getreideanbau oder Viehzucht. Der Begriff 'Bauernhof' sagt allerdings noch nichts über die Grösse aus, die von mehreren Morgen bis hin zu mehreren Tausend Hektar variieren kann.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LARGE_FARM</Tag>
        <English>Large Farm</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Grande ferme</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Große Farm</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Large Farm</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Large Farm</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Spanish>
        <Russian>Большая ферма</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LARGE_FARM_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Large farms[COLOR_REVERT] are the upgrades of [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_FARM]farms[\LINK]. The production of [LINK=YIELD_FOOD]food[\LINK] and [LINK=YIELD_BARLEY]barley[\LINK] there is increased.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]A farm is an area of land, including structures, devoted to producing food (vegetables, grains, or livestock), fibres and, increasingly, fuel. It is the basic facility for food production. Farms may be owned and operated by a single individual, family, community, corporation or a company. A farm can be a holding of any size from a fraction of a hectare to several thousand hectares.</English>
        <French>[BOLD]Stratégie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Une ferme, ou exploitation agricole, est une entreprise (ou partie d'une entreprise) constituée en vue de la production agricole et caractérisée par une gestion unique et des moyens de production propres.</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Große Bauernhöfe[COLOR_REVERT] sind die Erweiterung des [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_FARM]Bauernhofes[\LINK]. Die Produktion von [LINK=YIELD_FOOD]Nahrung[\LINK] und [LINK=YIELD_BARLEY]Gerste[\LINK] ist dort erhöht.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Hintergrund :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Ein Bauernhof ist ein mit verschiedensten Gebäuden bebautes Stück Land, das von Anbauflächen umgeben ist und primär der Produktion von Nahrung dient. Oft in Form von Getreideanbau oder Viehzucht. Der Begriff 'Bauernhof' sagt allerdings noch nichts über die Grösse aus, die von mehreren Morgen bis hin zu mehreren Tausend Hektar variieren kann.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_WIND_MILL</Tag>
        <English>Windmill</English>
        <German>
            <Text>Windmühle</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
		<French>Moulin àvent</French>
        <Russian>Ветряк</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_WIND_MILL_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Windmills[COLOR_REVERT] on the map give a percentage bonus on the total production of [LINK=YIELD_FOOD]food[\LINK] in their city when worked by a citizen.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Historians debate whether Middle Eastern windmills triggered the first European windmills. In northwestern Europe the horizontal axis or vertical windmill (so called due to the plane of the movement of its sails) dates from the last quarter of the 12th century in the triangle of northern France, eastern England and Flanders. The earliest certain reference to a windmill in Europe (assumed to have been of the vertical type) dates from 1185 in Weedley, Yorkshire, although a number of earlier but less certainly dated twelfth century European sources referring to windmills have also been found. These earliest mills were used to grind cereals.</English>
		<French>[BOLD]Stratégie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Les moulins à vent[COLOR_REVERT] sur la carte donnent un pourcentage de bonus sur la production totale de [LINK=YIELD_FOOD]nourriture[\LINK] dans leur ville lorsqu'ils sont travaillés par un citoyen.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Contexte :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Les historiens débattent pour savoir si les moulins à vent du Moyen-Orient ont déclenché les premiers moulins à vent européens. En Europe du Nord-Ouest, le moulin à vent à axe horizontal ou vertical (appelé ainsi en raison du plan du mouvement de ses voiles) date du dernier quart du XIIe siècle dans le triangle du nord de la France, de l'est de l'Angleterre et des Flandres. La plus ancienne référence certaine à un moulin à vent en Europe (que l'on suppose avoir été de type vertical) date de 1185 à Weedley, dans le Yorkshire, bien qu'un certain nombre de sources européennes du XIIe siècle, plus anciennes mais dont la datation est moins certaine, fassent également référence à des moulins à vent. Ces premiers moulins étaient utilisés pour moudre des céréales.</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Windmühlen[COLOR_REVERT] auf der Karte geben einen prozentualen Bonus auf die gesamte Herstellung von [LINK=YIELD_FOOD]Nahrung[\LINK] der Stadt, wenn sie von einem Bürger in der Stadt bearbeitet werden.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Hintergrund :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Aufgrund des Fehlens von Beweisen, existiert eine Debatte unter Historikern, ob die Windmühlen des Mittleren Ostens die Entwicklung der europäischen Windmühlen ausgelöst haben. Im nordwestlichen Europa datieren horizontale oder vertikale Windmühlen vom Ende des 12. Jahrhunderts. Die ersten Windmühlen dienten ausschliesslich zum Mahlen von Getreide.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_IRON_MILL</Tag>
        <English>Iron Mill</English>
        <German>
            <Text>Eisenmühle</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
		<French>Bas-fourneaux</French>
        <Russian>Железная мельница</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_IRON_MILL_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Iron mills[COLOR_REVERT] on the map add a bonus percentage to the total production of [LINK=YIELD_TOOLS]tools[\LINK] in their city when they are worked by a citizen of the city.[NEWLINE]The iron mill can be built only on terrains that already have [LINK=YIELD_ORE]iron ore[\LINK]. It's like the situation for windmills on terrains where there's no food.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]An iron mill relies on a power source and gearing. It can increase the volume of forced air for smelting, or drive a mechanical process for grinding, rolling, or hammering. Such processes accelerate the production of many metal products.</English>
		<French>[BOLD]Stratégie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Les [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]bas-fourneaux[COLOR_REVERT] sur la carte ajoutent un pourcentage de bonus à la production totale de [LINK=YIELD_TOOLS]outils[\LINK] dans leur ville quand ils sont travaillés par un citoyen de la ville. [Ils ne peuvent être construits que sur les terrains qui possèdent déjà du [LINK=YIELD_ORE]minerai de fer[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Contexte :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Un moulin à fer repose sur une source d'énergie et un engrenage. Il peut augmenter le volume d'air forcé pour la fusion, ou entraîner un processus mécanique pour le broyage, le laminage ou le martelage. Ces processus accélèrent la production de nombreux produits métalliques.</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Eisenmühlen[COLOR_REVERT] auf der Karte geben, wenn sie von einem Bürger in der Stadt bearbeitet werden, einen prozentualen Bonus auf die gesamte Herstellung von [LINK=YIELD_TOOLS]Eisenwaren[\LINK] in der Stadt.[NEWLINE]Sie können nur auf Gelände errichtet werden, auf welchem bereits [LINK=YIELD_ORE]Eisenerz[\LINK] abgebaut werden kann.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Hintergrund :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Eine Wassermühle ist eine meist historische technische Anlage, die mittels einer Wasserkraftmaschine durch Wasserkraft angetrieben wird und die kinetische Energie des Wassers nutzt. Bei der Anlage kann es sich um eine Mühle im engeren Sinne handeln, in der etwas gemahlen bzw. zerkleinert wird (Mahlmühle), oder um eine Mühle, in der sonstige Maschinen angetrieben werden (z. B. Hammerwerk, Sägemühle, Schleifmühle, Papiermühle, Pumpwerk, Pochmühle). Für die Umsetzung der Wasserenergie in mechanische Arbeit kommen bei historischen Mühlen fast ausschließlich Wasserräder zum Einsatz; diese wurden in neuerer Zeit oft durch Wasserturbinen ersetzt. Das zum Antrieb nötige Wasser (Aufschlagwasser) wird normalerweise einem Fließgewässer entnommen. Je nach örtlichen Gegebenheiten sind zur Erhöhung der Fallhöhe und zur Speicherung von Wasser Teiche, Stauwehre, Kanäle oder andere Wasserbauwerke erforderlich, siehe dazu auch Schlacht (Wasserbauwerk).</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_SUPPLY_DEPOT</Tag>
        <English>Supply Depot</English>
        <German>
            <Text>Versorgungslager</Text>
            <Gender>Neuter</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
		<French>Dépôt d'approvisionnement</French>
        <Russian>Склад припасов</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_SUPPLY_DEPOT_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Supply depots[COLOR_REVERT] on the map give additional storage capacity to their city if when worked by a citizen.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Supply depots were first used by used by the military to store battlefield supplies so they could be distributed to units in the field. They would hold all types of materiel, except ammunition. In times of peace they offered added storage for the civilian community.</English>
		<French>[BOLD]Stratégie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Les dépôts d'approvisionnement[COLOR_REVERT] sur la carte donnent une capacité de stockage supplémentaire à leur ville s'ils sont travaillés par un citoyen.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Contexte :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Les dépôts d'approvisionnement ont d'abord été utilisés par les militaires pour stocker les fournitures du champ de bataille afin qu'elles puissent être distribuées aux unités sur le terrain. Ils pouvaient contenir tous les types de matériel, à l'exception des munitions. En temps de paix, ils offraient un stockage supplémentaire pour la communauté civile.</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Versorgungslager[COLOR_REVERT] auf der Karte geben ihrer Stadt zusätzliche Lagerkapazität, wenn sie von einem Bürger in der Stadt bearbeitet werden.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Hintergrund :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Versorgungslager wurden zunächst vom Militär genutzt, um Vorräte auf dem Schlachtfeld zu lagern, damit sie an die Einheiten vor Ort verteilt werden konnten. Sie enthielten alle Arten von Material, außer Munition. In Friedenszeiten dienten sie als zusätzliche Lager für die Zivilbevölkerung.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LARGE_SUPPLY_DEPOT</Tag>
        <English>Large Supply Depot</English>
        <German>
            <Text>Großes Versorgungslager</Text>
            <Gender>Neuter</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
		<French>Grand dépôt d'approvisionnement</French>
        <Russian>Большой склад припасов</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LARGE_SUPPLY_DEPOT_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Supply depots[COLOR_REVERT] on the map give extra storage capacity to their city when worked by a citizen.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Supply depots were first used by used by the military to store battlefield supplies so they could be distributed to units in the field. They would hold all types of materiel, except ammunition. In times of peace they offered added storage for the civilian community.</English>
		<French>[BOLD]Stratégie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Les dépôts d'approvisionnement[COLOR_REVERT] sur la carte donnent une capacité de stockage supplémentaire à leur ville lorsqu'ils sont utilisés par un citoyen.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Contexte :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Les dépôts d'approvisionnement ont d'abord été utilisés par les militaires pour stocker les fournitures du champ de bataille afin qu'elles puissent être distribuées aux unités sur le terrain. Ils pouvaient contenir tous les types de matériel, à l'exception des munitions. En temps de paix, ils offraient un stockage supplémentaire pour la communauté civile.</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Versorgungslager[COLOR_REVERT] auf der Karte geben ihrer Stadt zusätzliche Lagerkapazität, wenn sie von einem Bürger in der Stadt bearbeitet werden.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Hintergrund :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Versorgungslager wurden zunächst vom Militär genutzt, um Vorräte auf dem Schlachtfeld zu lagern, damit sie an die Einheiten vor Ort verteilt werden konnten. Sie enthielten alle Arten von Material, außer Munition. In Friedenszeiten dienten sie als zusätzliche Lager für die Zivilbevölkerung.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_CANAL</Tag>
        <English>Canal</English>
        <German>
            <Text>Kanal</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
		<French>Canal</French>
        <Russian>Канал</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_CANAL_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Canals[COLOR_REVERT] allow small ships to pass throught and to connect to water plots or to connect a coastal city to a nearby lake or large river. They may however only be one plot long.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]DThe Panama Canal (Spanish: Canal de Panamá) is an artificial 82 km (51 mi) waterway in Panama that connects the Atlantic Ocean with the Pacific Ocean and divides North and South America. The canal cuts across the Isthmus of Panama and is a conduit for maritime trade.</English>
		<French>[BOLD]Stratégie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Les canaux[COLOR_REVERT] permettent aux petits navires de passer à travers eux pour se connecter à des parcelles d'eau ou pour donner à une ville intérieure un accès à l'océan, à un lac ou à une grande rivière. Ils ne peuvent cependant avoir qu'une seule parcelle de long.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Contexte :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]DLe canal de Panama (en espagnol : Canal de Panamá) est une voie navigable artificielle de 82 km (51 mi) au Panama qui relie l'océan Atlantique à l'océan Pacifique et divise l'Amérique du Nord et du Sud. Le canal traverse l'isthme de Panama et sert de voie d'accès au commerce maritime.</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Kanäle[COLOR_REVERT] erlauben es kleinen Schiffen durch sie hindurch zu fahren und somit zwei Gewässer zu verbinden oder eine Stadt an der Küste einen Zugang zu einem nahen See oder einem größeren Fluss zu geben. Sie dürfen nur ein Feld länge sein.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Hintergrund :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]er Panamakanal ist eine künstliche, rund 82 Kilometer lange Wasserstraße mit einer Scheitelhaltung von 26 Metern, die die Landenge von Panama in Mittelamerika durchschneidet, den Atlantik mit dem Pazifik für die Schifffahrt verbindet und ihr damit die Fahrt um das Kap Hoorn oder durch die Magellanstraße an der Südspitze Südamerikas erspart.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_FORT</Tag>
        <English>Fort</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Fort</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Fort</Text>
            <Gender>Neuter</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Fort</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Fuerte</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Spanish>
        <Russian>Форт</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_FORT_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Forts[COLOR_REVERT] only operate as long as a [LINK=CONCEPT_MILITARY_UNITS]military unit[\LINK] is stationed inside. To manage this, [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]fortify[COLOR_REVERT] a military unit on the plot where the fort is located.[PARAGRAPH:2]For more information on their benefits, see [LINK=CONCEPT_FORTS]Forts[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Fortifications are military constructions designed for defence in warfare. Humans have made defensive works for many thousands of years, creating increasingly complex designs. The term is derived from the Latin fortis (strong) and facere (to make).</English>
        <French>[BOLD]Stratégie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]La fortification (du latin fortificatio « action de fortifier ») est l'art militaire de renforcer une position ou un lieu par des ouvrages de défense en prévision de leur éventuelle attaque par un ennemi hostile. Par extension, la fortification désigne ces ouvrages de défense eux-mêmes.</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Forts[COLOR_REVERT] sind nur aktiv, wenn eine [LINK=CONCEPT_MILITARY_UNITS]Militäreinheit[\LINK] darin stationiert ist. Dafür muss diese Einheit in dem Fort [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]befestigt[COLOR_REVERT] werden.[PARAGRAPH:2]Für weitere Informationen siehe [LINK=CONCEPT_FORTS]Forts[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Hintergrund :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Befestigungen sind Konstruktionen mit militärischen Zweck und dienen der Verteidigung gegen Feinde. Defensive Anlagen wurden von der Menschheit schon seit Jahrtausenden genutzt. Der Begriff 'Fort' leitet sich vom Lateinischen Wort 'fortis' ab, welches übersetzt 'stark' bedeutet.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LARGE_FORT</Tag>
        <English>Large Fort</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Grand Fort</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Großes Fort</Text>
            <Gender>Neuter</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Large Fort</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Large Fort</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Spanish>
        <Russian>Большой форт</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LARGE_FORT_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Large Forts[COLOR_REVERT], the upgrades of [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_FORT]forts[\LINK], only function only as long as a [LINK=CONCEPT_MILITARY_UNITS]military unit[\LINK] is stationed inside. To manage this, [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]fortify[COLOR_REVERT] a military unit on the plot with the large fort.[PARAGRAPH:2]For more information on using large forts, see [LINK=CONCEPT_FORTS]Forts[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Fortifications are military constructions for defence in warfare. People have made defensive works for many thousands of years, in increasingly complex designs. The term is derived from the Latin fortis (strong) and facere (to make).</English>
        <French>[BOLD]Stratégie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]La fortification (du latin fortificatio « action de fortifier ») est l'art militaire de renforcer une position ou un lieu par des ouvrages de défense en prévision de leur éventuelle attaque par un ennemi hostile. Par extension, la fortification désigne ces ouvrages de défense eux-mêmes.</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Grosse Forts[COLOR_REVERT], die Ausbaustufe der [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_FORT]Forts[\LINK], sind nur aktiv, wenn eine [LINK=CONCEPT_MILITARY_UNITS]Militäreinheit[\LINK] darin stationiert ist. Dafür muss diese Einheit in dem Fort [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]befestigt[COLOR_REVERT] werden.[PARAGRAPH:2]Für weitere Informationen siehe [LINK=CONCEPT_FORTS]Forts[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Hintergrund :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Befestigungen sind Konstruktionen mit militärischen Zweck und dienen der Verteidigung gegen Feinde. Defensive Anlagen wurden von der Menschheit schon seit Jahrtausenden genutzt. Der Begriff 'Fort' leitet sich vom Lateinischen Wort 'fortis' ab, welches übersetzt 'stark' bedeutet.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_GOODY_HUT</Tag>
        <English>TXT_KEY_GOODY_BURIAL_GROUNDS</English>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_GOODY_HUT_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]In [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]burial grounds[COLOR_REVERT] you can often find treasures, useful information or even units. Beware though: Natives regard them as sacred. Like Europeans they are offended and disgusted by grave robbers. Only [LINK=UNIT_SCOUT]seasoned scouts[\LINK] are furtive enough to evade their ire.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]After funeral rites native dead may be put to rest on raised platforms on a burial ground, often with their possessions to accompany them into the hereafter, thus the attraction to scouts. A cemetery is more commonly where European people are interred.[PARAGRAPH:1]In the colonies settlers rarely buried their wealth so those graves would be looted mainly for medical training, as described by Charles Dickens in "A Tale of Two Cities".</English>
        <French>[BOLD]Stratégie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Un cimetière est un endroit spécifiquement dédié au repos des personnes décédés. Ces dernières sont généralement enterrées ou incinérées.</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]In [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Begräbnisstätte[COLOR_REVERT] lassen sich Schätze, nützliche Informationen oder sogar Einheiten finden. Vorsicht ist geboten, denn die Eingeborenen betrachten diese oftmals als heilig. Wie Europäer auch verachten sie Grabräuber und sind schnell beleidigt durch deren Tun. Lediglich [LINK=UNIT_SCOUT]Routinierte Späher[\LINK] sind erfahren - und heimlich - genug, um ihrem Zorn zu entgehen.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Hintergrund :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Eine [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Begräbnisstätte[COLOR_REVERT] oder ein Friedhof sind Orte, an denen Verstorbene begraben werden. In manchen Kulturen war und ist es üblich, den Toten reiche Grabbeigaben mitzugeben. Sie gelten in den meisten Kulturen als geheiligte Orte.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_GOODY_HUT2</Tag>
        <English>Ancient Ruins</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Ruines antiques</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>Antike Ruinen</German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Antiche rovine</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Ruinas antiguas</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Spanish>
        <Russian>Древние руины</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_GOODY_HUT2_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]In [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Ancient ruins[COLOR_REVERT] you may find treasures, useful information or even units. Beware though: Natives regard them as sacred. Like Europeans they are offended and disgusted by plunderers. Only [LINK=UNIT_SCOUT]seasoned scouts[\LINK] are furtive enough to evade their ire.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Ruins are the remains of human architecture: structures once complete that have fallen into a state of disrepair. Natural disaster, war and depopulation are the most common causes, with many structures deteriorating over time from weather and scavenging.</English>
        <French>[BOLD]Stratégie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Les ruines sont les restes d'architecture humaine passée : des structures autrefois complètes qui, par abandon, se sont désagrégés pour atteindre un état difficilement réparable. Les désastres naturels, la guerre ou le dépeuplement sont les causes principales de tels abandons. Les conditions climatiques et le pillage sont les principales causes de délabrement de ces structures.</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]In [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Antiken Ruinen[COLOR_REVERT] lassen sich Schätze, nützliche Informationen oder sogar Einheiten finden. Vorsicht ist geboten, denn die Eingeborenen betrachten diese oftmals als heilig. Wie Europäer auch verachten sie Plünderer und sind schnell beleidigt durch deren Tun. Lediglich [LINK=UNIT_SCOUT]Routinierte Späher[\LINK] sind erfahren - und heimlich - genug, um ihrem Zorn zu entgehen.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Hintergrund :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Ruinen sind die Reste menschlicher Architektur: Strukturen, die einst vollständig waren, dann aber durch den Einfluss der Umwelt, wie Pflanzen, Regen oder Wind, über die Zeit zerfielen. Gründe für die Verwahrlosung können Kriege, Katastrophen, Krankheiten und vieles mehr gewesen sein. In diesen Ruinen können sich manchmal noch wertvolle Dinge befinden.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_GOODY_HUT3</Tag>
        <English>Ship Wreckage</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Débris d'épave</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Treibgut</Text>
            <Gender>Neuter</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Ship Wreckage</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Ship Wreckage</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Spanish>
        <Russian>Обломки корабля</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_GOODY_HUT3_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Shipwrecks[COLOR_REVERT] indicate ships that sank or lost something during a storm. In any case, the flotsam may still contain valuable items. Maps or gold might be found among the wreckage.</English>
        <French>Les [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]débris d'épaves[COLOR_REVERT] indiquent qu'il devait y avoir un navire à proximité. Soit il a coulé, soit il a perdu quelque chose dans la tempête. Dans tous les cas, les débris peuvent contenir des objets de valeur. Des cartes ou de l'or peuvent être trouvés parmi les épaves.</French>
        <German>[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Treibgut[COLOR_REVERT] zeugt davon, dass sich ganz in der Nähe ein Schiff befunden haben muss. Entweder ist es gesunken oder es hat im Sturm etwas verloren. Jedenfalls kann man in dem Treibgut vielleicht noch wertvolle Dinge finden.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_GOODY_HUT4</Tag>
        <English>Ship Wreck</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Épave échouée</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Schiffswrack</Text>
            <Gender>Neuter</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Ship Wreck</Text>
            <Gender>Neutral</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Ship Wreck</Text>
            <Gender>Neutral</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Spanish>
        <Russian>Кораблекрушение</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_GOODY_HUT4_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Shipwrecks[COLOR_REVERT] are scattered across the ocean. Maps, gold and even survivors from the crew might be found among the wreckage.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]A shipwreck is what remains of a destroyed ship. Shipwrecks are either beached on land or resting on the sea floor. Whatever the cause, a sunken ship or a wrecked ship can be looted or recovered. The United Nations estimates that there are more than three million sunken shipwrecks.</English>
        <French>Dans le domaine maritime, une épave est ce qui reste d'un navire en mer (épave dérivante), sur le rivage ou au fond de la mer, après qu'il a été abandonné, qu'il s'est échoué ou a coulé, à la suite d'un « événement de mer » (naufrage, avarie, collision, erreur de navigation, etc.) ou d'un sabordage. L' UNESCO évalue à 3 millions leur nombre total, mais dont à peine un millier seraient rentables économiquement.</French>
        <German>Unter einem [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Schiffswrack[COLOR_REVERT] versteht man die Überreste eines verunglückten Schiffes. Manchmal kann man darin noch wertvolle Dinge finden. Ist man schnell Genug am Ort des Unglücks, gelingt es vielleicht sogar Überlebende zu retten.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_GOODY_HUT5</Tag>
        <English>Campfire</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Feu de camp</Text>
            <Gender>Neutral</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Lagerfeuer</Text>
            <Gender>Neuter</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Fuoco da campo</Text>
            <Gender>Neutral</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Fogata</Text>
            <Gender>Neutral</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Spanish>
        <Russian>Лагерь с костром</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_GOODY_HUT5_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>A [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]campfire[COLOR_REVERT] shows where people spent the night. If the fire is still warm, they may still be nearby. Are they friend or foe? It's worth looking. Maybe they're abandoned settlers who want to join us.</English>
        <French>A [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT] Camp Fire[COLOR_REVERT] testifies to the fact that people must have stayed at night. If the fire is still warm, they may still be nearby. Are they friend or foe? In any case, it is worth looking. Maybe they are abandoned settlers who want to join us.</French>
        <German>Ein [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Lagerfeuer[COLOR_REVERT] zeugt davon, dass sich Menschen in der Näche aufgehalten haben müssen. Ist das Feuer noch warm, sind sie vielleicht noch in der Nähe. Sind sie Freund oder Feind? Es lohnt sich auf jeden Fall nachzusehen. Vielleicht sind es zurückgelassene Siedler, die sich uns anschließen möchten.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_GOODY_HUT6</Tag>
        <English>Raiders' Camp</English>
        <German>
            <Text>Verbrecherversteck</Text>
            <Gender>Neuter</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
		<French>Camps des maraudeurs</French>
        <Russian>Лагерь разбойников</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_GOODY_HUT6_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Raiders' camps[COLOR_REVERT] are goodies that are protected. When you defeat the outlaws you can take their riches.</English>
		<French>Les [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]camps des maraudeurs[COLOR_REVERT] sont des goodies protégés par des hors-la-loi. Une fois battus, vous pouvez confisquer leurs biens.</French>
        <German>[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Verbrecherversteck[COLOR_REVERT] sind Goodies, die bewacht werden. Wenn die Kriminellen besiegt wurden, gehören Ihnen ihre Schätze.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_GOODY_HUT7</Tag>
        <English>Animal Lair</English>
        <French>Antre d'animaux</French>
		<German>
            <Text>Tierversteck</Text>
            <Gender>Neuter</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Russian>Логово животных</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_GOODY_HUT7_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Animal lairs[COLOR_REVERT] are goodies protected by wild animals. Maybe there's somthing valuable in there?</English>
		<French>[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Les repaires d'animaux [COLOR_REVERT] sont des lieux protégés par des animaux sauvages. Peut-être qu'il y a quelque chose de précieux là-dedans?</French>
        <German>[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Tierverstecke[COLOR_REVERT] sind Goodies, die durch wilde Tiere bewacht werden. Vielleicht findet sich darin ja etwas Wertvolles?</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_GOODY_HUT8</Tag>
        <English>Hostile Native Village</English>
        <French>Village indigène hostile</French>
		<German>
            <Text>Feindliches Ureinwohnerdorf</Text>
            <Gender>Neuter</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Russian>Деревня враждебных индейцев</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_GOODY_HUT8_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Hostile Native villages[COLOR_REVERT] are goodies that are protected by hostile Natives. When you defeat the hostile Natives you can seize their riches and secrets.</English>
		<French>[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Les villages d'indigènes hostiles[COLOR_REVERT] sont des biens protégés par des indigènes hostiles. Lorsque vous vainquez les indigènes hostiles, vous pouvez vous emparer de leurs richesses et de leurs secrets.</French>
        <German>[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Feindliche Ureinwohnerdörfer[COLOR_REVERT] sind Goodies, die durch feindselige Ureinwohner bewacht werden. Sobald Sie die feindlichen Ureinwohner besiegt haben, gehören Ihnen ihre Schätze.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LAND_WORKED</Tag>
        <English>Land worked</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Terre travaillée</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Bearbeitetes Land</Text>
            <Gender>Neuter</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Terreno bonificato:Terreni bonificati</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Tierra trabajada:Tierras trabajadas</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LAND_WORKED_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>Land is the part of the planet not covered by water - a terrestrial ecoregion, based on soil instead of water.</English>
        <French>La terre peut faire référence à : la partie du sol qui n'est pas couverte par l'eau. Il s'agit d'une écorégion terrestre basée sur un sol ferme et non sur de l'eau.</French>
        <German>Der Begriff 'Land' kann sich auf den Teil der Erde beziehen, der nicht von Wasser überzogen ist bzw. ein ökologisches System, dass auf Grundboden basiert anstatt auf Wasser.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LODGE</Tag>
        <English>Lodge</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Abri:Abris</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>Holzfällerhütte</German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Capanno</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Pabellón:Pabellones</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Spanish>
        <Russian>Домик лесорубов</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LODGE_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Lodges[COLOR_REVERT] can be built in [LINK=FEATURE_FOREST]forests[\LINK], [LINK=FEATURE_LIGHT_FOREST]light forests[\LINK], [LINK=FEATURE_FOREST_TUNDRA]taiga[\LINK] and [LINK=FEATURE_JUNGLE]Jungle[\LINK]. The production of [LINK=YIELD_LUMBER]lumber[\LINK] and [LINK=YIELD_VALUABLE_WOOD]valuable wood[\LINK] there is increased.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]At first a lodge will be a small, makeshift shelter of boughs, poles, skins, earth or rough boards; but over time it can become permanent, even luxurious.</English>
        <French>[BOLD]Stratégie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Un abri est un logement temporaire dont a besoin pour répondre aux besoins naturels de sécurité, d'hygiène et de confort. Il peut prendre la forme d'une cabine ou d'une hutte.</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Holzfällerhütten[COLOR_REVERT] können im [LINK=FEATURE_FOREST]Wald[\LINK], [LINK=FEATURE_LIGHT_FOREST]Buschland[\LINK], in der [LINK=FEATURE_FOREST_TUNDRA]Taiga[\LINK] und im [LINK=FEATURE_JUNGLE]Dschungel[\LINK] gebaut werden. Die Produktion von [LINK=YIELD_LUMBER]Holz[\LINK] und [LINK=YIELD_VALUABLE_WOOD]Edelholz[\LINK] ist dort erhöht.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Hintergrund :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Am Anfang wird eine Holzfällerhütte ein kleiner, behelfsmäßiger Unterschlupf aus Ästen, Stangen, Fellen, Erde oder groben Brettern sein; aber mit der Zeit kann sie dauerhaft, sogar luxuriös werden.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LUMBERJACK_CAMP</Tag>
        <English>Lumberjack Camp</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Camp de bûcherons</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Holzfällercamp</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Lumberjack Camp</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Lumberjack Camp</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Spanish>
        <Russian>Лагерь лесорубов</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LUMBERJACK_CAMP_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Lumberjack camps[COLOR_REVERT] are the upgrades of [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_LODGE]lodges[\LINK], that can be built in [LINK=FEATURE_FOREST]forests[\LINK], [LINK=FEATURE_LIGHT_FOREST]light forests[\LINK], [LINK=FEATURE_FOREST_TUNDRA]taiga[\LINK] and [LINK=FEATURE_JUNGLE]jungle[\LINK]. The production of [LINK=YIELD_LUMBER]lumber[\LINK] and [LINK=YIELD_VALUABLE_WOOD]valuable wood[\LINK] there is increased.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]At first a lodge will be a small, makeshift shelter of boughs, poles, skins, earth or rough boards. Over time it evolves into a lumberjack camp.[PARAGRAPH:1]Lumberjacks are known for their music and cameraderie at the end of a hard day's work.</English>
        <French>[BOLD]Stratégie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Un abri est un logement temporaire dont a besoin pour répondre aux besoins naturels de sécurité, d'hygiène et de confort. Il peut prendre la forme d'une cabine ou d'une hutte.</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Holzfällercamps[COLOR_REVERT] sind die höhere Stufe einer [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_LODGE]Holzfällerhütte[\LINK]. Diese können in [LINK=FEATURE_FOREST]Wäldern[\LINK], [LINK=FEATURE_LIGHT_FOREST]Buschland[\LINK], [LINK=FEATURE_FOREST_TUNDRA]Taiga[\LINK] und [LINK=FEATURE_JUNGLE]Dschungel[\LINK] errichtet werden. Die Produktion von [LINK=YIELD_LUMBER]Holz[\LINK] und [LINK=YIELD_VALUABLE_WOOD]Edelholz[\LINK] erhöht sich deutlich.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Hintergrund :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Zunächst wird eine Holzfällerhütte ein kleiner, behelfsmäßiger Unterstand aus Ästen, Stangen, Fellen, Erde oder groben Brettern sein. Im Lauf der Zeit entwickelt es sich zu einem Holzfällerlager.[PARAGRAPH:1]Holzfäller sind bekannt für ihre Kameradschaft und Musik am Ende eines harten Arbeitstages.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LUMBERMILL</Tag>
        <English>Sawmill</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Scierie en forêt</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Sägewerk</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Sawmill</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Sawmill</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Spanish>
        <Russian>Лесопилка</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LUMBERMILL_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Sawmills[COLOR_REVERT] give a percentage bonus on [LINK=YIELD_HAMMERS]hammer[\LINK] production in their city when worked by a citizen.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Lumberjacks are known for their music and cameraderie at the end of a hard day's work.</English>
		<French>[BOLD]Stratégie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Les scieries[COLOR_REVERT] donnent un pourcentage de bonus sur la production de [LINK=YIELD_HAMMERS]marteaux[\LINK] dans leur ville lorsqu'ils sont travaillés par un citoyen. [PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Contexte :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Les bûcherons sont connus pour leur musique et leur camaraderie à la fin d'une dure journée de travail.</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Sägewerk[COLOR_REVERT] auf der Karte geben einen prozentualen Bonus auf die gesamte [LINK=YIELD_HAMMERS]Bauproduktion[\LINK] der Stadt, wenn sie von einem Bürger in der Stadt bearbeitet werden.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Hintergrund :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Holzfäller sind bekannt für ihre Kameradschaft und Musik am Ende eines harten Arbeitstages</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_MINE</Tag>
        <English>Mine</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Mine</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Mine</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Miniera:Miniere</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Mina:Minas</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Spanish>
        <Russian>Шахта</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_MINE_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Mines[COLOR_REVERT] can be built on all unvegetated hills and peaks, as well as on [LINK=TERRAIN_DESERT]desert[\LINK] terrain. Mines increase the production of [LINK=YIELD_ORE]ore[\LINK], [LINK=YIELD_RAW_SALT]rock salt[\LINK], [LINK=YIELD_SILVER]silver[\LINK], [LINK=YIELD_GEMS]gems[\LINK] and [LINK=YIELD_GOLD]gold[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]A pick and shovel can start a mine. If the site is right and the wealth is there, that's good news for the owners. However the engineering challenges can become complex. Workers' safety will be balanced against the need for minerals.</English>
        <French>[BOLD]Stratégie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Une mine est un gisement exploité de matériaux (par exemple d'or, d'argent, de diamants, de fer, de sel, etc.). Elle peut être à ciel ouvert ou souterraine.</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Minen[COLOR_REVERT] können auf allen unbewaldeten Hügeln und Bergen, sowie in der [LINK=TERRAIN_DESERT]Wüste[\LINK] angelegt werden. Minen steigern die Förderung von [LINK=YIELD_ORE]Eisenerz[\LINK], [LINK=YIELD_RAW_SALT]Steinsalz[\LINK], [LINK=YIELD_SILVER]Silber[\LINK], [LINK=YIELD_GEMS]Edelsteinen[\LINK] und [LINK=YIELD_GOLD]Gold[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Hintergrund :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Der Begriff 'Miene' bezieht sich auf eine Abbaufläche für Metalle, Edelsteine oder Mineralien. Eine Miene kann sowohl oberirdisch, wie auch unterirdisch angelegt sein.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_DEEP_MINE</Tag>
        <English>Large Mine</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Grande mine</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Große Mine</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Large Mine</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Large Mine</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Spanish>
        <Russian>Большая шахта</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_DEEP_MINE_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Large mines[COLOR_REVERT] are the upgrades of [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_MINE]mines[\LINK]. They increase the production of [LINK=YIELD_ORE]ore[\LINK], [LINK=YIELD_RAW_SALT]rock salt[\LINK], [LINK=YIELD_SILVER]silver[\LINK], [LINK=YIELD_GEMS]gems[\LINK] and [LINK=YIELD_GOLD]gold[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]A pick and shovel can start a mine. If the site is right and the wealth is there, that's good news for the owners. However engineering challenges often become complex. Workers' lives can be be balanced against the need for minerals.</English>
        <French>[BOLD]Stratégie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Une mine est un gisement exploité de matériaux (par exemple d'or, d'argent, de diamants, de fer, de sel, etc.). Elle peut être à ciel ouvert ou souterraine.</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Die [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Große Mine[COLOR_REVERT] ist eine Erweiterung der [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_MINE]Mine[\LINK]. Sie steigert die Förderung von [LINK=YIELD_ORE]Eisenerz[\LINK], [LINK=YIELD_RAW_SALT]Steinsalz[\LINK], [LINK=YIELD_SILVER]Silber[\LINK], [LINK=YIELD_GEMS]Edelsteinen[\LINK] und [LINK=YIELD_GOLD]Gold[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Hintergrund :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Der Begriff 'Miene' bezieht sich auf eine Abbaufläche für Metalle, Edelsteine oder Mineralien. Eine Miene kann sowohl oberirdisch, wie auch unterirdisch angelegt sein.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_MONASTERY</Tag>
        <English>Monastery</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Monastère</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Kloster</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Monastery</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Monastery</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Spanish>
        <Russian>Монастырь</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_MONASTERY_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Monasteries[COLOR_REVERT] only function as long as they are inhabited by monks. A colonist with the [LINK=PROFESSION_MISSIONARY]missionary[\LINK] profession needs to be fortified in the monastery. Employing [LINK=UNIT_CHRISTIAN_MISSIONARY]Jesuit missionaries[\LINK] or [LINK=UNIT_PREACHER]firebrand preachers[\LINK] increases the effectiveness of the monastery.[PARAGRAPH:2]For more information on managing monasteries, see [LINK=CONCEPT_MONASTERIES]Monasteries[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]"Monastery" denotes the building, or complex of buildings, comprising the domestic quarters and workplace(s) of monastics, whether monks or nuns, and whether living in community or alone (hermits).[PARAGRAPH:1]The monastery includes a place reserved for prayer which may be a chapel, church or temple, and may also serve as an oratory. A monastery complex can include a church, dormitory, cloister, refectory, library, balneary and infirmary.[PARAGRAPH:1]Depending on the location, the monastic order and the occupation of its inhabitants, the complex may also have buildings to aid self-sufficiency and community service. These may include a hospice, a school, and agricultural and manufacturing buildings such as a barn, a forge or a brewery.</English>
        <French>[BOLD]Stratégie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Un monastère (du grec monos, « seul ») est un ensemble de bâtiments où habite une communauté religieuse de moines ou de moniales. On parle également d'abbaye s'il est dirigé par un abbé ou de prieuré s'il est dépendant ou de moindre importance. Souvent, le prieuré est dépendant d'une abbaye ou monastère. Les monastères des ordres militaires du Moyen âge sont appelés commanderies. On parle de couvent pour les résidences de Franciscains et Dominicains, ainsi que d'autres ordres, tandis que les Bénédictins ou Prémontrés habitent des abbayes ou prieurés.</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Ein [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Kloster[COLOR_REVERT] ist nur aktiv, wenn Mönche darin leben. Dafür muss ein Kolonist im Beruf [LINK=PROFESSION_MISSIONARY]Missionar[\LINK] im Kloster befestigt werden. Wird ein [LINK=UNIT_CHRISTIAN_MISSIONARY]Jesuitenmissionar[\LINK] oder ein [LINK=UNIT_CHRISTIAN_MISSIONARY]Evangelist[\LINK] eingesetzt, erhöht sich die Effektivität des Klosters.[PARAGRAPH:2]Für weitere Informationen siehe [LINK=CONCEPT_MONASTERIES]Klöster[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Hintergrund :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Der Begriff 'Kloster' steht für ein Gebäude oder einen Komplex mehrerer Gebäude, welches üblicherweise von Mönchen oder Nonnen bewohnt wird. Ein Kloster beinhaltet üblicherweise Gebetsstellen, wie eine Kapelle, eine Kirche oder einen Tempel, aber auch Räume oder Gebäude für den Alltag und die Selbstversorgung, wie einen Schlafsaal, Speisesaal, Werkstellen, Scheunen, Schmieden und manchmal Brauereien. In manchen größeren Klöstern findet man auch Büchereien, Schulen oder Krankenhäuser, die dann auch oft den umliegenden Gemeinden Dienste anbieten.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LARGE_MONASTERY</Tag>
        <English>Large Monastery</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Grand Monastère</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Großes Kloster</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Large Monastery</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Large Monastery</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Spanish>
        <Russian>Большой монастырь</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LARGE_MONASTERY_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]The [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]large monastery[COLOR_REVERT] is the upgrade of the [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_MONASTERY]monastery[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:1]Monasteries work only while they're inhabited by monks. A colonist with the [LINK=PROFESSION_MISSIONARY]missionary[\LINK] profession needs to be fortified on the plot with the monastery. Employing [LINK=UNIT_CHRISTIAN_MISSIONARY]Jesuit missionaries[\LINK] or [LINK=UNIT_PREACHER]firebrand preachers[\LINK] increases the effectiveness of the monastery.[PARAGRAPH:2]For more information on monasteries, see [LINK=CONCEPT_MONASTERIES]Monasteries[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]"Monastery" denotes the building, or complex of buildings, comprising the domestic quarters of monastics, whether monks or nuns, and whether living in community or alone (hermits). The monastery generally includes a place reserved for prayer which may be a chapel, church or temple, and may also serve as an oratory.[PARAGRAPH:1]A monastery complex typically has buildings which include a church, dormitory, cloister, refectory, library, balneary and infirmary. Depending on the location, the monastic order and the occupation of its inhabitants, the complex may also include buildings to aid self-sufficiency and service to the community. These could include a hospice, a school, and agricultural and manufacturing buildings such as a barn, forge or brewery.</English>
        <French>[BOLD]Stratégie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Un monastère (du grec monos, « seul ») est un ensemble de bâtiments où habite une communauté religieuse de moines ou de moniales. On parle également d'abbaye s'il est dirigé par un abbé ou de prieuré s'il est dépendant ou de moindre importance. Souvent, le prieuré est dépendant d'une abbaye ou monastère. Les monastères des ordres militaires du Moyen âge sont appelés commanderies. On parle de couvent pour les résidences de Franciscains et Dominicains, ainsi que d'autres ordres, tandis que les Bénédictins ou Prémontrés habitent des abbayes ou prieurés.</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Das [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Große Kloster[COLOR_REVERT] ist die Erweiterung des [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_MONASTERY]Klosters[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:1]Ein [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Kloster[COLOR_REVERT] ist nur aktiv, wenn Mönche darin leben. Dafür muss ein Kolonist im Beruf [LINK=PROFESSION_MISSIONARY]Missionar[\LINK] im Kloster befestigt werden. Wird ein [LINK=UNIT_CHRISTIAN_MISSIONARY]Jesuitenmissionar[\LINK] oder ein [LINK=UNIT_CHRISTIAN_MISSIONARY]Evangelist[\LINK] eingesetzt, erhöht sich die Effektivität des Klosters.[PARAGRAPH:2]Für weitere Informationen siehe [LINK=CONCEPT_MONASTERIES]Klöster[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Hintergrund :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Der Begriff 'Kloster' steht für ein Gebäude oder einen Komplex mehrerer Gebäude, welches üblicherweise von Mönchen oder Nonnen bewohnt wird. Ein Kloster beinhaltet üblicherweise Gebetsstellen, wie eine Kapelle, eine Kirche oder einen Tempel, aber auch Räume oder Gebäude für den Alltag und die Selbstversorgung, wie einen Schlafsaal, Speisesaal, Werkstellen, Scheunen, Schmieden und manchmal Brauereien. In manchen größeren Klöstern findet man auch Büchereien, Schulen oder Krankenhäuser, die dann auch oft den umliegenden Gemeinden Dienste anbieten.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_PASTURE</Tag>
        <English>Pasture</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Pâturage</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Ranch</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Pasture</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Pasture</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Spanish>
        <Russian>Пастбище</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_PASTURE_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Pastures[COLOR_REVERT] can be built on unvegetated terrain that is either flat or hilly, and where [LINK=CONCEPT_CATTLE_OR_SHEEP_BREEDING]livestock[\LINK] can be bred. The production of [LINK=YIELD_HORSES]horses[\LINK], [LINK=YIELD_CATTLE]cattle[\LINK] and [LINK=YIELD_SHEEP]sheep[\LINK] is increased on those tiles.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Pasture is land with forage for livestock either as part of a farm or for ranching on open range, or where wild animals can graze or browse. Before factory farming, pasture was where grazing animals such as cattle and horses fed. It is still used extensively, particularly in arid regions where pasture land is unsuitable for any other agricultural production. In wetter climates pasture is valued for free range and organic farming.</English>
        <French>[BOLD]Stratégie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Le pâturage est une forme d'alimentation des animaux herbivores qui se nourrissent de plantes (telles que les graminées). Le pâturage diffère de la prédation parce que l'organisme mangé n'est généralement pas tué, et du parasitisme parce que les deux organismes n'ont pas de relation symbiotique et que le « brouteur » n'est généralement pas limité dans le choix des espèces qu'il peut consommer (voir espèces généraliste et spécialisée).</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Als 'Weideland' bezeichnet man Flächen mit Vegetation, die der Viehzucht dienen. Oft gehören diese Flächen zu einer Farm oder einer Ranch. In vielen Fällen dient dazu Land, das ansonsten für den Anbau von Nutzpflanzen nicht geeignet ist.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_PEN</Tag>
        <English>Breeding Pen</English>
        <French>Basse-cour</French>
        <German>
            <Text>Zuchtstall</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Russian>Загон для скота</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_PEN_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Breeding Pen[COLOR_REVERT]A pigpen keeps the animals close, safe from predators and easy to feed. It's also a good source of manure for the fields - a dirty job but somebody's got to do it</English>
        <French>[BOLD]Stratégie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Les basses-cours[COLOR_REVERT]Une porcherie permet de garder les animaux proches, à l'abri des prédateurs et faciles à nourrir. C'est aussi une bonne source de fumier pour les champs. C'est un travail sale mais quelqu'un doit le faire.</French>
		<German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Zuchtstall[COLOR_REVERT]Ein Stall hält die Tiere in zusammen, schützt sie vor Raubtieren und lässt sie leichter füttern. Darüber hinaus bietet sich so eine gute Düngerquelle für die Felder - eine schmutzige Arbeit, aber irgendjemand muss sie ja machen</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LARGE_PEN</Tag>
        <English>Large Breeding Pen</English>
        <French>Grande basse-cour:Grandes basses-cours</French>
        <German>
            <Text>Großer Zuchtbetrieb</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Russian>Большой загон для скота</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LARGE_PEN_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Large Breeding Pen[COLOR_REVERT][NEWLINE]A pigpen keeps the animals close, safe from predators and easy to feed. It's also a good source of manure for the fields - a dirty job but somebody's got to do it.</English>
		<French>[BOLD]Stratégie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Une grande porcherie[COLOR_REVERT][NEWLINE]Une porcherie permet de garder les animaux proches, à l'abri des prédateurs et faciles à nourrir. C'est aussi une bonne source de fumier pour les champs. C'est un travail sale mais quelqu'un doit le faire.</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Großer Zuchtbetrieb[COLOR_REVERT][NEWLINE]Ein Stall hält die Tiere in zusammen, schützt sie vor Raubtieren und lässt sie leichter füttern. Darüber hinaus bietet sich so eine gute Düngerquelle für die Felder - eine schmutzige Arbeit, aber irgendjemand muss sie ja machen</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LARGE_PASTURE</Tag>
        <English>Large Pasture</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Grand pâturage</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Große Ranch</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Large Pasture</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Large Pasture</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Spanish>
        <Russian>Большое пастбище</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LARGE_PASTURE_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Large pastures[COLOR_REVERT] are the upgrades of [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_PASTURE]pastures[\LINK]. The production of [LINK=YIELD_HORSES]horses[\LINK], [LINK=YIELD_CATTLE]cattle[\LINK] and [LINK=YIELD_SHEEP]sheep[\LINK] is increased on those tiles.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Pasture is land with forage for livestock either as part of a farm or in ranching on open range, or where wild animals can graze or browse. Before factory farming, pasture was where grazing animals such as cattle and horses fed. It is still used extensively, particularly in arid regions where pasture land is unsuitable for any other agricultural production. In wetter climates pasture is valued for free range and organic farming.</English>
        <French>[BOLD]Stratégie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Le pâturage est une forme d'alimentation des animaux herbivores qui se nourrissent de plantes (telles que les graminées). Le pâturage diffère de la prédation parce que l'organisme mangé n'est généralement pas tué, et du parasitisme parce que les deux organismes n'ont pas de relation symbiotique et que le « brouteur » n'est généralement pas limité dans le choix des espèces qu'il peut consommer (voir espèces généraliste et spécialisée).</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Als 'Weideland' bezeichnet man Flächen mit Vegetation, die der Viehzucht dienen. Oft gehören diese Flächen zu einer Farm oder einer Ranch. In vielen Fällen dient dazu Land, dass ansonsten für den Anbau von Nutzpflanzen nicht geeignet ist.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_PLANTATION</Tag>
        <English>Plantation</English>
        <French>Plantation</French>
        <German>
            <Text>Plantage</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>Piantagione</Italian>
        <Spanish>Plantacion</Spanish>
        <Russian>Плантация</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_PLANTATION_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Plantations[COLOR_REVERT] can be built on all flat [LINK=TERRAIN_GRASS]grassland[\LINK], [LINK=TERRAIN_PLAINS]prairie[\LINK], [LINK=TERRAIN_SAVANNAH]savannah[\LINK] and [LINK=TERRAIN_MARSH]marsh[\LINK] terrain. Building a plantation significantly increases the production of [LINK=YIELD_COFFEE_BERRIES]coffee berries[\LINK], [LINK=YIELD_COTTON]cotton[\LINK], [LINK=YIELD_HEMP]hemp[\LINK], [LINK=YIELD_INDIGO]indigo[\LINK], [LINK=YIELD_SUGAR]sugar[\LINK] and [LINK=YIELD_TOBACCO]tobacco[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]A plantation is a large artificially established forest, farm or estate, where crops are grown for sale, intended for distant markets rather than local consumption.</English>
        <French>[BOLD]Stratégie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Une plantation est une exploitation agricole en monoculture de cultures à forte valeur économique destinées à la vente vers des marchés internationaux. La plantation est souvent associée à certaines cultures tels le coton, la canne à sucre, le tabac, le café, la banane, le cacao ou le chanvre.</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Plantagen[COLOR_REVERT] können auf flachem und unbewaldetem Terrain, wie z.B. [LINK=TERRAIN_GRASS]Grasland[\LINK], [LINK=TERRAIN_PLAINS]Prärie[\LINK], [LINK=TERRAIN_SAVANNAH]Savanne[\LINK] oder auch [LINK=TERRAIN_MARSH]Sumpf[\LINK], angelegt werden. Die Anlage einer Plantage steigert die Produktion von [LINK=YIELD_COFFEE_BERRIES]Kaffeebeeren[\LINK], [LINK=YIELD_COTTON]Baumwolle[\LINK], [LINK=YIELD_HEMP]Hanf[\LINK], [LINK=YIELD_INDIGO]Indigo[\LINK], [LINK=YIELD_SUGAR]Zucker[\LINK] und [LINK=YIELD_TOBACCO]Tabak[\LINK] erheblich.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Hintergrund :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Eine Plantage ist üblicherweise ein grösseres, künstlich angelegtes Anbaugebiet von Pflanzen, die dann in Europa verkauft und deren weiterverarbeitet werden sollen.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LARGE_PLANTATION</Tag>
        <English>Large Plantation</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Grande plantation</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Große Plantage</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Large Plantation</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Large Plantation</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Spanish>
        <Russian>Большая плантация</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LARGE_PLANTATION_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Large plantations[COLOR_REVERT] are upgraded versions of the [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_PLANTATION]plantation[\LINK]. The purpose of a plantation is to significantly increase the production of [LINK=YIELD_COFFEE_BERRIES]coffee berries[\LINK], [LINK=YIELD_COTTON]cotton[\LINK], [LINK=YIELD_HEMP]hemp[\LINK], [LINK=YIELD_INDIGO]indigo[\LINK], [LINK=YIELD_SUGAR]sugar[\LINK] and [LINK=YIELD_TOBACCO]tobacco[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]A plantation is a large artificially established forest, farm or estate, where crops are grown for sale, intended for distant markets rather than local consumption.</English>
        <French>[BOLD]Stratégie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Une plantation est une exploitation agricole en monoculture de cultures à forte valeur économique destinées à la vente vers des marchés internationaux. La plantation est souvent associée à certaines cultures tels le coton, la canne à sucre, le tabac, le café, la banane, le cacao ou le chanvre.</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Große Plantagen[COLOR_REVERT] sind eine Erweiterung der [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_PLANTATION]Plantage[\LINK]. Der Zweck einer Plantage ist die gesteigerte Produktion von [LINK=YIELD_COFFEE_BERRIES]Kaffeebeeren[\LINK], [LINK=YIELD_COTTON]Baumwolle[\LINK], [LINK=YIELD_HEMP]Hanf[\LINK], [LINK=YIELD_INDIGO]Indigo[\LINK], [LINK=YIELD_SUGAR]Zucker[\LINK] und [LINK=YIELD_TOBACCO]Tabak[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Hintergrund :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Eine Plantage ist üblicherweise ein grösseres, künstlich angelegtes Anbaugebiet von Pflanzen, die dann in Europa verkauft und weiterverarbeitet werden sollen.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_QUARRY</Tag>
        <English>Quarry</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Carrière</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Steinbruch</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Quarry</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Quarry</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Spanish>
        <Russian>Каменоломня</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_QUARRY_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Quarries[COLOR_REVERT] can be built only on peaks. They increase the production of [LINK=YIELD_STONE]stone[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]A quarry is an open-pit mine from which rock is extracted. Quarries are generally used for building materials such as dimension stone, construction aggregate, riprap, sand and gravel.[PARAGRAPH:1]They are often co-located with concrete and asphalt plants since large amounts of aggregate are used in those materials. The word "quarry" can include underground quarrying for stone, such as Bath stone.</English>
        <French>[BOLD]Stratégie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Une carrière est un endroit d'où sont extraits des matériaux de construction à partir de roche. Le chantier se fait à ciel ouvert, soit « à flanc de coteau », soit « en fosse » (jusqu'à une centaine de mètres de profondeur parfois). Les carrières exploitent des roches meubles (éboulis, alluvionnaires) ou massives (roches consolidées sédimentaire (calcaires et grès), éruptive ou métamorphique (granites, porphyres, gneiss, amphibolites, quartzites, schistes, basaltes).</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Steinbrüche[COLOR_REVERT] können nur in den Bergen angelegt werden. Sie erhöhen die Produktion von [LINK=YIELD_STONE]Steinen[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Hintergrund :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Ein Steinbruch ist meist eine grubenähnliche Anlage, die dazu dient, Fels oder Mineralien abzubauen. In vielen Fällen dient dieses Gestein als Baumaterial.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LARGE_QUARRY</Tag>
        <English>Large Quarry</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Grande carrière</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Großer Steinbruch</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Large Quarry</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Large Quarry</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Spanish>
        <Russian>Большая каменоломня</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LARGE_QUARRY_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Large quarries[COLOR_REVERT] are the upgrades of [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_QUARRY]quarries[\LINK]. They increase the production of [LINK=YIELD_STONE]stone[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]A quarry is an open-pit mine from which rock is extracted. Quarries are generally used for building materials such as dimension stone, construction aggregate, riprap, sand and gravel.[PARAGRAPH:1]They are often co-located with concrete and asphalt plants since large amounts of aggregate are used in those materials. The word "quarry" can include underground quarrying for stone, such as Bath stone.</English>
        <French>[BOLD]Stratégie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Une carrière est un endroit d'où sont extraits des matériaux de construction à partir de roche. Le chantier se fait à ciel ouvert, soit « à flanc de coteau », soit « en fosse » (jusqu'à une centaine de mètres de profondeur parfois). Les carrières exploitent des roches meubles (éboulis, alluvionnaires) ou massives (roches consolidées sédimentaire (calcaires et grès), éruptive ou métamorphique (granites, porphyres, gneiss, amphibolites, quartzites, schistes, basaltes).</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Große Steinbrüche[COLOR_REVERT] sind die Erweiterung des [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_QUARRY]Steinbruchs[\LINK]. Sie erhöhen die Produktion von [LINK=YIELD_STONE]Steinen[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Hintergrund :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Ein Steinbruch ist meist eine grubenähnliche Anlage, die dazu dient, Fels oder Mineralien abzubauen. In vielen Fällen dient dieses Gestein als Baumaterial.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_TRAPPER_HUT</Tag>
        <English>Trapper Hut</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Hutte du trappeur</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Jagdhütte</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Capanna da caccia</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Pabellón de caza</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Spanish>
        <Russian>Домик охотника</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_TRAPPER_HUT_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Trapper huts[COLOR_REVERT] can be built in [LINK=FEATURE_FOREST]forests[\LINK], [LINK=FEATURE_LIGHT_FOREST]light forests[\LINK] and [LINK=FEATURE_FOREST_TUNDRA]taiga[\LINK], on [LINK=TERRAIN_TUNDRA]tundra[\LINK] and [LINK=TERRAIN_SNOW]permafrost[\LINK] terrain, as well as tiles with the [LINK=BONUS_BISON]bison[\LINK] bonus. They boost the production of [LINK=YIELD_FUR]fur[\LINK] and [LINK=YIELD_PREMIUM_FUR]luxury fur[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Hunting wild animals like deer and beaver is a lonely job far from civilization and cities. During the trapping season hunters and trappers live in their trappers' huts, leaving only to sell their furs.</English>
        <French>[BOLD]Stratégie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Chasser et trapper les animaux sauvages comme les cerfs ou les visons a été pendant longtemp un travail solitaire loin de la civilization et des grandes villes. Pendant les mois de chasse, les chasseurs et trappeurs vivaient dans des huttes qu'ils ne quittaient que pour vendre leurs fourrures.</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Jagdhütten[COLOR_REVERT] können in [LINK=FEATURE_FOREST]Wäldern[\LINK], im [LINK=FEATURE_LIGHT_FOREST]Buschland[\LINK] und der [LINK=FEATURE_FOREST_TUNDRA]Taiga[\LINK], sogar auf [LINK=TERRAIN_TUNDRA]Tundra[\LINK] und [LINK=TERRAIN_SNOW]Permafrost[\LINK] sowie auf Geländefeldern mit der Bonusressource [LINK=BONUS_BISON]Büffel[\LINK] angelegt werden. Sie steigern die Ausbeute an [LINK=YIELD_FUR]Pelzen[\LINK] und [LINK=YIELD_PREMIUM_FUR]Hochwertigen Pelzen[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Hintergrund :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Die Jagd auf Rehe, Biber und andere Tiere fand meist weit abseits der Städte statt. Während der Jagdsaison lebten die Jäger und Trapper oft monatelang in einsamen Jagdhütten und verliessen diese nur zum Verkauf ihrer Waren in den Städten.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_TRAPPER_CAMP</Tag>
        <English>Trapper Camp</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Camp de trappeurs</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Trappercamp</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Trapper Camp</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Trapper Camp</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Spanish>
        <Russian>Лагерь охотников</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_TRAPPER_CAMP_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Trapper camps[COLOR_REVERT] are the upgrades of [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_TRAPPER_HUT]trapper huts[\LINK]. They boost the production of [LINK=YIELD_FUR]fur[\LINK] and [LINK=YIELD_PREMIUM_FUR]luxury fur[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Hunting wild animals like deer and beaver is a lonely job far from civilization and cities. During the trapping season hunters and trappers live in their trappers' huts, leaving only to sell their furs.</English>
        <French>[BOLD]Stratégie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Chasser et trapper les animaux sauvages comme les cerfs ou les visons a été pendant longtemp un travail solitaire loin de la civilization et des grandes villes. Pendant les mois de chasse, les chasseurs et trappeurs vivaient dans des huttes qu'ils ne quittaient que pour vendre leurs fourrures.</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Trappercamps[COLOR_REVERT] sind die Erweiterung der [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_TRAPPER_HUT]Jagdhütte[\LINK]. Sie verbessern die Ausbeute an [LINK=YIELD_FUR]Pelzen[\LINK] und [LINK=YIELD_PREMIUM_FUR]Hochwertigen Pelzen[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Hintergrund :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Die Jagd auf Rehe, Biber und andere Tiere fand meist weit abseits der Städte statt. Während der Jagdsaison lebten die Jäger und Trapper oft monatelang in einsamen Jagdhütten und verliessen diese nur zum Verkauf ihrer Waren in den Städten.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_VINEYARD</Tag>
        <English>Vineyard</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Vigne</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Weinberg</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Vineyard:Vineyards</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Vineyard:Vineyards</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Spanish>
        <Russian>Виноградник</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_VINEYARD_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Vineyards[COLOR_REVERT] can be built only on hilly [LINK=TERRAIN_GRASS]grassland[\LINK] terrain. The production of [LINK=YIELD_FOOD]food[\LINK] and [LINK=YIELD_GRAPES]grapes[\LINK] is increased by the vineyard.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Wine, a beverage made from fermented grapes, was first produced as early as 6000 BC. Its use spread throughout the Middle East and Egypt, and it quickly became a popular beverage of the ancient world. Grapes used for wine making are grown in many different regions of the world. Most vineyards are located in the hills and valleys of temperate regions. Wine making as an industry has been perfected over several centuries.[PARAGRAPH:1]Many regions such as the Rhine and Loire valleys of Europe are well-known for their fine wines, and derive a significant portion of their economy from wine making.</English>
        <French>[BOLD]Stratégie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Le vin est une boisson obtenue par la fermentation du raisin. Sa production débute dès 6 000 ans av. J.-C. Sa consommation se répand à travers tout le Moyen-Orient et l'Egypte, et il devient rapidement une boisson très populaire dans le monde antique. Le raisin utilisé dans la fabrication du vin est cultivé dans de nombreuses régions du monde. Les vignes sont généralement situées sur les coteaux et dans les vallées des régions tempérées. Les procédés de fabrication du vin ont été perfectionnés au cours des siècles. De nombreuses régions, comme les vallées du Rhin et de la Loire, sont réputées pour leurs bons vins, et une grande partie de leur économie est liée à la fabrication du vin.</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Der aus fermentierten Trauben hergestellte Wein wurde erstmals um 6000 vor Christus produziert und war im Nahen Osten und in Ägypten weit verbreitet. Das Getränk entwickelte sich schnell zu einem der beliebtesten kulinarischen Genüsse der Antike. Die für die Weinherstellung benötigten Trauben werden in vielen verschiedenen Gebieten der Welt angebaut, die meisten Weinhänge befinden sich jedoch in den Hügeln und Tälern von Regionen mit gemäßigtem Klima. Im Laufe mehrerer Jahrhunderte wurde die industrielle Weinherstellung immer weiter perfektioniert.[PARAGRAPH:1]Viele Anbaugebiete wie die Rhein- und Loiretäler in Europa sind für ihre feinen Weine bekannt und beziehen einen Großteil ihrer wirtschaftlichen Erträge aus der Weinproduktion.</German>
        <Italian>[BOLD]Strategia :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Realizzato dalla fermentazione dell'uva, il primo vino risale circa al 6000 a. C. e si diffuse rapirdamente attraverso il Medio Oriente e l'Egitto, diventando una delle bevande più popolari del mondo antico. Le qualità d'uva usate per la realizzazione del vino crescono in differenti zone del mondo; la maggior parte delle vigne si possono trovare sulle colline e nelle vallate di regioni dal clima temperato. L'industria del vino è andata perfezionandosi nel corso dei secoli: molte regioni europee, come le vallate del Reno e della Loira, sono rinomate per la produzione di ottimi vini, principale forma di economia della zona.</Italian>
        <Spanish>[BOLD]Estrategia :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]El vino, una bebida preparada a partir de uvas fermentadas, se elaboró por vez primera ya en el 6000 a. C. Su consumo se extendió rápidamente por Oriente Medio y Egipto, y pronto se convirtió en una popular bebida en el mundo antiguo. Las uvas empleadas en la fabricación del vino crecen en muchas y muy distintas partes del mundo. La mayoría de las viñas están en colinas y valles de regiones templadas. La vinicultura se ha perfeccionado como industria a lo largo de varios siglos. Muchas regiones, como los valles del Rin y del Loira en Europa, son conocidas por sus grandes vinos y obtienen una parte significativa de sus ingresos de la vinicultura.</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LARGE_VINEYARD</Tag>
        <English>Mature Vineyard</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Vigne mature</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Alter Weinberg</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Mature Vineyard</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Mature Vineyard</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Spanish>
        <Russian>Старый виноградник</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LARGE_VINEYARD_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Mature vineyards[COLOR_REVERT] are the upgrades of [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_VINEYARD]vineyards[\LINK]. The production of [LINK=YIELD_FOOD]food[\LINK] and [LINK=YIELD_GRAPES]grapes[\LINK] is increased by the mature vineyard.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Wine, a beverage from fermented grapes, was first produced as early as 6000 BC. Its use spread throughout the Middle East and Egypt, and it quickly became a popular beverage of the ancient world.[PARAGRAPH:1]The grapes used for the making of wine are grown in many different regions of the world. Most vineyards are located in hills and valleys of temperate regions. Wine making as an industry has been perfected over several centuries.[PARAGRAPH:1]Many regions such as the Rhine and Loire valleys of Europe are well-known for their fine wines, and derive a significant portion of their economy from wine making.</English>
        <French>[BOLD]Stratégie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Le vin est une boisson obtenue par la fermentation du raisin. Sa production débute dès 6 000 ans av. J.-C. Sa consommation se répand à travers tout le Moyen-Orient et l'Egypte, et il devient rapidement une boisson très populaire dans le monde antique. Le raisin utilisé dans la fabrication du vin est cultivé dans de nombreuses régions du monde. Les vignes sont généralement situées sur les coteaux et dans les vallées des régions tempérées. Les procédés de fabrication du vin ont été perfectionnés au cours des siècles. De nombreuses régions, comme les vallées du Rhin et de la Loire, sont réputées pour leurs bons vins, et une grande partie de leur économie est liée à la fabrication du vin.</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Der aus fermentierten Trauben hergestellte Wein wurde erstmals um 6000 vor Christus produziert und war im Nahen Osten und in Ägypten weit verbreitet. Das Getränk entwickelte sich schnell zu einem der beliebtesten kulinarischen Genüsse der Antike. Die für die Weinherstellung benötigten Trauben werden in vielen verschiedenen Gebieten der Welt angebaut, die meisten Weinhänge befinden sich jedoch in den Hügeln und Tälern von Regionen mit gemäßigtem Klima. Im Laufe mehrerer Jahrhunderte wurde die industrielle Weinherstellung immer weiter perfektioniert.[PARAGRAPH:1]Viele Anbaugebiete wie die Rhein- und Loiretäler in Europa sind für ihre feinen Weine bekannt und beziehen einen Großteil ihrer wirtschaftlichen Erträge aus der Weinproduktion.</German>
        <Italian>[BOLD]Strategia :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Realizzato dalla fermentazione dell'uva, il primo vino risale circa al 6000 a. C. e si diffuse rapirdamente attraverso il Medio Oriente e l'Egitto, diventando una delle bevande più popolari del mondo antico. Le qualità d'uva usate per la realizzazione del vino crescono in differenti zone del mondo; la maggior parte delle vigne si possono trovare sulle colline e nelle vallate di regioni dal clima temperato. L'industria del vino è andata perfezionandosi nel corso dei secoli: molte regioni europee, come le vallate del Reno e della Loira, sono rinomate per la produzione di ottimi vini, principale forma di economia della zona.</Italian>
        <Spanish>[BOLD]Estrategia :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]El vino, una bebida preparada a partir de uvas fermentadas, se elaboró por vez primera ya en el 6000 a. C. Su consumo se extendió rápidamente por Oriente Medio y Egipto, y pronto se convirtió en una popular bebida en el mundo antiguo. Las uvas empleadas en la fabricación del vino crecen en muchas y muy distintas partes del mundo. La mayoría de las viñas están en colinas y valles de regiones templadas. La vinicultura se ha perfeccionado como industria a lo largo de varios siglos. Muchas regiones, como los valles del Rin y del Loira en Europa, son conocidas por sus grandes vinos y obtienen una parte significativa de sus ingresos de la vinicultura.</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_WATER_WORKED</Tag>
        <English>Waterworks</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Mer travaillée</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Bearbeitetes Wasser</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Irrigazione:Irrigazioni</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Agua faenada:Aguas faenadas</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_WATER_WORKED_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>Waterworks are crucial for a community of any size. Clean abundant water is often the difference between health and death.</English>
        <French>L'eau est un composé chimique ubiquitaire sur la Terre, essentiel pour tous les organismes vivants connus. C'est le milieu de vie de la plupart des êtres vivants. Elle se trouve en général dans son état liquide répondant à la formule chimique H2O : la molécule contient un atome d'oxygène et deux atomes d'hydrogène.</French>
        <German>Wasser ist eine chemische Substanz mit der Formel H2O. Es enthält also Sauerstoff und Wasserstoff. Bei Raumtemperatur ist es flüssig, existiert aber auf der Erde auch oft in gefrorener Form als Eis oder Schnee oder in Gasform als Wasserdampf.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_RAFT_STATION</Tag>
        <English>River Ferry Station</English>
        <French>Gare de River Ferry</French>
		<German>
            <Text>Flussfährenstation</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Russian>Речная паромная переправа</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_RAFT_STATION_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]River ferries[COLOR_REVERT] and rafts were the most effective way to cross [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]large rivers[COLOR_REVERT] and streams in the New World before increasing traffic justified the cost of sturdy bridges.</English>
		<French>[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Les bacs fluviaux[COLOR_REVERT] et les radeaux étaient le moyen le plus efficace de traverser les [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]grandes rivières[COLOR_REVERT] et les ruisseaux dans le Nouveau Monde avant que l'augmentation du trafic ne justifie le coût de ponts robustes.</French>
        <German>[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Flussfähren[COLOR_REVERT] und Flöße waren die am meisten genutzen Transportmittel, um [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]große Flüsse[COLOR_REVERT] und Ströme in der Neuen Welt zu überqueren, bevor der technische Fortschritt es erlaubte, größere und stabilere Brücken zu bauen.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_ALLOWS_CROSSING_OF_LARGE_RIVERS</Tag>
        <English>[ICON_BULLET]Allows all land units to cross [LINK=TERRAIN_LARGE_RIVERS]large rivers[\LINK]</English>
        <French>[ICON_BULLET]Permet à toutes les unités terrestres de traverser [LINK=TERRAIN_LARGE_RIVERS]grands fleuves[\LINK]</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Erlaubt es allen Landeinheiten einen [LINK=TERRAIN_LARGE_RIVERS]Großen Fluss[\LINK] zu überqueren.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_IS_CANAL</Tag>
        <English>[ICON_BULLET]Can only be built adjacent to [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]water plots[COLOR_REVERT] like coasts, shallow coasts, large rivers, lakes or ice lakes [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Allows [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]coastal ships[COLOR_REVERT] and [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]fishing boats[COLOR_REVERT] to cross [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]land tiles[COLOR_REVERT]</English>
        <French>[ICON_BULLET]Ne peut être construit qu'à côté de [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]parcelles d'eau[COLOR_REVERT] comme les côtes, les côtes peu profondes, les grandes rivières, lacs ou lacs de glace [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Permet aux [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]navires côtiers[COLOR_REVERT] et aux [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]bateaux de pêche[COLOR_REVERT] de traverser des [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]tuiles terrestres[COLOR_REVERT].</French>
		<German>[ICON_BULLET]Kann nur angrenzend an [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Wassergeländefelder[COLOR_REVERT], wie z.B. Küsten, flache Küsten, große Flüsse, Seen oder Eisseen gebaut werden [NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Erlaubt [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Küstenschiffen [COLOR_REVERT] und [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Fischerbooten[COLOR_REVERT] die Durchfahrt über [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Land[COLOR_REVERT]</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_FISHING_NETS</Tag>
        <English>Fishing Nets</English>
		<French>Filets de pêche</French>
        <German>
            <Text>Fischernetze</Text>
            <Gender>Neuter</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </German>
        <Russian>Рыболовные сети</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_FISHING_NETS_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Fishing nets[COLOR_REVERT] can be woven to scoop up a shoal of fish or, with gill nets, to trap fish of the desired size. It's one of the two main systems used by fishing boats, the other being trawling with hooks.</English>
        <German>[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Fischernetze[COLOR_REVERT] werden genutzt um einen Fischschwarm zu fangen, oder mit sogenannten Kiemennetzen auch nur Fische einer bestimmten Größe. Daneben gibt es noch ein anderes Hauptsystem, das von Fischern verwendet wird: das Schleppnetz, welches mit einem Haken hinter dem Schiff hergezogen wird.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_HUNTERS_STAGE</Tag>
        <English>Hunters' Blind</English>
		<French>Affût de chasseur</French>
        <German>
            <Text>Jagdpier</Text>
            <Gender>Neuter</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Russian>Охотничье укрытие</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_HUNTERS_STAGE_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>The [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]hunters' blind[COLOR_REVERT] can be up a tree or in a bush, or even a ghillie suit in the middle of an open meadow, as long as it gets the hunter close enough to the wild game. Being close is especially important with a musket.[NEWLINE]Rifles won't be common until after 1740. A ghillie suit is a net or cloth coat made to look natural using leaves and twigs from the area.</English>
        <German>Das [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Jagdpier[COLOR_REVERT] kann auf einem Baum oder in einem Gebüsch sein, oder sogar in einem Ghillie-Anzug mitten auf einer offenen Wiese, solange er den Jäger nahe genug an das Wild bringt. Mit einer Muskete ist es besonders wichtig, nah dran zu sein.[NEWLINE]Gewehre wurden erst nach 1740 üblich. Ein Ghillie-Anzug ist ein Netz- oder Stoffmantel, der mit Blättern und Zweigen aus der Umgebung so hergestellt wird, sodass er der Tarnung dient.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_SALINA</Tag>
        <English>Salt Works</English>
		<French>Salines</French>
        <German>
            <Text>Saline</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Russian>Соляной рудник</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_SALINA_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Salt works[COLOR_REVERT] are where salt is purified either after being mined, which produces rock salt, or extracted by pumping water into a salt deposit. In either case, the salt may be purified by mechanical evaporation of brine. Purification is done using shallow open pans heated to accelerate evaporation.</English>
		<French>[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Les salines[COLOR_REVERT] sont les endroits où le sel est purifié soit après avoir été extrait, ce qui produit du sel gemme, soit en pompant de l'eau dans un gisement de sel. Dans les deux cas, le sel peut être purifié par évaporation mécanique de la saumure. La purification se fait à l'aide de bacs ouverts peu profonds, chauffés pour accélérer l'évaporation.</French>
        <German>[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Saline[COLOR_REVERT] sind Orte, an denen Salz gereinigt wird, entweder nach dem Abbau, bei dem Steinsalz entsteht, oder durch das Pumpen von Wasser in eine Salzlagerstätte gewonnen wird. In beiden Fällen kann das Salz durch mechanische Verdampfung der Sole gereinigt werden. Die Reinigung erfolgt in flachen, offenen Pfannen, die zur Beschleunigung der Verdunstung erhitzt werden.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LARGE_SALINA</Tag>
        <English>Large Salt Works</English>
		<French>Grande saline</French>
        <German>
            <Text>Große Saline</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Russian>Большой соляной рудник</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_LARGE_SALINA_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Large salt works[COLOR_REVERT] are where salt is purified either after being mined, which produces rock salt, or extracted by pumping water into a salt deposit. In either case, the salt may be purified by mechanical evaporation of brine. Purification is done using shallow open pans heated to accelerate evaporation.</English>
		<French>[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Les grandes salines[COLOR_REVERT] sont les endroits où le sel est purifié soit après avoir été extrait, ce qui produit du sel gemme, soit en pompant de l'eau dans un gisement de sel. Dans les deux cas, le sel peut être purifié par évaporation mécanique de la saumure. La purification se fait à l'aide de bacs ouverts peu profonds et chauffés pour accélérer l'évaporation.</French>
        <German>[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Große Saline[COLOR_REVERT] sind Orte, an denen Salz gereinigt wird, entweder nach dem Abbau, bei dem Steinsalz entsteht, oder durch das Pumpen von Wasser in eine Salzlagerstätte gewonnen wird. In beiden Fällen kann das Salz durch mechanische Verdampfung der Sole gereinigt werden. Die Reinigung erfolgt in flachen, offenen Pfannen, die zur Beschleunigung der Verdunstung beheizt werden.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_BUILD_ONLY_LARGE_RIVERS</Tag>
        <English>[ICON_BULLET]Can only be built on [LINK=TERRAIN_LARGE_RIVERS]large rivers[\LINK]</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Ne peut être construit que sur[LINK=TERRAIN_LARGE_RIVERS]large rivers[\LINK]</French>
        <German>[ICON_BULLET]Kann nur auf [LINK=TERRAIN_LARGE_RIVERS]Großen Flüssen[\LINK] gebaut werden.</German>
        <Russian>[ICON_BULLET]Можно строить только на [LINK=TERRAIN_LARGE_RIVERS]больших реках[\LINK]</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_BUILD_ONLY_LAKE</Tag>
        <English>[ICON_BULLET]Can only be built on [LINK=TERRAIN_LAKE]fresh water lakes[\LINK], [LINK=TERRAIN_ICE_LAKE]ice lakes[\LINK], [LINK=TERRAIN_ICE_LAKE]coasts[\LINK] or [LINK=TERRAIN_ICE_LAKE]shallow coasts[\LINK]</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Ne peut être construit que sur les [LINK=TERRAIN_LAKE]lacs d'eau douce[\LINK], les [LINK=TERRAIN_ICE_LAKE]lacs de glace[\LINK], les [LINK=TERRAIN_ICE_LAKE]côtes[\LINK] ou les [LINK=TERRAIN_ICE_LAKE]côtes peu profondes[\LINK].</French>
        <German>[ICON_BULLET]Kann nur auf [LINK=TERRAIN_LAKE]Süßwassersee[\LINK], [LINK=TERRAIN_ICE_LAKE]Eisseen[\LINK], [LINK=TERRAIN_ICE_LAKE]Küsten[\LINK] oderr [LINK=TERRAIN_ICE_LAKE]flachen Küsten[\LINK] gebaut werden.</German>
        <Russian>[ICON_BULLET]Можно строить только на [LINK=TERRAIN_LAKE]пресноводном озере[\LINK], [LINK=TERRAIN_ICE_LAKE]замерзшем озере[\LINK], [LINK=TERRAIN_ICE_LAKE]побережье[\LINK] или [LINK=TERRAIN_ICE_LAKE]мелководье[\LINK]</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_FOR_SPAWNING_UNITS</Tag>
        <English>[ICON_BULLET]Can spawn friendly units when explored.</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Peut donner naissance à des unités amies lorsqu'il est exploré.</French>
        <German>[ICON_BULLET]Kann freundliche Einheiten hervorbringen, wenn es erkundet wird.</German>
        <Russian>[ICON_BULLET]При исследовании может создавать дружественные юниты.</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_FOR_SPAWNING_HOSTILE_ANIMALS</Tag>
        <English>[ICON_BULLET]Spawns wild animals that then guard it.</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Donne naissance à des animaux sauvages qui la gardent ensuite.</French>
        <German>[ICON_BULLET]Erzeugt Wilde Tiere als Beschützer.</German>
        <Russian>[ICON_BULLET]Порождает диких животных, которые потом охраняют его.</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_FOR_SPAWNING_HOSTILE_NATIVES</Tag>
        <English>[ICON_BULLET]Spawns hostile Natives who guard it.</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Donne naissance à des indigènes hostiles qui la gardent.</French>
        <German>[ICON_BULLET]Erzeugt Feindliche Ureinwohner als Beschützer.</German>
        <Russian>[ICON_BULLET]Порождает враждебных туземцев, которые её охраняют..</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_FOR_SPAWNING_HOSTILE_CRIMINALS</Tag>
        <English>[ICON_BULLET]Spawns outlaws who guard their hideout.</English>
		<French>[ICON_BULLET]Donne naissance à des hors-la-loi qui gardent leur cachette.</French>
        <German>[ICON_BULLET]Erzeugt Revoltierende Sklaven und Kriminelle als Beschützer.</German>
        <Russian>[ICON_BULLET]Порождает преступников, которые охраняют свое убежище.</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_CLAY_PIT</Tag>
        <English>Clay Pit</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Fosse à argile</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Lehmgrube</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Clay Pit</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Clay Pit</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Spanish>
        <Russian>Глиняный карьер</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_CLAY_PIT_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]A [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]clay pit[COLOR_REVERT] can be built only on hills. They increase the production of [LINK=YIELD_CLAY]clay[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]A clay pit is an open-pit mine from which clay is extracted. Clay is generally used for goods and other everyday items.</English>
        <French>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]A [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]clay pit[COLOR_REVERT] can be built only on hills. They increase the production of [LINK=YIELD_CLAY]clay[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]A clay pit is an open-pit mine from which clay is extracted. Clay is generally used for goods and other everyday items.</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Lehmgruben[COLOR_REVERT] können nur auf Hügeln angelegt werden. Sie erhöhen die Produktion von [LINK=YIELD_CLAY]Ton[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Hintergrund :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Eine Tongrube ist eine Anlage, die dazu dient, Ton abzubauen. In vielen Fällen dient dieses Material als Material zur Herstellung von Waren und anderen Alltagsgegenständen.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_OPEN_CLAY_MINE</Tag>
        <English>Open Clay Mine</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Mine ouverte d'argile</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Lehmtagebau</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Open Clay Mine</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Open Clay Mine</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Spanish>
        <Russian>Открытый глиняный рудник</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_OPEN_CLAY_MINE_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Open clay mines[COLOR_REVERT] are the upgrades of [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_CLAY_PIT]clay pits[\LINK]. They increase the production of [LINK=YIELD_CLAY]clay[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]In open-pit clay mines clay is extracted. Clay is generally used for goods and other everyday items.</English>
        <French>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Open clay mines[COLOR_REVERT] are the upgrades of [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_CLAY_PIT]clay pits[\LINK]. They increase the production of [LINK=YIELD_CLAY]clay[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]In open-pit clay mines clay is extracted. Clay is generally used for goods and other everyday items.</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Der[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Lehmtagebau[COLOR_REVERT] ist die Erweiterung der [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_CLAY_PIT]IMPROVEMENT_CLAY_PIT[\LINK]. Er erhöht die Produktion von [LINK=YIELD_CLAY]Ton[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Hintergrund :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Ein Tagebau ist meist eine grubenähnliche Anlage, die dazu dient, Ton in großen Mengen abzubauen. In vielen Fällen dient dieses Material als Material zur Herstellung von Waren und anderen Alltagsgegenständen.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_PEAT_PIT</Tag>
        <English>Peat Pit</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Fosse à tourbe</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Torfgrube</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Peat Pit</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Peat Pit</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Spanish>
        <Russian>Торфяной карьер</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_PEAT_PIT_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]A [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]peat pit[COLOR_REVERT] can be built only on flat wetlands. They increase the production of [LINK=YIELD_PEAT]peat[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]A peat pit is an open-pit mine from which peat is extracted. </English>
        <French>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]A [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]peat pit[COLOR_REVERT] can be built only on flat wetlands. They increase the production of [LINK=YIELD_PEAT]peat[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]A peat pit is an open-pit mine from which peat is extracted. </French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Torfgruben[COLOR_REVERT] können nur auf flachem Feuchtland angelegt werden. Sie erhöhen die Produktion von [LINK=YIELD_PEAT]Torf[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Hintergrund :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Eine Torfgrube ist eine Anlage, die dazu dient, Torf abzubauen.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_OPEN_PEAT_MINE</Tag>
        <English>Open Peat Mine</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Mine ouverte de tourbe</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Torf Tagebau</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Open Peat Mine</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Open Peat Mine</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Spanish>
        <Russian>Открытая торфяная шахта</Russian>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_IMPROVEMENT_OPEN_PEAT_MINE_PEDIA</Tag>
        <English>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Open peat mines[COLOR_REVERT] are the upgrades of [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_PEAT_PIT]peat pits[\LINK]. They increase the production of [LINK=YIELD_PEAT]peat[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Peat forms when plant material does not fully decay in acidic and anaerobic conditions. It is composed mainly of wetland vegetation: principally bog plants including mosses, sedges, and shrubs. As it accumulates, the peat holds water. This slowly creates wetter conditions that allow the area of wetland to expand. Peatland can include ridges and raised bogs.</English>
        <French>[BOLD]Strategy :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1][COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Open peat mines[COLOR_REVERT] are the upgrades of [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_PEAT_PIT]peat pits[\LINK]. They increase the production of [LINK=YIELD_PEAT]peat[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]In open-pit peat mines peat is extracted.</French>
        <German>[BOLD]Strategie :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Der [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Torf Tagebau[COLOR_REVERT] ist die Erweiterung der [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_PEAT_PIT]Torfgrube[\LINK]. Er erhöht die Produktion von [LINK=YIELD_PEAT]Torf[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Hintergrund :[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Ein Tagebau ist meist eine grubenähnliche Anlage, die dazu dient, Torf in großen Mengen abzubauen. </German>
    </TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>
