<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_BURIAL_GROUNDS</Tag>
        <English>Burial Grounds</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Cimetière:Cimetières</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>Grabstätten</German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Cimiteri</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Túmulos funerarios</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_CHRISTIAN_MISSIONARY</Tag>
        <English>You have discovered a lost missionary!</English>
        <French>Vous avez découvert un missionnaire perdu !</French>
        <German>Ihr habt einen verlaufenen Missionar entdeckt!</German>
        <Italian>You have discovered a lost missionary!</Italian>
        <Spanish>You have discovered a lost missionary!</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_COLONIST</Tag>
        <English>You have discovered a lost colonist from a former failed colony!</English>
        <French>Vous avez découvert un colon perdu d'une ancienne colonie !</French>
        <German>Ihr habt einen verlorenen Kolonisten einer gescheiterten Kolonie entdeckt!</German>
        <Italian>You have discovered a lost colonist from a former failed colony!</Italian>
        <Spanish>You have discovered a lost colonist from a former failed colony!</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_CONQUISTADOR</Tag>
        <English>You have discovered a lost conquistador who was separated from his fellows!</English>
        <French>Vous avez découvert un conquistador perdu abandonné par les siens !</French>
        <German>Ihr habt einen Conquistador entdeckt, der von seiner Truppe getrennt wurde!</German>
        <Italian>You have discovered a lost conquistador who was separated from his fellows!</Italian>
        <Spanish>You have discovered a lost conquistador who was separated from his fellows!</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_DESERTED_SHIP</Tag>
        <English>You have discovered a ship floating in the seas! All sailors are dead. They seem to have died of thirst.</English>
        <French>Vous avez découvert un navire flottant sur les mers ! Tous les marins sont morts. Il semble par déshydratation.</French>
        <German>Ihr habt ein steuerlos treibendes Schiff im offenen Meer entdeckt! Die gesamte Besatzung ist to. Es scheint als sei sie verdurstet.</German>
        <Italian>You have discovered a ship floating in the seas! All sailors are dead. They seem to have died of thirst.</Italian>
        <Spanish>You have discovered a ship floating in the seas! All sailors are dead. They seem to have died of thirst.</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_EXPERIENCE</Tag>
        <English>Experience</English>
        <French>Expérience</French>
        <German>Erfahrung</German>
        <Italian>Esperienza</Italian>
        <Spanish>Experiencia:</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_EXPERIENCE_SEA</Tag>
        <English>INTERFACE_PANE_EXPERIENCE</English>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_HEALING</Tag>
        <English>Ancient Medicine</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Médecine traditionnelle</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>Traditionelle Medizin</German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Antica medicina</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Medicina antigua</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_HIGH_GOLD</Tag>
        <English>TXT_KEY_TRADE_TITLE_GOLD</English>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_HOSTILE_STRONG</Tag>
        <English>TXT_KEY_GOODY_HOSTILE_NATIVES</English>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_HOSTILE_WEAK</Tag>
        <English>Hostile Natives</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Indigène hostile:Indigènes hostiles</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>Feindselige Ureinwohner</German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Nativi ostili</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Nativos hostiles</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>1</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_LOW_GOLD</Tag>
        <English>Gold</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Or</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Gold</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Oro</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Oro</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_LOW_GOLD_SEA</Tag>
        <English>TXT_KEY_TRADE_TITLE_GOLD</English>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_MAP</Tag>
        <English>Map</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Carte</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Karte</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Mappa</Text>
            <Gender>Female</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Mapa</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_MAP_SEA</Tag>
        <English>TXT_KEY_MAIN_MENU_MAP</English>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_NATIVE_MERC</Tag>
        <English>You have discovered a proud native warrior who offers to join you!</English>
        <French>Vous avez découvert un fier guerrier indigène qui propose de vous rejoindre !</French>
        <German>Ihr habt einen stolzen Ureinwohnerkrieger entdeckt, der sich euch anschliesst!</German>
        <Italian>You have discovered a proud native warrior who offers to join you!</Italian>
        <Spanish>You have discovered a proud native warrior who offers to join you!</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_NATIVE_SLAVE</Tag>
        <English>You have discovered a runaway slave from a native tribe!</English>
        <French>Vous avez découvert un esclave fuyant une tribu indigène !</French>
        <German>Ihr habt einen Ureinwohnersklaven entdeckt, der von seinem Stamm geflohen ist!</German>
        <Italian>You have discovered a runaway slave from a native tribe!</Italian>
        <Spanish>You have discovered a runaway slave from a native tribe!</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_RUMORS_EL_DORADO</Tag>
        <English>Rumours about El Dorado</English>
        <French>Rumeurs à propos de l'El Dorado</French>
        <German>Gerüchte über El Dorado</German>
        <Italian>Rumors about El Dorado</Italian>
        <Spanish>Rumors about El Dorado</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_RUMORS_FOUNTAIN_OF_YOUTH</Tag>
        <English>Rumours about the Fountain of Youth</English>
        <French>Rumeurs à propos de la Fontaine de Jouvence</French>
        <German>Gerüchte über den Jungbrunnen</German>
        <Italian>Rumors about the Fountain of Youth</Italian>
        <Spanish>Rumors about the Fountain of Youth</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_RUMORS_PIRATE_TREASURE</Tag>
        <English>Rumours about a Pirate Treasure</English>
        <French>Rumeurs à propos du trésor pirate</French>
        <German>Gerüchte über über einen Piratenschatz</German>
        <Italian>Rumors about a Pirate Treasure</Italian>
        <Spanish>Rumors about a Pirate Treasure</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_SCOUT</Tag>
        <English>Seasoned Scout:Seasoned Scouts</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Eclaireur aguerri:Eclaireurs aguerris</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>
            <Text>Routinierter Späher:Routinierte Späher</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Scout esperto:Scout esperti</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Batidor curtido:Batidores curtidos</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_SHIPWRECKED</Tag>
        <English>You have discovered a survivor from a shipwreck!</English>
        <French>Vous avez découvert les survivants d'un nauffrage !</French>
        <German>Ihr habt einen Überlebenden eines Schiffsunglücks entdeckt!</German>
        <Italian>You have discovered a survivor from a shipwreck!</Italian>
        <Spanish>You have discovered a survivor from a shipwreck!</Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_TREASURE</Tag>
        <English>Treasure</English>
        <French>
            <Text>Trésor:Trésors</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </French>
        <German>Schatz</German>
        <Italian>
            <Text>Tesoro</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0</Plural>
        </Italian>
        <Spanish>
            <Text>Tesoro:Tesoros</Text>
            <Gender>Male</Gender>
            <Plural>0:1</Plural>
        </Spanish>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_WAR</Tag>
        <English>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_WAR</English>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_RANGER</Tag>
        <English>You have discovered a wounded Ranger who offers his services to us for our help.</English>
        <German>Ihr habt einen verwundetetn Ranger entdeckt, der uns für unsere Hilfe seine Dienste anbietet!</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_NATIVE_TRADER</Tag>
        <English>You have discovered a Native Trader who had lost his orientation and now wants to offer his services to you!</English>
        <German>Ihr habt einen Uhreinwohnerhändler entdeckt, der die Orientierung verloren hatte und Euch nun seine Dienste anbietet.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_CRAZY_SECT_OF_MISSIONARIES</Tag>
        <English>Sir, we have found Christian Missionaries in the Wilderness that seem to have gone crazy. They prey to small yellow blue frogs in a pool of water.</English>
        <German>Sir, wir haben christliche Missionare in der Wildnis gefunden, die anscheinend verrückt sind. Sie beten kleine bunte Frösche in einem Tümpel an.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_HOSTILE_RANGER_IN_THE_WILDERNESS</Tag>
        <English>Sir, we have found a Ranger in the Wilderness refusing to talk to us. When we approach anyways he attacked.</English>
        <German>Sir, wir haben einen Ranger in der Wildnis gefunden, der sich weigerte mit uns zu reden. Als wir uns dennoch näherten griff er uns an.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_SEVEN_CITIES_OF_CIBOLA</Tag>
        <English>It seems we found the legendary golden city of Cibola. But other conquistadores seem to have found it before us and do not want to share its wealth.</English>
        <German>Wir haben die legendäre goldene Stadt Cibola gefunden. Doch andere Conquistadores haben sie vor uns entdeckt und wollen den Reichtum nicht teilen.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_CONQUISTADOR_TREASURE_GUARD</Tag>
        <English>Sir, we found a mysterious Mounted Conquistador carrying a small treasure. When we asked for his origin he simply attacked without warning.</English>
        <German>Sir, wir haben einen mysteriösen berittenen Conquistador entdeckt der einen kleinen Schatz bei sich trug. Als wir fragten woher er kam griff er uns an.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_NATIVES_ON_WAR_PATH</Tag>
        <English>As it seem the Natives in this village have been preparing to go on the War path. This is going to be a tough fight.</English>
        <German>So wie es scheint haben sich die Ureinwohner darauf vorbereitet auf den Kriegspfad zu gehen. Dies wird ein schwieriger Kampf.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_TREASURE_RUN</Tag>
        <English>Sir, we seem to have found an undefended treasure train of our enemies. Catch them all before they can flee!</English>
        <German>Sir, wir scheinen einen unverteidigten Schatzzug unserer Feinde entdeckt zu haben. Wir sollten Sie schnell fassen bevor sie fliehen!</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_CRIMINAL_CAMP</Tag>
        <English>This seems to be a camp of criminals and outlaws. Let us teach them order and law!</English>
        <German>Dies scheint ein Lager voller Krimineller und Gesetzloser zu sein. Lasst uns ihnen Recht und Gottesfürchtigkeit beibringen.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_DESERTED_MILITIA</Tag>
        <English>Sir, it seems we have found a coward that fled from his duties from the colonial militia. Let us bring him to justice.</English>
        <German>Sir, es scheint wir haben einen Feigling gefunden, der vor seinen Pflichten in der Kolonialmiliz geflohen ist.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_RUNAWAY_NATIVE_SLAVES</Tag>
        <English>Sir, we have found runaway Native Slaves. Let us catch them and bring them back to their owners.</English>
        <German>Sir, wir haben entlaufene Ureinwohnersklaven gefunden. Lasst uns sie ihren rechtmäßigen Besitzern zurückbringen.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_RUNAWAY_AFRICAN_SLAVES</Tag>
        <English>Sir, we have found runaway African Slaves. Let us catch them and bring them back to their owners.</English>
        <German>Sir, wir haben entlaufene Sklaven gefunden. Lasst uns sie ihren rechtmäßigen Besitzern zurückbringen.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_RUNAWAY_SERVANT</Tag>
        <English>Sir, we have found a servant that fled the castigation of his Master. He was so scared that he even dared to attack us instead of being brought home.</English>
        <German>Sir, wir haben einen Diener gefunden, der von den Züchtigungen seines Herrn geflohen ist. Er war so verängstigt nach Hause zu müssen, dass er uns angriff.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_ARMED_NATIVE_SLAVES_COLONY</Tag>
        <English>Sir, we have found a hidden colony of armed Native Slaves. How could they flee and where did they get those weapons from?</English>
        <German>Sir, wir haben eine versteckte Kolonie von bewaffneten Ureinwohnersklaven gefunden. Wie konnten sie fliehen und woher haben sie diese Waffen?</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_ARMED_AFRICAN_SLAVES_COLONY</Tag>
        <English>Sir, we have found a hidden colony of armed African Slaves. How could they flee and where did they get those weapons from?</English>
        <German>Sir, wir haben eine versteckte Kolonie von bewaffneten Sklaven gefunden. Wie konnten sie fliehen und woher haben sie diese Waffen?</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_SCALP_HUNTER</Tag>
        <English>Sir, we have met heavily armed Native Mercenaries. As it seems somebody has offered them a bounty for our scalps.</English>
        <German>Sir, wir haben schwer bewaffnete Ureiwohnersöldner getroffen. Anscheinend hat man ihm ein Kopfgeld für unsere Scalps geboten.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_DAMAGED_WAGON_TRAIN</Tag>
        <English>Sir, we have found a heavily damaged Wagon Train in the Wilderness. We could repair it but we found no traces of its owners.</English>
        <German>Sir, wir haben einen schwer beschädigten Wagenzug in der Wildnis gefunden. Wir konnten ihn reparieren, fanden aber keine Spuren seiner Besitzer</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_ESCAPING_SMUGGLING_SHIP</Tag>
        <English>Sir, it seems that we have found the secret smuggling port of the local black market traders. They now try to flee with their ship.</English>
        <German>Sir, anscheinend haben wir den Schmugglerhafen der lokalen Schwarzmarkthändler gefunden. Sie versuchen nun mit ihrem wendigen Schiff zu entkommen.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_ATTACKING_PIRATE_FRIGATE</Tag>
        <English>Commander, we have found a still floating but unsavably damaged Ship showing signs of a a battle. It seems it has been attacked by Pirates.</English>
        <German>Commader, wir haben ein noch treibendes aber unrettbar beschädigtes Schiff mit Spuren eines Kampfes entdeckt. Es wurde anscheinend von Piraten angegriffen.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_WOLF_PACK</Tag>
        <English>Sir, the cave we have found seems to be the home of a wolf pack. They returned from their hunt and now circle us ready to attack.</English>
        <German>Sir, die Höhle, die wir betreten haben, scheint das Heim eines Wolfrudels zu sein. Sie sind nun von ihrer Jagd zurückgekehrt und unkreisen uns feindselig.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_GRIZZLY_GRIM</Tag>
        <English>Sir, the cave we have found seems to be the home of a grizzly. It seems we have woken him from his sleep and he does not like that.</English>
        <German>Sir, die Höhle, die wir betreten haben, scheint das Heim eines Grizzlys zu sein. Er scheint es nicht zu mögen, dass wir ihn aus seinem Schlaf geweckt haben.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_SEE_YOU_LATER_ALLIGATOR</Tag>
        <English>Sir, we have found an alligator nest. These beasts seem to be hungry. We should better not get any closer if we do not want to become their lunch.</English>
        <German>Sir, wir haben ein Alligatornest gefunden. Diese Biester scheinen hungrig zu sein. Wir sollten uns ihnen daher nicht weiter nähern.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_MOTHER_BEAR</Tag>
        <English>Sir we have stumbled across a black bear with its cub. The mother now charges at us to defend against the intruders.</English>
        <German>Sir, wir sind über einen Schwarzbärin mit ihrem Jungen gestolpert. Die Mutter stürmt nun auf uns zu um </German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_WHITE_HUNTER_IN_THE_SNOW</Tag>
        <English>Sir, we have found the most gigantic Bear we have ever seen. It is white as Snow and incredibly fast and strong.</English>
        <German>Sir, wir haben den größten Bären aller Zeiten gefunden. Er ist weiß wie Schnee und unglaublich stark und schnell.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_LYNX_TRAIL</Tag>
        <English>Sir, we have found a dead dear. Our scouts report that all footprints and traces point towards a lynx hunting in this area.</English>
        <German>Sir, wir haben ein totes Reh gefunden. Unsere Späher berichten, dass die Fußabdrücke und andere Spuren auf einen Luchs hindeuten, der in dieser Gegend jagt.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_SHADOW_IN_THE_JUNGLE</Tag>
        <English>Sir, our men report that they have seen a shadow moving in the trees. Maybe we should listen to them and get ready for an attack.</English>
        <German>Sir, unsere Männer berichten über einen Schatten, der sich in den Bäumen bewegt. Wir sollten vielleicht auf sie hören und uns auf einen Angriff vorbereiten.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_COUGAR_IN_THE_NIGHT</Tag>
        <English>Sir, the men at the campfire report to have heart silent noises in the gras. We think there is a big cat or other predator close by.</English>
        <German>Sir, die Männer am Lagerfeuer berichten, dass sie leise Geräusche im Gras gehört haben. Wir vermuten eine Raubkatze oder ein anderes Raubtier in der Nähe.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_GREAT_WHITE</Tag>
        <English>Sir, there are parts of a sunken ship and also dead bodies of sailors floating in the water. Their blood seems to have lured a great white.</English>
        <German>Sir, es triben Teile eines gesunken Schiffes und auch Körper toter Seemänner im Wasser. Ihr Blut scheint einen Weissen Hai angelockt zu haben.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_MOBY_DICK</Tag>
        <English>Sir, something gigantic must have rammed and thus almost sunken that ship. But what could have been that huge?</English>
        <German>Sir, irgendetwas riesiges scheint dieses Schiff gerammt und dadurch fast versenkt zu haben. Aber was kann so groß gewesen sein?</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_KRAKEN_ARMS</Tag>
        <English>Sir, it seems this ship has been ripped apart by incredible forces. One of our old sailors swears that this must have been a giant kraken.</English>
        <German>Sir, es scheint dass dieses Schiff von unglaublichen Kräften auseinander gerissen wurde. Laut unsere Schiffsmannschaft, kann dies nur ein Riesenkrake gewesen sein.</German>
    </TEXT>
    <TEXT>
        <Tag>TXT_KEY_GOODY_ORCA_SCHOOOL</Tag>
        <English>Sir, the floating parts of this ship seem to have interested some orcas. Several of them swim around our ship without yet having attacked.</English>
        <German>Sir, die treibenden Schiffsteile scheinen einige Orcas angelockt zu haben. Mehrere von ihnen schwimmen um uns herum ohne bisher anzugreifen.</German>
    </TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>
